<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Story-Cards on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/story-cards/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Infection Growing</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/agile_infection_growing</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/agile_infection_growing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mikemason.ca/2007/03/21/#20070321CardInfected&#34;&gt;This is a bloody good idea&lt;/a&gt;.  It builds upon my own Virgoen tendancies to write lists and tick things off, but what the list model lacks is the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; state.  Plus occasionally my lists get confused.  See today&amp;rsquo;s notebook page:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;form&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Fix bugs in Test Director&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Merge fixes up&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Do build&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;true&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Merge down&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Read terms of contract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;E-mail solicitor&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Go to Robert Dyas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;true&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Order DAB Radio&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Finish business analysis docs&lt;br/&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34;/&gt;Carry on with QCon note consolidation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How do I know which ones I&amp;rsquo;ve started?  I could do with a couple of boards at least as well to separate the personal from the business.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Also note that I took something away from my Time Management course, attended when I was a mere graduate at a large manufacturing organisation: make a new list for each day, discarding your completed items and moving forward the incomplete ones (it also mentions to discard &amp;ldquo;low priority&amp;rdquo; items that haven&amp;rsquo;t been done over a week or two under the theory that you&amp;rsquo;ll never do it if you haven&amp;rsquo;t by then).&amp;nbsp; This is great for keeping a nice clean list of achievable goals for the day, but a bit rubbish at giving any positive feedback - no matter how much you get done, every day there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;yet more &lt;/span&gt;to do, and lack of visibility on what you have actually achieved. The example story wall in the link above is great for a sense of acheivement - yes there&amp;rsquo;s still things to be done but look how much has been achieved in comparison!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;However, I am going to make the common criticism of cards: one of their major advantages, their &amp;ldquo;physicality&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, is also the disadvantage - whilst I can take my little notebook round with me, I can&amp;rsquo;t lug a story wall between work and home.  And although some of those things are personal tasks, they need to be done at work (e.g. e-mailing because I haven&amp;rsquo;t got my broadband at home yet) or between work and home.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mind you, I actually have 3 pieces of paper containing lists of things to do / buy / check / clean with regards to my new flat, because of my inability to actually carry the notebook with me.&amp;nbsp; Or the same one at least.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I think this means two more items to be added to the &amp;ldquo;To Buy&amp;rdquo; list: a magnetic whiteboard and some story cards.  I like whiteboards because you can even scribble stuff behind / around the cards.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;EDIT: Bah, someone else &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xprogramming.com/xpmag/jatLetsGetOrganized.htm&#34;&gt;already beat me to it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; This is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jamesshore.com/Agile-Book/stories.html&#34;&gt;James Shore&amp;rsquo;s section on Stories&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Write stories on index cards.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t the result of some strange Ludditian urge on the part of XP&amp;rsquo;s creators—it&amp;rsquo;s a deliberate choice based on the strengths of the medium. You see, physical cards have one feature that no conglomeration of pixels has: you can pick them up and move them around. They&amp;rsquo;re tactile. This gives them power.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
