<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ide on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/ide/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Java developers hate .NET</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/why_java_developers_hate_net</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/why_java_developers_hate_net</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling with .NET.&amp;nbsp; Actually, I have been fighting pitched battles with it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All I want to do is take our existing Java client example code and write an equivalent in C#.&amp;nbsp; Easy, right?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Trisha&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Converting Java to C#&lt;/h3&gt;Turns out writing the actual C# is relatively straightforward.&amp;nbsp; Putting to one side the question of writing optimal code (these are very basic samples after all), to get the examples to compile and run was a simple process:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;1. Find-and-replace the following (only you can&amp;rsquo;t use Ctrl+R like I expect.&amp;nbsp; Sigh.)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;line-height: 16px; size: 10px;&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt; = &lt;code&gt;readonly&lt;/code&gt; (but remove from method params)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;System.out.printf&lt;/code&gt; = &lt;code&gt;Console.WriteLine&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt; = &lt;code&gt;Dictionary&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;BigDecimal&lt;/code&gt; = &lt;code&gt;decimal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set&lt;/code&gt;&amp;hellip; oh.&amp;nbsp; I have no idea. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2. When using callbacks, replace anonymous inner classes with delegates&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Java&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;clear: both;&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;something.doSomething(new SomethingRequest(),&lt;br /&gt;  new SomethingCallBack()&lt;br /&gt;  {&lt;br /&gt;    public void onSuccess()&lt;br /&gt;    {&lt;br /&gt;      System.out.println(&amp;ldquo;Action successful&amp;rdquo;);&lt;br /&gt;    }&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    public void onFailure()&lt;br /&gt;    {&lt;br /&gt;      System.err.println(&amp;ldquo;Action failed&amp;rdquo;);&lt;br /&gt;    }&lt;br /&gt;  });&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;C#&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;clear: both;&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private void foo ()&lt;br /&gt;{&lt;br /&gt;  _something.DoSomething(new SomethingRequest(), &lt;br /&gt;                         SomethingSuccess, &lt;br /&gt;                         SomethingFailure);&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;private void SomethingSuccess()&lt;br /&gt;{&lt;br /&gt;  Console.WriteLine(&amp;ldquo;Action successful&amp;rdquo;);&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;private void SomethingFailure()&lt;br /&gt;{&lt;br /&gt;  Console.Error.WriteLine(&amp;ldquo;Action failed&amp;rdquo;);&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I rather like this pattern actually.  You can&amp;rsquo;t really tell in the noddy example above, but the C# code is generally shorter and more reusable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;3. Replace getters and setters with properties&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Java&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;clear: both;&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private class MyClass&lt;br /&gt;{&lt;br /&gt;  private BigDecimal myField = new BigDecimal(&amp;ldquo;-1.0&amp;rdquo;);&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  public BigDecimal getMyField()&lt;br /&gt;  {&lt;br /&gt;    return myField;&lt;br /&gt;  }&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  public void setMyField(BigDecimal instructionId)&lt;br /&gt;  {&lt;br /&gt;    this.myField = myField&lt;br /&gt;  }&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;C#&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;clear: both;&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;internal class MyClass&lt;br /&gt;{&lt;br /&gt;  public decimal MyField{ get; set; }&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What the&amp;hellip; where did all my code go??&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;My Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;I was pleasantly surprised with the language.  In general, for what I was doing, the equivalent C# was a lot less code.  The fact that the syntax is not wildly different from Java made the transition relatively easy, even if I don&amp;rsquo;t get all the nuances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the enums - I can see what purpose they serve, but I quite like the way the Java ones are pretty much classes in their own right with properties of their own - it allows you to encapsulate some of your simplest domain objects.  But it&amp;rsquo;s a minor point, not a deal-breaker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The C# capitalisation makes me queasy though.  I just can&amp;rsquo;t get my head around it.  In Java, if I say:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;com.mechanitis.foo.Bar&lt;/pre&gt;I know the class is Bar and the rest is the package (or namespace, or whatever).  This is more useful when you&amp;rsquo;re using static methods and so forth:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;com.mechanitis.foo.Bar.thatThingIWantToDo()&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In C#, I know the thing at the end is a method and the thing before that is a class, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t jump out at me:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Com.Mechanitis.Foo.Bar.ThatThingIWantToDo();&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And if you&amp;rsquo;re using a property:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Com.Mechanitis.Foo.Bar.MyProperty;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The whole thing makes me dizzy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You could argue that all this is redundant with modern tools and IDEs doing all the heavy lifting for you - nice colourisation etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Which brings me to The Rant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Oh My Dear God What Is Wrong With Visual Studio?&lt;/h3&gt;C# needs to be a shorter, more succinct language because it takes &lt;i&gt;three billion times longer&lt;/i&gt; to do anything in Visual bloody Studio.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m coming at this from a Java, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ &lt;/a&gt;point of view, so there&amp;rsquo;s always the possibility it might be lack of familiarity with the tool, rather than the tool itself, which is the problem.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s a long time since I used VS, and that was back in the 90s when I was doing ASP and COM (shhh, don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But things shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this hard.&amp;nbsp; I was ready to accept, due to my newbie status, the IDE not helping me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect it to actively hinder me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For example: it took hours of my life that I will never get back to discover that you can&amp;rsquo;t simply run a class that has a main method by right-clicking and selecting &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; (note: I&amp;rsquo;m not even trying Ctrl+F10).&amp;nbsp; No.&amp;nbsp; I have to select, at a Solution level, which Projects are runnable.&amp;nbsp; Then I have to select at the Project level the class with the main method I actually want to run.&amp;nbsp; Then, it opens up a terminal window and runs it in there, which promptly disappears when the program errors or finishes.&amp;nbsp; What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with outputting in the output window of the IDE? Is that not what it&amp;rsquo;s for?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally I worked out how to run the cursed program (seriously, like that&amp;rsquo;s not the first thing everyone wants to do?&amp;nbsp; How do people write &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo;?).&amp;nbsp; Now, where are the command line arguments?&amp;nbsp; Of course, they&amp;rsquo;re at the project properties level too, because each project only has one entry point. &amp;nbsp;I seriously had to Google that too because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work it out from the IDE alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next day, my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper/&#34;&gt;ReSharper &lt;/a&gt;licence had expired. &amp;nbsp;I decided I should attempt to limp on without it, after all hundreds of developers must be surviving with just Visual Studio. &amp;nbsp;How bad could it be?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad, it turns out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All those helpful little squiggles I was leaning heavily on to convert my Java to C#?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The red to tell you you&amp;rsquo;re utterly wrong.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The orange to tell you could be using less code.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The blue to remind you to stop thinking in Java and helpfully offer corrected naming.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The green to suggest stuff that C# could do differently.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yeah, all gone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How do people code like this?&amp;nbsp; Do they really just do a build to check if it&amp;rsquo;s all wrong or not?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next, I try to find a class. &amp;nbsp;I actually&amp;nbsp;have no idea how to do this, because I can&amp;rsquo;t use Ctrl+N.&amp;nbsp; So I Ctrl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I realise this is a waste of time anyway, because one thing that &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; annoys me about Visual Studio is that I can&amp;rsquo;t find a way to sync the project tree to the class file I&amp;rsquo;m looking at. &amp;nbsp;I can&amp;rsquo;t get it to jump to highlight where I am. &amp;nbsp;When I&amp;rsquo;m using IntelliJ, I find this dead useful when I want to see other stuff in the same package.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Less than ten minutes after attempting to use Visual Studio without ReSharper, I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned the fight and tracked down a licence and installed it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation isn&amp;rsquo;t a standard function of .NET?&lt;/h3&gt;What sort of message does this give developers? &amp;nbsp;Documentation isn&amp;rsquo;t important?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I always thought&amp;nbsp;Javadoc was pretty ugly and clunky. In addition, now our IDEs generate so much, it&amp;rsquo;s frequently meaningless.&amp;nbsp; But it is generated by standard Java tools, and HTML is a standard format that can be read on pretty much any computer with any operating system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I could not believe how hard it was to get the XML comments out of&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;C# into something the user can actually read.&amp;nbsp; Thank goodness, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symphonious.net/&#34;&gt;some enterprising member of the team&lt;/a&gt; had already done that for us. &amp;nbsp;All I needed to do was hack/crowbar the tutorial I&amp;rsquo;d been working on into the generated documentation, so it ended up in the Windows help files in some fashion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know there&amp;rsquo;s a way to get HTML/XML files into the end result using &lt;a href=&#34;http://sandcastle.codeplex.com/&#34;&gt;Sandcastle&lt;/a&gt;, but hours of Googling only told me it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; possible, not how to do it. &amp;nbsp;I still have no idea what the correct question is to ask to find the solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Right now, this is an unsolved mystery. &amp;nbsp;Our .NET client users will have to read the plain HTML I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;Are we lowly Java developers spoilt with our shiny IDEs?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Or is there such a fundamentally different approach to development for .NET people that all the functionality is there, I just can&amp;rsquo;t find it?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed if I&amp;rsquo;m honest.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;m sure the .NET camp used to tout their tools as their superiority.&amp;nbsp; I ended up feeling sorry for the poor NET people.&amp;nbsp; Is there anything they can use that isn&amp;rsquo;t Visual Studio?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In Conclusion: Despite the nasty capitalisation I found myself surprisingly taken with C#. &amp;nbsp;But until they can give me a proper development environment, I won&amp;rsquo;t be tempted by the dark side any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
