<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>user groups on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/user-groups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in user groups on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/user-groups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla MUG, first event</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/sevilla_mug_first_event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/sevilla_mug_first_event/</guid>
      <description>Last night was the inaugural meeting of the Sevilla MongoDN User Group. &amp;nbsp;An event organised with just over 48 hours notice, in a city where I don&#39;t speak the language and where even my best-connected contacts aren&#39;t sure they&#39;re fully plugged in to the tech scene.
I&#39;ll admit, I had some reservations:
a lightning talk? Will people come all that way for beer and 15 minutes of presentation?in English? Whilst I&#39;m desperately learning Spanish to get closer to presenting in Spanish, at this point I&#39;m just not ready and have to hope people want to listen to me ramble in a foreign languagea MUG?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The birth of a new community</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community/</guid>
      <description>Topping off my mini-tour at the end of May, I was invited to Rotterdam to present to a brand new community of developers. I was really interested in attending because my experience with user groups is pretty much limited to the London Java Community, and I knew this would be different due to being a) across a wider range of technologies and b) shiny and new.
It was hosted (rather awesomely) in a brewery, and until then I&#39;d never given a presentation in a pub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>