<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB London</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mongodb_london/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mongodb_london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt;, 6th November, 50% off with discount code &lt;strong&gt;50Trisha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt; is nearly upon us again,
and I&amp;rsquo;m dead disappointed I can&amp;rsquo;t make it this year (I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2014/presentation/Party%20Keynote:%20Staying%20Ahead%20of%20the%20Curve&#34;&gt;keynoting at GOTO Berlin&lt;/a&gt; instead,
which I&amp;rsquo;m terrified, I mean, excited, about). The last MongoDB London was really interesting for me - I was fairly new to the company,
I&amp;rsquo;d been here less than six months, and it was a really great way to go both broad and deep on the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was trying to find a blog post where I talked about my experiences, but it looks like I only wrote that In My Mind. In fact,
I only only wrote two whole lines of notes on the conference.  But 18 months later I clearly remember presentations from my colleagues
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Ross&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://derickrethans.nl/&#34;&gt;Derick&lt;/a&gt; demonstrating the geo capabilities in MongoDB,
presentations which heavily influenced the &lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/&#34;&gt;live coding demo&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving
recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also remember Eliot&amp;rsquo;s presentation - Eliot is one of those people who totally gets away with breaking the &amp;ldquo;speak in a measured,
clear fashion&amp;rdquo; presenters rule, he fires fascinating information at you at high speed and it&amp;rsquo;s actually one of the compelling things
about his talks. If you ever get a chance to see him talk about the product, it&amp;rsquo;s totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, the most awesome thing about the conference was the chance to meet, and talk to,
a bunch of different MongoDB people - there are the engineers who work on the product (like me and my colleagues);
the people leading the way with the technology, like Eliot; and finally, but for me most importantly,
you get to meet really interesting people who are using MongoDB in ways that you might not even imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway the point of this sales pitch is, whether you&amp;rsquo;re using MongoDB already or you&amp;rsquo;re keen to find out about it,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt; is only going to take a day from your life,
and you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a bunch of interesting things. And, with a Special Discount Code from me,
it&amp;rsquo;s only £45! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mongodb-london-2014-registration-13140209721&#34;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt; with code &lt;strong&gt;50Trisha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/upcoming_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/upcoming_events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the list in the &lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/public_appearances/&#34;&gt;talks section&lt;/a&gt; of my blog covers past presentations,
this page should, if I keep it up to date, list my confirmed upcoming events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19-24 Oct&lt;/strong&gt;: In New York City for department meetings. Sadly not available for drinks/meeting up/events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 Nov&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2014&#34;&gt;GOTO Berlin&lt;/a&gt; - where I&amp;rsquo;m presenting
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2014/presentation/Party%20Keynote:%20Staying%20Ahead%20of%20the%20Curve&#34;&gt;my first keynote&lt;/a&gt;,
eeek. Even more terrifying, there are some really fantastic speakers there, including at least two of my mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10-14 Nov&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.be/&#34;&gt;Devoxx&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;ll be in the Hackergarten on Tuesday and Wednesday,
and in the BOF (Bird of a Feather) &amp;ldquo;Women and female speakers in the Java ecosystem - How to ameliorate the current situation?&amp;rdquo;
on Wednesday from 20:00 to 21:00. Travel is still unconfirmed but looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going to be at the conference all week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22 Nov&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.nosql-matters.org/bcn/&#34;&gt;NoSQL Matters, Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; - presenting the AngularJS/Java/MongoDB demo again,
with more of a focus on the MongoDB side. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be really nice to present so close to home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24 Nov&lt;/strong&gt;: Tentatively scheduled for an event in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29 Nov&lt;/strong&gt;: London Java Community Open Conference? Unconfirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently have nothing planned for 2015, and looking at that list of fixtures, I think I&amp;rsquo;d like it to stay that way for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS, HTML5, Groovy, Java and MongoDB All Together - What Could Possibly Go Wrong??</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving an evolving live demonstration of coding a Fully Buzz Word Compliant,
mobile-friendly web application.  The aim of the demo is to show, via a real-world application rather than snippets or a toy example,
where these popular technologies sit in your archtecture, and how they interact with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact code I present has changed a bit over time, but the vJUG has a pretty recent version of the demo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/MRrSAkEAnZQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;ll see there are a number of different branches for the
different versions I&amp;rsquo;ve presented. The current one is the JavaOne version.  With all the branches,
the commits correspond to the user stories in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/i-want-coffeejavaone&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;,
so you can get a feel for how the code builds up throughout the demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk has been videod several times, some of these videos aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet, but there are videos of older versions of this talk -
these older versions use a different library to talk to MongoDB and (I hope) you&amp;rsquo;ll see that the most recent code is even simpler than
these initial demos.  If more videos become available I&amp;rsquo;ll add them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago, May 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/demo-java-javascript-mongodb&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding, March 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a full list of this and all my presentations, see &lt;a href=&#34;presentation/public_appearances/&#34;&gt;Public Appearances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Groovy to import XML into MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been demonstrating how easy it is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRrSAkEAnZQ&#34;&gt;create modern web apps using AngularJS,
Java and MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.  I also use Groovy during this demo to do the sorts of things Groovy is
really good at - writing descriptive tests, and creating scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the time pressures in the demo, I never really get a chance to go into the details of the script I use,
so the aim of this long-overdue blog post is to go over this Groovy script in a bit more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly I want to clarify that this is not my original work - I &lt;strike&gt;stole&lt;/strike&gt; borrowed most of the ideas for the demo from my
colleague Ross Lawley. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/posts/the-most-popular-pub-name/&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; he goes into detail of how he built
up an application that
finds the most popular pub names in the UK.  There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/posts/the-most-popular-pub-name/#toc_1&#34;&gt;section in there&lt;/a&gt;
where he talks about downloading the open street map data and using python to convert the XML into something more MongoDB-friendly - it&amp;rsquo;s
this process that I basically stole, re-worked for coffee shops, and re-wrote for the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m assuming if you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Java for any period of time, there has come a moment where you needed to use it to parse XML. Since my
demo is supposed to be all about how easy it is to work with Java, I did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; want to do this. When I wrote the demo I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really all
that familiar with Groovy, but what I did know was that it has built in support for parsing and manipulating XML,
which is exactly what I wanted to do. In addition, creating &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/Collections#Collections-Mapsmaps&#34;&gt;Maps&lt;/a&gt; (the
data structures, not the geographical ones) with Groovy is really easy, and this is effectively what we need to insert into
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Goal of the Script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parse an XML file containing open street map data of all coffee shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract latitude and longitude XML attributes and transform into
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-geojson&#34;&gt;MongoDB GeoJSON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform some basic validation on the coffee shop data from the XML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert into MongoDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure MongoDB knows this contains query-able geolocation data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/blob/java-one/src/main/scripts/PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34;&gt;PopulateDatabase.groovy&lt;/a&gt;,
that link will take you to the version I presented at JavaOne:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript.png&#34; alt=&#34;PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34; title=&#34;PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Firstly, we need data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the same service Ross used in his blog post to obtain the XML file containing &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rdquo; coffee shops around the world. Now,
the open street map data is somewhat&amp;hellip; raw and unstructured (which is why MongoDB is such a great tool for storing it),
so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I really have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the coffee shops, but I obtained enough data for an interesting demo using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.overpass-api.de/api/xapi?*[amenity=cafe][cuisine=coffee_shop]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/blob/master/src/main/scripts/resources/all-coffee-shops.xml&#34;&gt;resulting XML file&lt;/a&gt; is in the
github project, but if you try this yourself you might (in fact, probably will) get different results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each XML record looks something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;node id=&amp;quot;178821166&amp;quot; lat=&amp;quot;40.4167226&amp;quot; lon=&amp;quot;-3.7069112&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;amenity&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;cafe&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;cuisine&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;coffee_shop&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;name&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;Chocolatería San Ginés&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;wheelchair&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;limited&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;wikipedia&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;es:Chocolatería San Ginés&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/node&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each coffee shop has a unique identifier and a latitude and longitude as attributes of a &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt; element.  Within this node is a series
of &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; elements, all with &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; attributes. Each coffee shop has a varying number of these attributes,
and they are not consistent from shop to shop (other than &lt;code&gt;amenity&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;cuisine&lt;/code&gt; which we used to select this data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Initialisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Script Initialisation&#34; title=&#34;Script Initialisation&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything else we want to prepare the database.  The assumption of this script is that either the
collection we want to store the coffee shops in is empty, or full of stale data.  So we&amp;rsquo;re going to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/ecosystem/drivers/java/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt; to get the collection that we&amp;rsquo;re interested in, and then drop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s two interesting things to note here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Groovy script is simply using the basic Java driver.  Groovy can talk quite happily to vanilla Java,
it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to use a Groovy library.  There are Groovy-specific libraries for talking to MongoDB (e.g. the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://grails.org/plugin/mongodb&#34;&gt;MongoDB GORM Plugin&lt;/a&gt;), but the Java driver works perfectly well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-database&#34;&gt;databases&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-collection&#34;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt; (collections are
a bit like tables, but less structured) explicitly in MongoDB.  You simply use the database and collection you&amp;rsquo;re interested in,
and if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist, the server will create them for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we&amp;rsquo;re just using the default constructor for the &lt;code&gt;MongoClient&lt;/code&gt;, the class that represents the connection to the database
server(s).  This default is localhost:27017, which is where I happen to be running the database.  However you can specify your own
address and port - for more details on this see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94065240033/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-i&#34;&gt;Getting Started With MongoDB and Java&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Turn the XML into something MongoDB-shaped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Parse &amp;amp; Transform XML&#34; title=&#34;Parse &amp;amp; Transform XML&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next we&amp;rsquo;re going to use Groovy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/api/groovy/util/XmlSlurper.html&#34;&gt;XmlSlurper&lt;/a&gt; to read the open street map
XML data that we talked about earlier.  To iterate over every node we use: &lt;code&gt;xmlSlurper.node.each&lt;/code&gt;.  For those of you who are new to
Groovy or new to Java 8, you might notice this is using a closure to define the behaviour to apply for every &amp;ldquo;node&amp;rdquo; element in the XML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Create GeoJSON&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Create GeoJSON&#34; title=&#34;Create GeoJSON&#34; /&gt;

Since MongoDB documents are effectively just maps of key-value pairs, we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a Map &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt; that contains the
document structure that represents the coffee shop that we want to save into the database.  Firstly,
we initialise this map with the attributes of the &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt;. Remember these attributes are something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;node id=&amp;quot;18464077&amp;quot; lat=&amp;quot;-33.8911183&amp;quot; lon=&amp;quot;151.1958773&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to save the ID as a value for a new field called &lt;code&gt;openStreetMapId&lt;/code&gt;. We need to do something a bit more
complicated with the latitude and longitude, since we need to store them as GeoJSON, which looks something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ &#39;location&#39; : { &#39;coordinates&#39;: [&amp;lt;longitude&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;latitude&amp;gt;],
                 &#39;type&#39;       : &#39;Point&#39; } }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lines 12-14 you can see that we create a &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt; that looks like the GeoJSON, pulling the &lt;code&gt;lat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;lon&lt;/code&gt; attributes into the appropriate
places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Insert Remaining Fields&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Insert Remaining Fields&#34; title=&#34;Insert Remaining Fields&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Validate Field Name&#34; title=&#34;Validate Field Name&#34; /&gt;

Now for every &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; element in the XML, we get the &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; attribute and check if it&amp;rsquo;s a valid field name for MongoDB (it won&amp;rsquo;t let us
insert fields with a dot in, and we don&amp;rsquo;t want to override our carefully constructed &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; field). If so we simply add this key as the
field and its the matching &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; attribute as the value into the map. This effectively copies the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; key/value data into key/value pairs in the MongoDB document so we don&amp;rsquo;t lose any data,
but we also don&amp;rsquo;t do anything particularly interesting to transform it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Save Into MongoDB&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Save Into MongoDB&#34; title=&#34;Save Into MongoDB&#34; /&gt;

Finally, once we&amp;rsquo;ve created a simple &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt; Map representing the document we want to save into MongoDB,
we insert it into MongoDB if the map has a field called &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;.  We could have checked this when we were reading the XML and putting it
into the map, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually much easier just to use the pretty Groovy syntax to check for a key called &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we want to insert the Map we need to turn this into a &lt;code&gt;BasicDBObject&lt;/code&gt;, the Java Driver&amp;rsquo;s document type,
but this is easily done by calling the constructor that takes a Map.  Alternatively, there&amp;rsquo;s a Groovy syntax which would effectively do
the same thing, which you might prefer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;collection.insert(coffeeShop as BasicDBObject)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Tell MongoDB that we want to perform Geo queries on this data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add Geo Index&#34; title=&#34;Add Geo Index&#34; /&gt;

Because we&amp;rsquo;re going to do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/operator/query/nearSphere/&#34;&gt;nearSphere&lt;/a&gt; query on this data,
we need to add a &amp;ldquo;2dsphere&amp;rdquo; index on our location field. We created the &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; field as GeoJSON,
so all we need to do is call &lt;code&gt;createIndex&lt;/code&gt; for this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it!  Groovy is a nice tool for this sort of script-y thing - not only is it a scripting language,
but its built-in support for XML, really nice Map syntax and support for closures makes it the perfect tool for iterating over XML data
and transforming it into something that can be inserted into a MongoDB collection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2014, Day One</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m at JavaOne again, and after only one day I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt stuff.  And, of course,
had a great time catching up with interesting people.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=10289&#34;&gt;Superpowered CI with Git - Sarah Goff-Dupont&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Continuous Integration we did at LMAX is quite different to what we do at MongoDB, and I was hoping to get some tips on better CI with
Git, especially given feature branches.  There was a good overview of development process using branch-per-feature,
 and a comment that it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible to do &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; CI in this sort of environment.  But there was pragmatic advice on how to manage
 the process and run automated builds in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The take-home point for me is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to investigate &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks&#34;&gt;git hooks&lt;/a&gt; to try and
  streamline our process and run some fast checks more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Sarah showed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hipchat.com&#34;&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt; in anger - I&amp;rsquo;ve now heard this mentioned enough that I&amp;rsquo;m going to look into it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2276&#34;&gt;Advanced Unit Testing with Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve [spoken before about Spock](&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/tags/spock/), and how much I love it.  The first section of this talk was a recap
of some of the basics, but the second part went on to some features I either previously ignored or wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of.  For example, in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt;, we do use annotations to denote slower-running tests so we can select which environments to run in,
but we&amp;rsquo;re not using Spock annotations for this.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more we could do with both custom annotations like our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/blob/3.0.x/util/src/main/category/Slow.java&#34;&gt;@Slow&lt;/a&gt; annotation,
Spock&amp;rsquo;s built in annotations like &lt;code&gt;@Issue&lt;/code&gt;, and some others which may not yet be in maven central like &lt;code&gt;@Requires&lt;/code&gt; for running
language-version tests (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/JavaLanguageSpec
.groovy&#34;&gt;e.g. Java 8 tests&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;@IgnoreRest&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also liked the example of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/OldExampleSpec.groovy&#34;&gt;checking the new value against an old
value&lt;/a&gt;,
I can totally see this being useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other bits and pieces in this talk I&amp;rsquo;d like to dig into in more detail that I think will be very useful for the Java Driver.
But even more importantly, I learnt how to zoom into my screen so I can use that in my own presentation. Pro presentation top tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you have even minor testing pains, it&amp;rsquo;s worth finding Ken&amp;rsquo;s talks on Spock, they&amp;rsquo;re great! And a source of inspiration for
better testing, as well as a sneaky way to understand why Groovy is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCP Awards and Party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But it&amp;rsquo;s not all work at these events.  For me, the highlight was the music at at the JCP Awards party.  Firstly,
we had an award-winning beat-box guy from the UK (sadly I don&amp;rsquo;t remember his name so I can&amp;rsquo;t link to his stuff).  An unusual choice for
an event like this, but it was a lot of fun. Then there was the live super-band, The Null Pointers, made up of JUG leaders from around the
world (including &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matkar&#34;&gt;@matkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/frankgreco&#34;&gt;@frankgreco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fguime&#34;&gt;@fguime&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit,
 I was a little concerned about this idea, but the guys were fantastic, and it was a lot of fun singing along to Free&amp;rsquo;s Alright Now and
 Radiohead&amp;rsquo;s Creep. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/openworld/appreciation-event/index.html&#34;&gt;Aerosmith&lt;/a&gt; is going to have to work hard to compete with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;and a quick plug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=1703&#34;&gt;main presentation is on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a keyword-tastic live demo of AngularJS, Java &amp;amp; MongoDB.  Something &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; goes wrong in
this presentation, so I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://doodle.com/fvrasw9vrpxyb9dm&#34;&gt;taking bets right now on what that will be&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with MongoDB and Java</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_started_with_mongodb_and_java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_started_with_mongodb_and_java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been missing an introduction to using MongoDB from Java for a little while now - there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of information in &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/ecosystem/drivers/java/&#34;&gt;the
documentation&lt;/a&gt;, but we were lacking a step-by-step guide to getting started as a Java
developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sought to rectify this with a couple of blog posts for the MongoDB official blog: the first, an introduction to using MongoDB from
Java, including a non-comprehensive list of some of the libraries you can use; the second, an introductory guide to simple CRUD
operations using the Java driver:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94065240033/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-i&#34;&gt;Getting Started with MongoDB and Java, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94724924068/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-ii&#34;&gt;Getting Started with MongoDB and Java, Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very much aimed at Java/JVM developers who are new to MongoDB, and want to get a feel for how you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guides are for the current (2.x) driver. When we release 3.x, we&amp;rsquo;ll release updated guides as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could possibly go wrong? (GOTO Chicago)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, I was given the chance to chat a bit about the presentation I was giving,
which happens to be the same one I&amp;rsquo;m giving at a number of conferences this year (although of course I&amp;rsquo;m evolving it as I go along).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation leaves very little time for anything other than coding, as it&amp;rsquo;s quite challenging to create a full app in 50
minutes, so it was great to have the chance to talk about the motivations for the demo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/sZee7lRAUF4&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;The video of the actual talk is also available now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/kmVnhyWqozA&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning it doesn&amp;rsquo;t clearly show the screen, but it does improve.  You can see an earlier version from the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/demo-java-javascript-mongodb#anch110035&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding&lt;/a&gt; as well,
so if something&amp;rsquo;s not clear on one of the videos, hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s better in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/tree/goto-chicago&#34;&gt;code for the Chicago version is on Github&lt;/a&gt;,
and if you look through the history you can see how it builds up, the same as it does in the demo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiesta de lanzamiento de Java 8</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/es/post/svq_java8_launch_party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/es/post/svq_java8_launch_party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anoche, a la Sevilla JUG, hemos celebrado el lanzamiento de &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/&#34;&gt;Java 8&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Bt48HX7IQAAQBQq.jpg:large&#34; alt=&#34;Partay&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si te perdiste el sesion, o si quieres leer/mirar los materiales, estan aqui:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/lambda-streams-java-8&#34;&gt;The Main Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/happy-mappy&#34;&gt;Trisha&amp;rsquo;s real-life lambda code&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;code&gt;TweetDecorator&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Y usamos el &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/SimonRitter/javase8-55thingsv2-sritter&#34;&gt;slide deck&lt;/a&gt; de Simon Ritter, de esta
presentation: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rtAredKhyac&#34;&gt;55 New Features in Java SE 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla Java User Group Java 8 Launch Party</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_java8_launch_party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_java8_launch_party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night at the Sevilla JUG we officially celebrated the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/&#34;&gt;Java 8&lt;/a&gt; - yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Bt48HX7IQAAQBQq.jpg:large&#34; alt=&#34;Partay&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled by the picture, people had more fun than it looks.  Honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who missed the session, or who was there and wants access to the materials, here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/lambda-streams-java-8&#34;&gt;The Main Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/happy-mappy&#34;&gt;Trisha&amp;rsquo;s real-life lambda code&lt;/a&gt; (the class we were looking at was &lt;code&gt;TweetDecorator&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/SimonRitter/javase8-55thingsv2-sritter&#34;&gt;slide deck&lt;/a&gt; of another of Simon&amp;rsquo;s
presentations, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rtAredKhyac&#34;&gt;55 New Features in Java SE 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the last link is to a video from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/virtualJUG/&#34;&gt;vJUG&lt;/a&gt;, the Virtual Java User Group,
which is a great source of presentations from international speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readable, Succinct, or Just Plain Short?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/short_vs_readable.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/short_vs_readable.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which is more readable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;releaseVersion = version.substring(0, version.indexOf(&#39;-SNAPSHOT&#39;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;releaseVersion = version[0..-10]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a value of &lt;code&gt;0.109-SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt;, they both give the same result.  And I&amp;rsquo;m tempted by the second,
because it&amp;rsquo;s shorter.  But I&amp;rsquo;m going to go with the first one - not because it&amp;rsquo;s more Java-ish and I&amp;rsquo;m scared of Groovy syntax,
but because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to understand if/when something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: if &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t conform to the expected pattern, the two code fragments fail in two different ways.  If &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt;
doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain &lt;code&gt;-SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt;, the first will fail with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java.lang.StringIndexOutOfBoundsException: String index out of range: -1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;whereas the second will either arbitrarily slice the last 9 characters off the end of whatever the String does contain,
or if it&amp;rsquo;s too short you&amp;rsquo;ll get something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java.lang.ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException: Negative array index [-10] too large for array size 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you, the developer, see this error (or notice your mangled version number) and look at the failing line of code,
you&amp;rsquo;ll have two different experiences.  When looking at the second example, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t write it in the first place or if you have a
memory as shocking as mine, you won&amp;rsquo;t get any clues from that code as to what the &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt; is - you&amp;rsquo;ll see what it does (chop the last
9 characters off the &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; string), but not why.  You can &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; the problem by adding an arbitrary 9 characters onto your &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking at the first example, however, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the intent right there - it&amp;rsquo;s trying to chop the string &lt;code&gt;-SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt; (and any
characters that might happen to come after it) off the end of the &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; string.  With this line of code,
if you checked the value of &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; and saw it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the correct suffix, you&amp;rsquo;d have a good idea of what the problem is and how
to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a third way, that potentially keeps the descriptiveness (is that a word?) of the first solution and makes it a bit shorter and
Groovier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;releaseVersion = version[0..&amp;lt;version.indexOf(&#39;-SNAPSHOT&#39;)]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need the less-than sign plonked in there to make it work correctly, which I find a bit jarring,
but it does work.  It&amp;rsquo;s a little more succinct than the original Java syntax and retains the intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in conclusion: yes, shorter code is generally better (and often more readable).  But I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in sacrificing code that
expresses the intent in order to reduce the number of characters used.  We&amp;rsquo;re not living in a memory-poor world any more,
and code is meant to be read by humans as well as computers.  Let&amp;rsquo;s make our code easy to understand when it goes wrong,
not simply the shortest way to do something when the stars are all perfectly aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Handover</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_handover.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_handover.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I walked into the kitchen to see how lunch was going and my boyfriend handed me a knife,
a part-chopped hard boiled egg and said &amp;ldquo;finish this, I need to have a shower&amp;rdquo;. As you do. Apparently there were two things that needed
doing - &amp;ldquo;this&amp;rdquo; needed finishing, and I needed to keep an eye on the fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;paired&amp;rdquo; with him while we&amp;rsquo;ve made that salad before, and I can tell when a fish is burning.  How hard could it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished chopping the egg and putting it into the salad, I realised I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if that was the last thing that needed to go into
the salad - when he said &amp;ldquo;finish this&amp;rdquo;, did he mean the whole salad, or just the egg chopping?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This blog post will be vaguely about technology at some point.  Probably.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After searching for other eggs that might need to be added, and sifting through the salad to see what was already in there,
I was still unclear about whether it was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrum.org/Resources/Scrum-Glossary/Definition-of-Done&#34;&gt;done&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; or not, so I
went to bother my boyfriend in the bathroom (this is not a euphemism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I told you there were only two things left to do&amp;rdquo; he said - it was so clear to him what the steps were to finish,
that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand that there might be hidden assumptions in his handover.  All he wanted was for me to finish chopping the
(only) egg.  Oh and mix it all up. Of course. When I checked if I was supposed to add the olive oil and the salt, the answer was &amp;ldquo;No,
I don&amp;rsquo;t trust you to do that&amp;rdquo; (he&amp;rsquo;s right - I&amp;rsquo;m English, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know you could put salt in a salad
and certainly have no idea about quantities of olive oil. My Spanish boyfriend is genetically wired to know this stuff).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the unclear instructions (&amp;ldquo;keep an eye on the fish&amp;rdquo;, if taken literally, could result in me watching it burn - fortunately I knew it
was secret code for &amp;ldquo;remove it from the heat when it&amp;rsquo;s done&amp;rdquo;) we had a very nice lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/HandoverSalad.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Salmon &amp;amp; Salad&#34; title=&#34;Salmon and Salad&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are parallels between this, and what I was struggling with last week (hurrah, we get to the tenuous analogy!).  I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying
to do my first release for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/morphia&#34;&gt;Morphia&lt;/a&gt;, the project I&amp;rsquo;m taking over
for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.  I know my colleague was working hard on an automated release script (one click releasing FTW),
and I know he invested a reasonable amount of time in automating the release process (this is code for &amp;ldquo;I had a bad feeling about this&amp;rdquo;).
I was going to be the first to try this out without his machine/settings/user. Yay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday night Justin gave me some tips of what was involved, finishing with &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;and then &lt;code&gt;.gradlew relase&lt;/code&gt; should just work&amp;rdquo;.  Simples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day One: I struggled with the nexus plugin and permissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Two: I woke up with one of those ideas that hit you in the night and fixed that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I spent two days trying to work out why the Git plugin wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me log in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I realised that for the whole time I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been using the local version of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evanchooly/github-release-gradle-plugin&#34;&gt;gradle release plugin&lt;/a&gt; like I thought,
but an older version. When I fixed that&amp;hellip; I spent half a day proving I still had the same issue as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I commented out the code that wasn&amp;rsquo;t working, hard coded a bunch of values and used an old script to upload the Javadoc (don&amp;rsquo;t
get me started on how long it took me to find how &lt;a href=&#34;http://maven.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Maven&lt;/a&gt; was populating the release number,
nor do I want to express the pain I felt at having to install Maven after being in love with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gradle.org/&#34;&gt;Gradle&lt;/a&gt; for the
last two years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/morphia/releases/tag/r0.108&#34;&gt;release 0.108 of Morphia&lt;/a&gt; went live on Thursday night - huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, as a responsible human being, rather than high-fiving myself, cracking open a bottle of wine and knocking off for the
weekend, next I need to prepare the handover for the next person doing the release. Not least because it&amp;rsquo;s probably going to be me,
and my memory is shocking.  I have two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a wiki page with the steps needed, manual or automated, including all the local properties that need to be set up as we can&amp;rsquo;t
have some of these passwords floating around on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the automated release so it really is one click / command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, option 2 still needs documentation because of the local properties that are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really want to do is crack open that wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the moral of the story is: handovers are hard.  And essential.  And worse, often the person doing the handing over is doing so
because they&amp;rsquo;re short on time and, for whatever reason, not responsible for the next phase of the project. Combine this lack of time with
all the assumptions and implicit knowledge in that person&amp;rsquo;s head, and the information being transferred is likely to be&amp;hellip; less than
optimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the handover receiver is now responsible for something they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough knowledge of and they&amp;rsquo;re not even aware of assumptions or
unknown unknowns. If you&amp;rsquo;re handing over between departments or teams, they might not even have the right tools to find out how to
progress (Ops teams and testers don&amp;rsquo;t always have access to the code, for example, and if they did might not have the context to find it
useful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tools to help ease the pain of handovers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/PairProgrammingMisconceptions.html&#34;&gt;Pairing&lt;/a&gt;. Pairing might seem expensive (two people at one
keyboard?? How will they type fast enough?), but the savings in handover time (and increase in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia
.org/wiki/Bus_factor&#34;&gt;Bus Factor&lt;/a&gt;) make it completely worthwhile.  Pairing with The Boy in making salad meant at least I knew what the steps and
ingredients were, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what stage we were at. At LMAX, we reduced a lot of our testing backlog by embedding the testers
in the development team, and pairing with them at the start and at the end of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/UserStory.html&#34;&gt;user stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t do pairing, code reviews help. I was at least aware of our release plugin as I&amp;rsquo;d seen the original develop in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/&#34;&gt;Java
driver&lt;/a&gt;. If I&amp;rsquo;d been pairing or code reviewing on Morphia,
I would have been even more aware of what the steps were and what changes had been made for that project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, if good old fashioned talking isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing, documentation is a good start.  And everyone who uses the docs needs to be
able to update the documentation when they find something wrong, missing, confusing, or just want to annotate it with something useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of these good practices, really what you want is to remove all possible areas of miscommunication. Computers are logical things,
 so if you can write down an exact list of steps that need to be done in order to achieve something,
you might be able to, I dunno, write that in a script, or something. If you
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321601912/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0321601912&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=M5DNVR42T66J63VO&#34;&gt;Automate All The Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0321601912&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to have these messy,
complicated conversations with these messy, complicated people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you knew that already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m off to try and fix my script. I&amp;rsquo;ve even thought of a way to not need local properties, so maybe next time (or the time after),
when I have to do a release I&amp;rsquo;ll only have to type a single command. It&amp;rsquo;ll be worth a week or two to implement this if it saves me a week
like the last one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, that wine&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;No boyfriends or colleagues were harmed in the making of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nighthacking at Sevilla Java User Group</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_jug_sevilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_jug_sevilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday &lt;a href=&#34;http://steveonjava.com/&#34;&gt;Mr Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt; came to Sevilla on his crazy European tour to show us Lego and Robots.  This was our largest turnout yet
for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Java User Group&lt;/a&gt; event in Sevilla, which surprised me as it was on a weekend,
and the weekend before the spectacle that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Week_in_Seville&#34;&gt;Semana
Santa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/I5rnDZGNJW8&#34;&gt;in Sevilla&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also the first event that we&amp;rsquo;ve had videoed (apologies for the horrible focus at times on the video,
I&amp;rsquo;m just learning and used to relying heavily on auto-focus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/q3OKs08X3oo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks very much to Stephen for visiting, and thank you to those who came, you&amp;rsquo;re making me re-think the idea of running events at
weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/photos/all_photos/?photoAlbumId=21306622&#34;&gt;photos on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, Backwards Compatibility? (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOW recorded me, yet again, talking about the adventure that is the design of the new Java Driver for MongoDB.  This is the same talk I
gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;,
with some updates based on our Journey So Far.  In it, I cover the architecture of the new driver and some of our current thoughts
around where we want the API to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yow.eventer.com/yow-2013-1080/what-do-you-mean-backwards-compatibility-by-trisha-gee-1398&#34;&gt;See the video here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Advice for Programmers (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I have a tendancy to bang on every now and again about how we, as developers, could do better in managing our careers (for example,
by &lt;a href=&#34;/post/how_to_make_your_cv_not_suck/&#34;&gt;creating CVs that don&amp;rsquo;t suck&lt;/a&gt;, and by &lt;a href=&#34;/post/staying_ahead_of_the_curve/&#34;&gt;staying ahead of the curve&lt;/a&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davethomas.net/&#34;&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/a&gt; asked me to speak for a mere 50 minutes on the subject at &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon
.com/video#36&#34;&gt;GOTO Aarhus&lt;/a&gt;, a talk I wasn&amp;rsquo;t enormously happy with as there was no way to cover a lifetime of hard-fought experience in such a short
time.  Dave seemed to like something in it though, as he gave me the opportunity to present the topic again at YOW last December,
and this time I think I managed to distill the important points into the (still ridiculously short) time allotted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yow.eventer.com/yow-2013-1080/career-advice-for-programmers-by-trisha-gee-1380&#34;&gt;See the video here&lt;/a&gt;,
and please give me any feedback you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recognise there are many many more topics I could cover, so I&amp;rsquo;d better start making a list.  Suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events 2014</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I updated you on my travel plans, so now I&amp;rsquo;ve had some more conferences confirmed,
I thought I would pass the information on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been really lucky to have been selected for some great conferences this year.  I was asked to do a few more,
and it was genuinely painful to say no to everything, but it seems the laws of space and time cannot be broken,
and so I&amp;rsquo;ve been forced to select a tiny subset of all the places I&amp;rsquo;d like to go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 May: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/presentation/HTML5,%20Angular.js,%20Groovy,%20Java,
%20MongoDB%20all%20together%20-%20what%20could%20possibly%20go%20wrong?&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;m giving the same live coding presentation from QCon London,
although knowing me I expect there will be some tweaks, changes, additions, and maybe improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22-23 May: In New York City, since I&amp;rsquo;m more or less in the area.  Gimme a shout if you want to meet for a drink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25-28 May: &lt;a href=&#34;http://speakerconf.com/&#34;&gt;SpeakerConf&lt;/a&gt; Barcelona.  And while I&amp;rsquo;m in the area&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29 May: Barcelona JUG - &amp;ldquo;HTML5, Angular.js, Groovy, Java, MongoDB all together - what could possibly go wrong?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-5 June: New York City, probably (wait, am I going to be at home at all??)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23 July: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2014/public/schedule/detail/35444&#34;&gt;OSCON&lt;/a&gt; - live coding again!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;28 Sep - 2 Oct: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/speakers/index.html#gee&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt; woohoo!  I love having this opportunity to visit San
Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple of other events I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to work out the details for, but I think this is 2014 all booked up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
