<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 8</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_8/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving a presentation showing &amp;ldquo;Java 8 in Anger&amp;rdquo; - no, it&amp;rsquo;s not that the most recent release of Java has me
particularly enraged, &amp;ldquo;in anger&amp;rdquo; is (apparently) a British phrase meaning &amp;ldquo;in practice&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;in the real world&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of this talk is to demo, with live code, how to use some of the Java 8 features like Lambda Expressions and
the Streams API to solve some of the coding problems you might come across in your day job as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to transcribe the whole talk for this article, it probably works best (if you&amp;rsquo;re interested) to
watch the video instead. What I do want to do is to use the application from the presentation to explore some
specific Java 8 features in more detail. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the wider context, I&amp;rsquo;ve got
&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/java8_in_anger/&#34;&gt;links to the videos and source code&lt;/a&gt; on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;method-references-and-new-methods-in-java-8:d169180f3a40e9c29149c257bc7fd971&#34;&gt;Method References and New Methods in Java 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first section where we start using some of the new methods available in Java 8 is when we&amp;rsquo;re building up a
leaderboard of top tweeters. This leaderboard will be a table of the Twitter users who have tweeted the most, in
descending order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/leaderboard.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Leaderboard&#34; title=&#34;Twitter Leaderboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We store every Twitter handle we see in as a key in a &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt;, and for
the value we have a &lt;code&gt;TwitterUser&lt;/code&gt; (an object to represent this particular user). When we
see a new Twitter handle, we want to create a &lt;code&gt;TwitterUser&lt;/code&gt; for this person and store it in the map, keyed against
this Twitter handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-Java-8, we&amp;rsquo;d write something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private final Map&amp;lt;String, TwitterUser&amp;gt; allTwitterUsers = new HashMap&amp;lt;&amp;gt;();

public void onMessage(String twitterHandle) {
    TwitterUser twitterUser = allTwitterUsers.get(twitterHandle);
    if (twitterUser == null) {
        twitterUser = new TwitterUser(twitterHandle);
        allTwitterUsers.put(twitterHandle, twitterUser);
    }
    // then do stuff...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Java 8 has not only given us lambdas and streams, it&amp;rsquo;s added new methods to some of our favourite classes.  &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt;
now has a &lt;code&gt;computeIfAbsent()&lt;/code&gt; method which allows you to define what to do if an item doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private final Map&amp;lt;String, TwitterUser&amp;gt; allTwitterUsers = new HashMap&amp;lt;&amp;gt;();

public void onMessage(String twitterHandle) {
    TwitterUser twitterUser = allTwitterUsers.computeIfAbsent(twitterHandle, 
                                                              TwitterUser::new);
    // then do stuff...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does the same thing as the first example and is clearly far fewer lines of code, especially as it also makes use
of &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/javaOO/methodreferences.html&#34;&gt;Method References&lt;/a&gt;, which usually work
out to be even shorter than lambda expressions. As a long-term Java programmer with limited exposure to other
languages, although this may be shorter, learning to write code this way is going to take me a while to get used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me and my old-school Java approach, &lt;a href=&#34;www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; can help me get to
grips with the new syntax. When I first came to Java 8, I found it more understandable (although &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more code)
to call these sorts of methods using an anonymous inner class rather than a lambda expression or a method reference.
IntelliJ IDEA can help create this anonymous inner class and convert it into something more Java 8-ish:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/ReplaceWithMethodReference.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Convert to method reference&#34; title=&#34;Convert to method reference&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Method references are going to take me a while to grasp instinctively, but I am starting to see how the succinct
syntax could be more expressive, once I get used to it - &lt;code&gt;computeifAbsent()&lt;/code&gt; is going to call a constructor on
&lt;code&gt;TwitterUser&lt;/code&gt; to create a new user if one doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist in the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;streams:d169180f3a40e9c29149c257bc7fd971&#34;&gt;Streams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we need to increment the number of times we&amp;rsquo;ve seen
this &lt;code&gt;TwitterUser&lt;/code&gt;, and then figure out how this impacts our leaderboard of tweeters. We can use the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/ma14-java-se-8-streams-2177646.html&#34;&gt;Streams API&lt;/a&gt; to
turn our map of all Twitter users into a list of the top ten Tweeters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we need to sort our &lt;code&gt;TwitterUsers&lt;/code&gt; according to the number of times they&amp;rsquo;ve tweeted.
There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;code&gt;sorted()&lt;/code&gt; method on &lt;code&gt;Stream&lt;/code&gt; which takes a &lt;code&gt;Comparator&lt;/code&gt;, so it seems logical to use this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public void onMessage(String twitterHandle) {
    TwitterUser twitterUser = allTwitterUsers.computeIfAbsent(twitterHandle, TwitterUser::new);
    twitterUser.incrementCount();

    allTwitterUsers.values().stream()
                   .sorted(new Comparator&amp;lt;TwitterUser&amp;gt;() {
                       @Override
                       public int compare(TwitterUser o1, TwitterUser o2) {
                           return o2.getNumberOfTweets() - o1.getNumberOfTweets();
                       }
                   });
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found comparators a little hard to work with - I&amp;rsquo;m never quite sure if I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be
subtracting the first object from the second, or vice versa.  Fortunately, once again Java 8 makes things a little
easier. You can use the new &lt;code&gt;Comparator.comparing()&lt;/code&gt; method, which you can combine with a method reference to state
which method on &lt;code&gt;TwitterUser&lt;/code&gt; you want to sort by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;allTwitterUsers.values().stream()
               .sorted(Comparator.comparing(TwitterUser::getNumberOfTweets));
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a leaderboard which shows the most active tweeters at the top, we need to sort in descending order, which is also
simple and descriptive using this method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;allTwitterUsers.values().stream()
               .sorted(comparing(TwitterUser::getNumberOfTweets).reversed());
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I&amp;rsquo;ve added a static import for &lt;code&gt;comparing&lt;/code&gt; to make the code a bit shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;rsquo;ve sorted all the values in the map, now we need to just get the top ten. Since we&amp;rsquo;re using Streams, it&amp;rsquo;s easy
to chain together all the operations we want to perform on our collection, so we add a call to &lt;code&gt;limit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;allTwitterUsers.values().stream()
               .sorted(comparing(TwitterUser::getNumberOfTweets).reversed())
               .limit(10);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far all we&amp;rsquo;ve done is build up a recipe for the operations we want to perform, we need to somehow execute all of
these. Streams have intermediate operations which return a &lt;code&gt;Stream&lt;/code&gt; so that we can perform further operations (for
example, both &lt;code&gt;sorted()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;limit()&lt;/code&gt; above), and terminal operations which will return some concrete value. In this
case, what we want is a new list with these top ten tweeters. Telling the &lt;code&gt;collect&lt;/code&gt; method to put the results
into a &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; will do just this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;List&amp;lt;TwitterUser&amp;gt; topTen = allTwitterUsers.values().stream()
                                          .sorted(comparing(TwitterUser::getNumberOfTweets).reversed())
                                          .limit(10)
                                          .collect(Collectors.toList());
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this set of stream operations, we&amp;rsquo;re effectively querying our map of all users. If we were querying a
database instead of a map, we might have written something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * from TwitterUsers
ORDER BY numberOfTweets DESC
LIMIT 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how we built the whole operation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/Streams.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Using Streams&#34; title=&#34;Using Streams&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creating-our-own-streams:d169180f3a40e9c29149c257bc7fd971&#34;&gt;Creating our own Streams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of this application requires a bar chart, where each bar corresponds to a minute in time over a period
of ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/bar-chart.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bar Chart Widget&#34; title=&#34;Bar Chart Widget&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the application starts for the first time, each of these bars needs to be set to an initial value of zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not an unusual situation - we&amp;rsquo;ve probably all written code that has to loop for some number of iterations and
initialise some value.  We would probably usually do it using something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public HappinessChartData() {
    int nowMinute = LocalDateTime.now().getMinute();

    for (int i = nowMinute; i &amp;lt; nowMinute + 10; i++) {
        initialiseBarToZero(i);
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we also use a very small part of the new
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/jf14-date-time-2125367.html&#34;&gt;Date &amp;amp; Time API&lt;/a&gt;.  In the Java 8 world, we
have more options for iterating over values.  In this case, we can create our own &lt;code&gt;IntStream&lt;/code&gt; from a range of
values and perform some operation for each of these values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public HappinessChartData() {
    int nowMinute = LocalDateTime.now().getMinute();

    IntStream.range(nowMinute, nowMinute + 10)
             .forEach(value -&amp;gt; initialiseBarToZero(value));
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can use a lambda expression to specify what to do with each of the values.  As before, we can also
simplify this lambda expression to a method reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    IntStream.range(nowMinute, nowMinute + 10)
             .forEach(this::initialiseBarToZero);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method of iterating is marginally less code, and, once we get used to the new syntax, arguably more readable.
The performance of the two methods is not the same, however, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to decide which method to use based on
your team&amp;rsquo;s preferences for syntax and the performance requirements of your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/CreateStream.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Create a Stream&#34; title=&#34;Create a Stream&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;file-handling-in-java-8:d169180f3a40e9c29149c257bc7fd971&#34;&gt;File Handling in Java 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java 7 introduced some really nice features for file handling. Working with files has become even
more intuitive when you combine these Java 7 features with streams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we&amp;rsquo;re parsing a file which contains Tweets recorded from the Twitter firehose.  Each line contains a
different tweet, and what we want to do is filter out the noise (there are lines that contain only the single String
&amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; as a response from Twitter) and then publish the remaining tweets via websockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    try (Stream&amp;lt;String&amp;gt; lines = Files.lines(filePath)) {
        lines.filter(s -&amp;gt; !s.equals(&amp;quot;OK&amp;quot;))
             .forEach(tweetsEndpoint::onMessage);
    } catch (IOException e) {
        //error handling here
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I&amp;rsquo;m not tempted to show the Java 6 version of the code, as the Java 8 version is much simpler.  The first line
uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/essential/exceptions/tryResourceClose.html&#34;&gt;try-with-resources&lt;/a&gt;
to obtain a strea, of &lt;code&gt;Strings&lt;/code&gt;, one string per line in our file.  Then we use the &lt;code&gt;filter()&lt;/code&gt;
method to exclude the lines that aren&amp;rsquo;t tweets, and finally publish all the remaining tweets via our websocket
server endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/Java7And8.gif&#34; alt=&#34;File handling with Java 8&#34; title=&#34;File handling with Java 8&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;advanced-streams-and-more-collectors:d169180f3a40e9c29149c257bc7fd971&#34;&gt;Advanced Streams and More Collectors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part of the application that I&amp;rsquo;d like to show you in more depth, is the mood analyser.  The aim of
this small service is to take a single Tweet and figure out the mood of that Tweet in a very rough fashion.  It will
generally decide if a single Tweet is &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;sad&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;happy &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; sad&amp;rdquo;, and return a comma separated String of
the mood in upper case. So for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;would be classified as &amp;ldquo;HAPPY&amp;rdquo;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m irritated I have to work tomorrow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;would be &amp;ldquo;SAD&amp;rdquo;, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start of this week was fantastic, but today sucks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;contains both good and bad news, so would be &amp;ldquo;HAPPY,SAD&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had an automated system for applying moods to Twitter messages, I&amp;rsquo;d be retired on a beach
somewhere, this kind of analysis is very much in demand.  In my application, I settle instead for a very crude method
of classifying the messages - we&amp;rsquo;re going to parse the message and look for words that might imply &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;sad&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start with a &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt;, which maps words to their associated mood (represented as an enum).  Something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[&amp;quot;happy&amp;quot;: HAPPY,
 &amp;quot;fantastic&amp;quot;: HAPPY,
 &amp;quot;awesome&amp;quot;: HAPPY,
 ...
 &amp;quot;sad&amp;quot;: SAD,
 &amp;quot;terrible&amp;quot;: SAD,
 &amp;quot;sucks&amp;quot;: SAD]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of approaches to this problem, this is not a definitive answer. I will demonstrate
with my selected method how you can chain together stream operations to get the output that you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we create a stream where each item is a word in the original Twitter message.  We use &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;split()&lt;/code&gt;
method to create an array of words, and use &lt;code&gt;Stream.of()&lt;/code&gt; to turn this into a &lt;code&gt;Stream&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;code&gt;Strings&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we&amp;rsquo;re going to convert all these words to lowercase, as our map of words to moods only has lowercase keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
      .map(String::toLowerCase)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;map()&lt;/code&gt; method takes one value and turns it into another.  In this case, we want to turn a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; value like
&amp;ldquo;Awesome&amp;rdquo; into its lowercase version, &amp;ldquo;awesome&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s easy pass in String&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;toLowerCase()&lt;/code&gt; method as a method
reference to do the conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a string in the correct case, we can search our map of words-to-moods for the mood that corresponds to
this word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
      .map(String::toLowerCase)
      .map((lowerCaseWord) -&amp;gt; WORD_TO_MOOD.get(lowerCaseWord))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every word is going to have a corresponding mood in the map, so we&amp;rsquo;re only going to pass non-null moods to the
next step of the pipeline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
      .map(String::toLowerCase)
      .map((lowerCaseWord) -&amp;gt; WORD_TO_MOOD.get(lowerCaseWord))
      .filter(mood -&amp;gt; mood != null)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what I have is a &lt;code&gt;Mood&lt;/code&gt;, an enum value of either &lt;code&gt;HAPPY&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;SAD&lt;/code&gt;. Our requirements state that for each tweet, we
need to return one of &amp;ldquo;HAPPY&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;SAD&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;HAPPY,SAD&amp;rdquo;. We don&amp;rsquo;t need an indication of whether there are multiple happy
words or sad words in the same tweet, so we only need one instance of each mood. This is easily done by requiring the
stream to contain only distinct values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
      .map(String::toLowerCase)
      .map((lowerCaseWord) -&amp;gt; WORD_TO_MOOD.get(lowerCaseWord))
      .filter(mood -&amp;gt; mood != null)
      .distinct()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to our requirements, we need to convert our enum value to a String&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
      .map(String::toLowerCase)
      .map((lowerCaseWord) -&amp;gt; WORD_TO_MOOD.get(lowerCaseWord))
      .filter(mood -&amp;gt; mood != null)
      .distinct()
      .map((mood) -&amp;gt; mood.name())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, we want to merge together all the moods found for this message into a comma separated string of moods.
In our previous Stream example, we used &lt;code&gt;Collectors.toList()&lt;/code&gt; to return a &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt;
of &lt;code&gt;TwitterUsers&lt;/code&gt;. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re going to use another built in collector, &lt;code&gt;Collectors.joining()&lt;/code&gt; and give it the
characters we want to use to separate our results. &lt;code&gt;joining()&lt;/code&gt; will return a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; of your results, separated by
your chosen delimiter. Which means that now in Java 8 we can easily create comma separated strings without having to
iterate over a list and figure out if we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be putting a comma after this item or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
      .map(String::toLowerCase)
      .map((lowerCaseWord) -&amp;gt; WORD_TO_MOOD.get(lowerCaseWord))
      .filter(mood -&amp;gt; mood != null)
      .distinct()
      .map((mood) -&amp;gt; mood.name())
      .collect(Collectors.joining(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;));
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let&amp;rsquo;s simplify the lambdas to method references where possible, and turn this into a method we can use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public static String identifyMood(String twitterMessage) {
    return Stream.of(twitterMessage.split(&amp;quot;\\s+&amp;quot;))
                 .map(String::toLowerCase)
                 .map(WORD_TO_MOOD::get)
                 .filter(mood -&amp;gt; mood != null)
                 .distinct()
                 .map(Enum::name)
                 .collect(joining(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;));
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we called &lt;code&gt;identifyMood&lt;/code&gt; with the message &amp;ldquo;Yesterday I was sad sad sad, but today is awesome&amp;rdquo;, we&amp;rsquo;ll get the
String &amp;ldquo;SAD,HAPPY&amp;rdquo; in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8/AdvancedStreams.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Advanced Streams&#34; title=&#34;Advanced Streams&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this example we have seen how you can chain multiple operations to perform fairly complex processing, with limited
lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary:d169180f3a40e9c29149c257bc7fd971&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java 8 is more than just a bit of extra syntax to learn, or a couple of new methods that might be useful.
It can change the way we approach solving common problems. With lambda expressions, streams and some of the other
new methods in Java 8, you can use easily perform common operations (for example, &lt;code&gt;computeIfAbsent()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;joining()&lt;/code&gt;),
and you gain a new set of tools, particularly in manipulating data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extraordinary Team Of Developers</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/the_extraordinary_team_of_developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/the_extraordinary_team_of_developers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Bryant and I did a keynote at Devoxx UK about how individuals can add something to a team to make the team
more productive, and overall more awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div data-parleys-presentation=&#34;keynote-extraordinary-team-developers&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;height:300px&#34;&gt;&lt;script type = &#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;//parleys.com/js/parleys-share.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parleys.com/play/keynote-extraordinary-team-developers&#34;&gt;Watch on Parleys.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We mention a number of books, so I&amp;rsquo;ve made a list of them here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1594484805/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1594484805&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=GSO6AH7236C37XUL&#34;&gt;Drive: The Surprising Truth About What Motivates
Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1594484805&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1491919019/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1491919019&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=S3PUS65PBYMVIK4U&#34;&gt;Badass: Making Users Awesome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img 
src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1491919019&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316346624/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0316346624&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=JSKRNEPP3R3RTZH4&#34;&gt;The Tipping Point: How Little Things Can Make a
Big Difference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0316346624&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321356683/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0321356683&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=WFSI2OVJKEBPD7YA&#34;&gt;Effective Java (2nd Edition)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img 
src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0321356683&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0982201222/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0982201222&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=26DOP5D3JV2MWTGW&#34;&gt;The Servant as Leader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na
.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0982201222&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591842697/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1591842697&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=NJ42CVES4P6F7FEA&#34;&gt;The Back of the Napkin: Solving Problems and Selling Ideas with Pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1591842697&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract:55bdc67688424da8fd656071ea3cbd85&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rock stars are dead. Ninjas are banished. There are simply too many trashed hotel rooms, dead bodies and failed
projects. The age of the individual superhero coder is over.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But if we’re still striving for excellence, what’s replaced the rock-star-ninja-hero programmer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The team. The team that’s greater than the sum of its parts. Like The Avengers, but with less latex.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the same way those without super powers, genius levels of intelligence and pots of money were vital to The
Avengers, every developer, no matter how much or how little experience they have, brings something important to the
team and has the potential to make it better: a nicer place to work, an openness to learning, a focus on clean code or a deeper understanding of the business’ needs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can a collection of good developers become a super-performing business-impact-delivering team? What do you, as
an individual, add to the mix?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daniel and Trisha will share stories of individuals and teams who have made an impact (both good and bad!) and offer
  suggestions for steps we, as individuals, can take to level up our teams.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Reviews 1</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/other-sites/code_reviews1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/other-sites/code_reviews1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about code reviews. If you take only a few seconds to search for information about code reviews, you&amp;rsquo;ll
see a lot of information about why code reviews are a Good Thing (for example,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codinghorror.com/code-reviews-just-do-it/&#34;&gt;this article by Jeff Atwood&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also see a lot of documentation on how to use Code Review tools like our very own
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/upsource/&#34;&gt;Upsource&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you don&amp;rsquo;t see so much of, is a guide to things to look for when you&amp;rsquo;re reviewing someone else&amp;rsquo;s code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the reason there&amp;rsquo;s no definitive article on what to be looking for is: there are a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;
of different things to consider. And, like any other set of requirements (functional or non-functional), individual
organisations will have different priorities for each aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this is a big topic to cover, the aim of this article is to outline just some of the things a reviewer could be
looking out for when performing a code review. Deciding on the priority of each aspect and checking them
consistently is a sufficiently complex subject to be an article in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-you-look-for-when-you-re-reviewing-someone-else-s-code:cd9fea566ab5046299e94562e7428608&#34;&gt;What do you look for when you&amp;rsquo;re reviewing someone else&amp;rsquo;s code?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how you&amp;rsquo;re reviewing code: via a tool like Upsource or Github pull requests; during someone else&amp;rsquo;s
walkthrough or demo of their code; sitting down with a colleague and checking through their changes; even looking
at code on StackOverflow. Whatever the situation, some things are easier to comment on than others. Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt;: Where are the spaces and line breaks? Are they using tabs or spaces? How are the curly braces laid
out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Style&lt;/strong&gt;: Are the variables/parameters declared as final? Are method variables defined close to the code where
they&amp;rsquo;re used or at the start of the method?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naming&lt;/strong&gt;: Do the field/constant/variable/param/class names conform to standards? Are the names overly short?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: Is there a test for this code?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all valid things to check to ensure the code is consistent with the rest of your codebase, to make it
easier for team members to understand - you want to reduce context switching between different areas of code and
reduce &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_load&#34;&gt;cognitive load&lt;/a&gt;, so the more consistent your code looks, the
better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, having humans check these is probably not the best use of time and resources in your organisation.  Although
a code review process that checks these kinds of properties will improve the overall quality of your code, many of
these checks can be
automated. This takes a little bit of work up-front, but pays off very quickly.  Tools like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://checkstyle.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Checkstyle&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;FindBugs&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pmd.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;PMD&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://codenarc.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;CodeNarc&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://emma.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cobertura.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Cobertura&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclemma.org/jacoco/&#34;&gt;JaCoCo&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sonarqube.org/&#34;&gt;SonarQube&lt;/a&gt; can, especially when combined, check that your code is
consistently formatted, that standards
around naming and the use of the final keyword are followed, and that common bugs caused by simple
programming errors are found. You can even run
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/running-inspections-offline.html&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&amp;rsquo;s inspections from the command line&lt;/a&gt;,
so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on all team members having the same inspections running in their IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-should-you-look-for:cd9fea566ab5046299e94562e7428608&#34;&gt;What should you look for?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we&amp;rsquo;ve just talked about what it&amp;rsquo;s easy to look for, and that you should consider using tools other than code
review to check these automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What sort of things are humans really good for? What can we spot in a code review that we can&amp;rsquo;t delegate to a tool?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out there&amp;rsquo;s a surprisingly large number of things. This is certainly not an exhaustive list, nor will
we go into any one of them in great detail here. Instead, this should be the start of a conversation in your
organisation about which things you currently look for in a code review, and what, perhaps, you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design:cd9fea566ab5046299e94562e7428608&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the new code fit with the overall architecture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the code follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOLID_(object-oriented_design)&#34;&gt;SOLID principles&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-driven_design&#34;&gt;Domain Driven Design&lt;/a&gt; and/or other design paradigms the team
favours?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_design_pattern&#34;&gt;design patterns&lt;/a&gt; are used in the new code? Are these
appropriate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the codebase has a mix of standards or design styles, does this new code follow the current practices? Is the
code migrating in the correct direction, or does it follow the example of older code that is due to be phased out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the code in the right place? For example, if the code is related to Orders, is it in the Order Service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could the new code have reused something in the existing code? Does the new code provide something
we can reuse in the existing code? Does the new code introduce duplication? If so, should it be refactored to a more
reusable pattern, or is this acceptable at this stage?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the code over-engineered? Does it build for reusability that isn&amp;rsquo;t required now? How does the team balance
considerations of reusability with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_aren%27t_gonna_need_it&#34;&gt;YAGNI&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;readability-maintainability:cd9fea566ab5046299e94562e7428608&#34;&gt;Readability &amp;amp; Maintainability&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the names (of fields, variables, parameters, methods and classes) actually reflect the thing they represent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I understand what the code does by reading it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I understand what the tests do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the tests cover a good subset of cases? Do they cover happy paths and exceptional cases? Are there cases that
haven&amp;rsquo;t been considered?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are the exception error messages understandable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are confusing sections of code either documented, commented, or covered by understandable tests (according to team
preference)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;functionality:cd9fea566ab5046299e94562e7428608&#34;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the code actually do what it was supposed to do? If there are automated tests to ensure correctness of the
code, do the tests really test the code meets the agreed requirements?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the code look like it contains subtle bugs, like using the wrong variable for a check, or accidentally using
an &lt;code&gt;and&lt;/code&gt; instead of an &lt;code&gt;or&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;have-you-thought-about:cd9fea566ab5046299e94562e7428608&#34;&gt;Have you thought about&amp;hellip;?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there potential security problems with the code?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there regulatory requirements that need to be met?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For areas that are not covered with automated performance tests, does the new code introduce avoidable performance
issues, like unnecessary calls to a database or remote service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the author need to create public documentation, or change existing help files?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have user-facing messages been checked for correctness?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there obvious errors that will stop this working in production? Is the code going to accidentally point at
the test database, or is there a hardcoded stub that should be swapped out for a real service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; code is a topic that every developer has an opinion on. We&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you in the comments
if you have things to add to our list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 8 MOOC - Session 1 Summary</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_8_mooc_session1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_8_mooc_session1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Sevilla Java User Group&lt;/a&gt; is working together towards completing the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apexapps.oracle.com/pls/apex/f?p=44785:145:0::::P145_EVENT_ID,P145_PREV_PAGE:4887,143&#34;&gt;Java 8 MOOC&lt;/a&gt; on
lambdas and streams. As part of this, we&amp;rsquo;re running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/events/223677436/&#34;&gt;three sessions&lt;/a&gt;
during the course so we can, as a group, ask  questions about the lectures, get help with the homework, and (if we&amp;rsquo;re
feeling very smart!) help people who may be struggling (or might not have watched the videos).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night we had the first session which went really well. We had a small-ish group, about half of whom had
completed the homework and the quiz (for the first lesson) and half had not. We worked through the homework exercises
together, saw how there were multiple solutions for each problem, and explored how to balance conciseness with
longer, more descriptive code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;First offline session for lesson 1 of the lambdas and streams mooc &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/java8?src=hash&#34;&gt;#java8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/40gradosAlaSombra?src=hash&#34;&gt;#40gradosAlaSombra&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/hJgPrLl3C5&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/hJgPrLl3C5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SVQ JUG (@SVQJUG) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SVQJUG/status/623199430158778368&#34;&gt;July 20, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the whole people thought the videos for the course were very clear and well-explained, although we also went
through how to run the videos at 1.5 speed, as most people wanted to run through them faster! I thought the pace of the
videos was especially good for those who aren&amp;rsquo;t so comfortable with listening in English, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to add
subtitles and speed it up if you feel comfortable with the material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lesson covers lambdas, and their use in some of the new Java 8 methods (specifically on collections, but
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; streams).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The areas we discussed most, the ones that needed more clarity were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/lang/FunctionalInterface.html&#34;&gt;Functional Interfaces&lt;/a&gt;:
what does &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/introduction-functional-1&#34;&gt;Single Abstract Method (SAM)&lt;/a&gt; really mean? Also, we
were interested in the &amp;ldquo;exception&amp;rdquo; of methods declared on &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt; as well as an interface (e.g. &lt;code&gt;equals()&lt;/code&gt;), but we
came
to the conclusion that it was easier to simply think of looking for only one method without any form of
implementation at all - methods defined on &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt; must have an implementation, since &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt; is not an
abstract class or interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/javaOO/methodreferences.html&#34;&gt;Method References&lt;/a&gt;: we looked at
examples of the three types that aren&amp;rsquo;t constructor references, what they look like in lambda form and how they
differ. Method references are&amp;hellip; not difficult to understand, but do look a bit awkward in the code if you&amp;rsquo;re not
used to them, and can be confusing as all your types, parameters and return values disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallel execution: The first lesson talks a lot about how lambdas are here to make parallelisation and
concurrency easier for developers, so obviously there was a question about how the code in the homework examples would
be executed in a multi-CPU environment. I assumed (although I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for clarification) that methods like
&lt;code&gt;removeIf&lt;/code&gt; are not parallelised, since in the case of Streams you have to explicitly state you want to go parallel.
We also talked a bit about
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/util/stream/BaseStream.html#parallel--&#34;&gt;parallel()&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/util/Collection.html#parallelStream--&#34;&gt;parallelStream()&lt;/a&gt;, even
though the lesson didn&amp;rsquo;t cover Streams at all. We wanted to understand a bit more about the pros and cons of going
parallel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I also snuck in some demos of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; awesomeness, including
its magical support for creating lambdas and turning things into (and from) method references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/java8mooc/ReplaceWithMethodReferenceMac.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Converting code to Java 8&#34; title=&#34;Converting code to Java 8&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great, collaborative session, with most people getting a chance to demonstrate their code (if they wanted
to!). And at the end we had solutions to the five exercise problems and had discussed all the areas people wanted
more clarity on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by InfoQ</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_for_infoq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_for_infoq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was at QCon New York (probably my business conference this year!) I was
interviewed by Ralph Winzinger for InfoQ. It felt like a short interview at the time,
but we covered a lot of ground - Java 8, Java vs other JVM languages, the effectiveness
of the JCP, and the future of Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video and the transcript are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/interviews/trisha-gee-java-eco-system&#34;&gt;available on InfoQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Path To Evangelism</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/becoming_an_evangelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/becoming_an_evangelist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I get asked a lot about how I got into technical advocacy /
evangelism&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;,
so it seems like the most cost-effective way to answer this question is to
write a post about it. Warning: it&amp;rsquo;s a long one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let me caveat this (I always have caveats, don&amp;rsquo;t I?) with, &amp;ldquo;this is
my personal experience&amp;rdquo;.  There may be other ways to get into this role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any long-time readers of the blog (I love you guys!!) will
know that I started blogging before I did any of this
running-around-the-world-speaking-at-conferences lark.  I started blogging
for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even &amp;ldquo;back then&amp;rdquo; (probably around 2007), it was definitely an advantage to
have something external to the day job to differentiate you from other job
candidates.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel comfortable with open source, Stack Overflow
wasn&amp;rsquo;t invented yet (and even if it had been, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I would have felt
knowledgeable enough to answer questions), and most of what I had learnt in
order to level-up my skills
was via blogs like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/&#34;&gt;Joel Spolsky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://randsinrepose.com/&#34;&gt;Rands in Repose&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed writing. One of the (many) things I had wanted to be
&amp;ldquo;when I grew up&amp;rdquo; was a writer or a journalist. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take that path
because I thought if I did I would be Poor Forever.  However, if I started
practising my writing in a blog, I would learn to find my voice, and have
something to show book publishers if I ever did get around to writing a
book, like I had always wanted to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If  you&amp;rsquo;ve ever started a blog, you know the problem is thinking of things to
write about. I generally documented things I&amp;rsquo;d had difficulty getting
working, because a) if I had trouble with the existing documentation, other
people would too and b) I have a memory like a goldfish, so it would be
useful for me if nothing else. But it took me years to really take the blog
seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2008, I joined the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;, largely
because I had returned to London from a year working in New York, and a) I needed a new job (during
the height of the crisis, when my recent experience was all financial
markets!) and b) although I had friends in London, I needed to rebuild my
social networks, and I was using meetup.com to do this. I tried lots of other
meetup groups, but like many geeks, I found it hard to connect to people
without the common ground of tech or code to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I ended up working for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lmax.com/&#34;&gt;LMAX Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, and
because we were always looking
for keen, bright developers, I started getting much more involved in the LJC
so that I could help us hire people I actually wanted to work with. During
this time, people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karianna&#34;&gt;Martijn&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kittylyst&#34;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jr0cket&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;
and, of course, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bcrecworks&#34;&gt;Barry&lt;/a&gt; were
encouraging me, consciously or not, to do a bit of technical presenting. I saw
a lot of different talks there, some from professional evangelists from
vendors, but many from &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; developers like me. It made me think that
a) I should do this (awesome for your profile/career etc) and b) I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt;
do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I saw very few women presenting (I do remember an
awesome presentation from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fabianenardon&#34;&gt;Fabiane&lt;/a&gt;) and
also very few women members. Many members
assumed I was a recruiter, even before I started trying to chat to people
to, well, recruit them for LMAX. In the first 2 minutes of meeting someone,
if they didn&amp;rsquo;t ask me directly if I was in recruitment or HR, I would always
make it clear that I was a Java developer. It was tedious but something I
just got used to. Interestingly, once it was clear I was a Java person,
people seemed to accept that and just treat me like any other techie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is one of the reasons I decided to start doing presentations - I
could a) show my own technical credentials, so I would spend less time having
these tiresome conversations (which, by the way, seems to have worked) and
b) make it more normal to see women techies, hopefully minimising the number
times other women faced the same assumptions (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this worked or
not, as I only have my own experiences to look at).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these thoughts were only floating around my mind, I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually
&lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; anything.  During this time, while working at LMAX, it seemed like there were lots of
things I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; blog about, or talk about, but I never really got round to it.
Plus, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure what I was allowed to talk about and what I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be
talking about. So apparently during these two years I only wrote a total of 6
posts, and I never did a single presentation at the LJC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I really wanted to do presenting and have time/inspiration for the
blog, so I chose to leave LMAX and join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtworks.com/&#34;&gt;ThoughtWorks&lt;/a&gt; - they were looking for
consultants and I knew this was a company that valued blogging and
presenting, and I&amp;rsquo;d had some exposure to their guys through the LJC and,
years before, I&amp;rsquo;d seen them speaking at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2007/03/qcon-london.html&#34;&gt;QCon London&lt;/a&gt;,
which had actually been my initial inspiration for blogging.
I told LMAX that was why I was leaving, and off I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s 2011, and I&amp;rsquo;ve joined ThoughtWorks. I revived the blog while I was
unassigned to a project, I invested that time in porting the blog to a
more sensible platform, and trying to write a blog a day. Again, I picked
topics I could comfortably talk about - I spoke about my experiences as a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_experiences_with_android_development/&#34;&gt;beginner trying Android for the first
time&lt;/a&gt; (sometimes people will be arsey
with beginners, but in reality many real human beings can&amp;rsquo;t tell you you&amp;rsquo;re
wrong when you&amp;rsquo;re just talking about your own experiences), and despite my
original intent to blog with zero gender identity (I was genuinely afraid
that if I wrote about tech subjects and I was wrong, or very junior, I would
give women programmers a bad name) I decided to blog about &amp;ldquo;the women in
technology subject&amp;rdquo;. Again, here I went for my personal opinion/experiences,
for which only mean people can criticise you (mean people are easier to
ignore than correct people :) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also fortunate enough to meet &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt;
in person while he was over
in London. We were talking over drinks (this is London, after all) about the
women in technology thing (ThoughtWorks are really big on this subject, and
determined to do something positive in this area), and I was complaining about
the lack of women at a particular conference. He asked me if I had submitted
a talk for the conference.  Me?? Of course not! I&amp;rsquo;m not ready for that! I&amp;rsquo;ve
got nothing to talk about. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been given permission to do this, or
guidance on how to do it. I haven&amp;rsquo;t even presented at the user group yet. But
it did make me think - I said I wanted to present, so what was stopping me?
Did I need someone to guide me through it, to assign it to me as a task? It
was going to be up to me to make this happen. And if Martin Fowler, who
had just met me 5 minutes beforehand, thinks I&amp;rsquo;m ready to do this, then who&amp;rsquo;s
to tell me I&amp;rsquo;m not? What&amp;rsquo;s the worst that could happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course life then got in the way - I was assigned to a couple of projects,
so the blogging stopped. I was interested in attending or
speaking at conferences, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to have anything ThoughtWorksy to
talk about for quite a while. And now, because I was commuting to my assigned
project, I had very little time even for the LJC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, LMAX called
to let me know that the talk they&amp;rsquo;d done at QCon San Francisco,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/LMAX&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Do 100K TPS at Less than 1ms Latency&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; had been
enormously popular, and they were open sourcing
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LMAX-Exchange/disruptor&#34;&gt;The Disruptor&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to do
some evangelism around this - did I want to come back and help a) do
evangelism and b) co-ordinate the company&amp;rsquo;s evangelism?  Yes, yes I did. So,
after just 3 months, I quit TW and went back to LMAX&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at LMAX, I started to take evangelism more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to blog every week - I set aside Sundays for blogging (at the time
I was, fortunately for my particular choices, single and not overburdened
with a social life outside of the LJC). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to sit all alone in my
tiny flat, so I&amp;rsquo;d go to the pub with my shiny new Macbook Air, bought
specially for blogging (thanks ThoughtWorks, you spoiled me - I needed a mac
after I&amp;rsquo;d invested 3 months getting to grips with the one you gave me) and
write &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t always amazing, but I&amp;rsquo;d do something. During the
week, when ideas came to me, I&amp;rsquo;d make a note of the title in the blogging
tool so that when Sunday came I&amp;rsquo;d pick one and go with it.  Early on it was
fairly easy - we&amp;rsquo;d released a white paper on the Disruptor, but I found it
hard to understand what it really meant, so I spent Sundays writing shorter
articles breaking down how it worked and how to use it. I needed a LOT of
help from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.real-logic.co.uk/about.html&#34;&gt;Martin Thompson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikeb2701&#34;&gt;Mike
Barker&lt;/a&gt; to understand it, but they were patient
with me (plus I think they were happy that &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; was writing this and it
didn&amp;rsquo;t
have to be them). They took the heavier, more complicated subjects and I
pitched my stuff at developers like myself. When I ran out of Disruptor
stuff, I moved on to the topics I had in the backlog - I generally had more
ideas for blogs than time to blog, so I ended up with quite a long list to
pick from. The key is to make a note of it at the time you think of it, and
not try and think of a topic when you sit down with time to blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I coordinated our events and publicised them on the new LMAX blog I&amp;rsquo;d created.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/davefarley77&#34;&gt;Dave Farley&lt;/a&gt; was often presenting on
something Continuous Delivery related since
&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1NyUQ53&#34;&gt;his book&lt;/a&gt; had been released, and Martin was talking
about hardcore concurrency stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and I got even more involved in the LJC, not just to recruit people.  We
got involved in the JCP and OpenJDK - since LMAX was doing cutting edge
technology stuff with Java, we wanted to see where the language was going
and influence it too if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martijn must&amp;rsquo;ve got fed up my lack of drive in the presenting area, as he
pretty much forced me to do my first presentation.  In a
nice way! But he told me I was ready, he checked my content before I did it,
and I did a short talk on the JCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, my plan was to spend this first year of presenting doing short
talks at the JUG, maybe work my way up to a longer talk by the end of the year, or maybe
the following year, then the year after that to submit to conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, with amazing mentors like mine, that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. Martin Thompson was
due to
give a talk at JavaOne at the end of that year (still 2011), and I was lucky
enough to get a ticket at the last minute (we won the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.java.net/dukeschoice/2011&#34;&gt;Duke&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award
for Innovative Programming Framework&lt;/a&gt;,
and LMAX was awesome enough to let me have the ticket to the
conference to receive the award, since the evangelism efforts and blogging
had had a direct influence on us winning this award). Martin
asked if I wanted to co-present with him. Of course this was terrifying! I
hadn&amp;rsquo;t even done a full length talk at the LJC, I had barely even been to a
conference, let alone presented at the largest Java conference In The World!
So I said yes. These opportunities do not come up every week. It&amp;rsquo;s a talk
Martin had given various times before, he would be there to pick up the slack
if I freaked out, and I knew this material, I&amp;rsquo;d been blogging about it and
answering questions for the last 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really was as terrifying as I thought.  But.  It went well. I answered
difficult questions. We got great feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup/&#34;&gt;JavaOne 2011&lt;/a&gt;
was an important milestone in my evangelism career.  Not only
did I get to put this presentation on my CV, I got to meet a lot of people in
this network: Martin introduced me to a lot of high performance specialists;
Martijn and Ben introduced me to people involved in the JCP, to other Java
User Group leaders, and we somehow got in to the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly party -
I finally got to meet a book publisher and get one step closer to my dream
of writing a book. I also met the ladies behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://jduchess.org/&#34;&gt;Duchess&lt;/a&gt;,
and they introduced me to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Stephan007&#34;&gt;Stephan&lt;/a&gt; who runs Devoxx. This turned out
to be an important step in turning an idea I had for a panel into a Devoxx
reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is October.  By the end of the year I had also presented at &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/video_of_our_jax_london_session/&#34;&gt;JAX London
with Mike&lt;/a&gt;, and at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/why_we_shouldnt_target_women/&#34;&gt;Devoxx Belgium on a panel&lt;/a&gt;,
largely thanks to the contacts I
had made and the prestige of having a JavaOne talk under my belt.  So I went
from basically zero at the start of that year (my blog had been dormant for
years and I had no experience presenting) to having a blog with thousands of
hits a month and being an &amp;ldquo;international conference speaker&amp;rdquo;. In many ways I
got lucky, because the Disruptor was a really interesting, technical topic
that is in an area developers feel they should understand (high performance).
But I believe it was more a) determination to make this work, even if it
meant using my own time to write blogs and prepare presentations and b)
fantastic mentors who pushed me to do it and opened up their networks to me,
that facilitated this rapid rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, after that things were a lot easier - I had the experience
presenting at conferences, I had Martin and Martijn suggesting conferences to
me (and introducing me to the right people where appropriate), which got me
into the QCon/GOTO loop and into OSCON. With videos of my presentations
availble, combined with the reach of my blog, I also had people approaching
me to do other events, like user groups in the cities I was visiting, and
conferences I had never heard of.  I think it helped that I&amp;rsquo;m a woman,
because conferences are always actively looking to increase their diversity
(whatever it might seem like at times!), but I think that anyone could follow
these sorts of steps with a similar outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk much about my career after that, because really that&amp;rsquo;s
the tipping point - after that it was more of the same, really. I will say
that I left LMAX because the pressure to be a full time developer &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; do
advocacy is hard, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re no longer single and you don&amp;rsquo;t have
the spare time you used to have. I joined
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; because they were well known for
understanding the technical community, and because they were looking for an
evangelist who would continue to be an engineer (although not for 40 hours a
week every week). I think they might have hired me without the previous
experience, but the blogging and presenting experience was a big selling
point for the guy who became my boss.  I eventually left
them for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt; because you learn, over
time, what your sweet spots are as an advocate/educator, and what your
interests are. After two years of MongoDB, I knew I really wanted to focus
on Java and the JVM, and JetBrains is a much better fit for that. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty
certain I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have got this job without a) having the
conference-presenting experience and therefore b) being known to the team
already through the conference circuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well. That was a massive post. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off
writing this for ages. That&amp;rsquo;s just my own story, I have another post in my
head about the challenges that face you on trying to sell the value of
evangelism/advocacy to your organisation (and maybe some suggestions). But
that&amp;rsquo;s for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, I shall try to leave you with take-away points that I hope will
be helpful if you either want to become a technical advocate, or are interested
in just some aspects, like writing or presenting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a user group.  I cannot, &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; stress how important the LJC was to
my career. If you do nothing else, this is the one thing that can help you.
You will meet people who will inspire you or give you the kick up the
backside you need. Try to remember that many of these people, like me, were
developers like you before they became bloggers/authors/speakers. If they
can, you can. These people also have networks, and whether you like it or
not, it really is not what you know but who you know (but don&amp;rsquo;t let that put
you off - meeting the right people can be easier than becoming some sort of
super-expert!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present at the user group. Preferably get them to video it - you can use
this in submissions to conferences, if it&amp;rsquo;s not a blind CFP they will like to
see examples of your style. Having an example, even one that you think isn&amp;rsquo;t
awesome, is much, much better than having nothing at all. (Also, and this is
not a blog post about becoming a better speaker, but do watch your own
videos - it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;insanely&lt;/em&gt; painful the first few times, but it gets easier and
will help you to improve).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be prepared to commit your own time to this. I blogged and prepared talks
at weekends, even for companies that valued evangelism. I gave up evenings
to attend the user group.  This will be
especially important in the early days when you probably have a day job too.
This investment should pay off, either your company will learn to see the
value of it and give you more time (having developers attend and speak at the
LJC was enormously successful for recruitment for LMAX), or you will get a
job better suited to what you want to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to have something awesome to talk about. I got lucky with
the Disruptor, true. But our most in-demand topics at the Sevilla Java User
Group are &amp;ldquo;Introduction to&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; topics, especially for things that are
no-longer cutting edge - not all developers were early adopters, and now they
need an overview of &amp;ldquo;why NoSQL&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s Docker&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be awesome. Your blog doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be perfect English
(especially if you&amp;rsquo;re not a native). It just needs to clearly describe the
thing you&amp;rsquo;re trying to explain. You don&amp;rsquo;t
have to be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/author/Damian-Conway&#34;&gt;Damian Conway&lt;/a&gt;(one of
my favourite presenters) when you speak - in my experience, a presenter
can get away with either &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; great content or &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; great delivery, you
actually don&amp;rsquo;t need both. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to conferences where presenters haven&amp;rsquo;t
really had either - you have to start somewhere, and audiences are
surprisingly forgiving (especially at user groups).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find mentors. Listen to them. You might not even meet them, you can watch
what they do. But I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to find real human beings who are a step
or two closer to where you want to be. Talk to them, let them know what you
want. And let them bully you into doing scary things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be yourself. Figure out your strengths and interests, and play to them. I
was scared of being a woman developer on show, via the blog or via
conferences, but it turns out to be an advantage. I was afraid that because
I&amp;rsquo;m not Martin Thompson I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly talk about difficult technical
subjects. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be him, I can be me - I can explain things to
the level that I need to understand them, so other developers like me can
catch up with me. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to all be genius-level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do things that scare you. The terrifying things are the things that got me
the furthest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;Evangelism / Technical Advocacy - I use these terms fairly
interchangeably. Evangelism was the common name some years back, but many
are uncomfortable with the religious overtones, so instead prefer Advocacy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; This is why I often talk about being at ThoughtWorks for a
minute and a half - I really loved a lot of things about the company, but what
I really wanted to do was offered to me in a company I already knew, where I
could get going straight away without any ramp up&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/upcoming_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/upcoming_events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the list in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/public_appearances/&#34;&gt;talks section&lt;/a&gt; of my blog covers past presentations,
this page should list my confirmed upcoming events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7-8 Sep&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://swancon.co.uk/#speakers&#34;&gt;Swansea Con&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://swancon.co.uk/schedule/#session-7&#34;&gt;Level Up Your
Automated Tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11 Sep&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://theleaddeveloper.com/&#34;&gt;The Lead Developer&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://theleaddeveloper.com/talks#trishagee&#34;&gt;Staying Ahead of the Curve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25-29 Oct&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/javaone/speakers.html#gee&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt; - Java 8 in Anger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November/December&lt;/strong&gt;: Most important event to date - the arrival of our
newest family member.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level Up Your Automated Tests</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/level_up_your_automated_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/level_up_your_automated_tests/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I presented a new talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2015&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago 2015&lt;/a&gt;
about how to change a team&amp;rsquo;s attitude towards writing automated tests.  The
talk covers the same case study as
&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/groovy_vs_java&#34;&gt;Groovy vs Java for Testing&lt;/a&gt;, adopting
Spock in MongoDB, but this is a more process/agile/people perspective, not a
technical look at the merits of one language over another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides available below.  As always, the slides are not super-useful out of
context, but they do contain my conclusions (also note that due to a technology
fail, my hand-drawn style is even more hand-drawn than usual).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/dJvHtktHbiDABW&#34; width=&#34;476&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions:369c5d835fdcc409d637a5ecd272b568&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sadly did not have a lot of time for questions during the presentation, but
thanks to the wonders of modern technology, I have a list of unanswered
questions which I will attempt to address here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is testing to find out your system works? Or is it so you know when your
system is broken?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Excellent question. I would expect that if you have a system that&amp;rsquo;s in
production (which is probably the large majority of the projects we work on),
we can assume the system is working, for some definition of working.
Automated testing is particularly good at catching when your system stops
doing the things you thought it was doing when you wrote the tests (which
may, or may not, mean the system is genuinely &amp;ldquo;broken&amp;rdquo;). Regression testing is
to find out when your system is no longer doing what you expect, and automated tests are
really good for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But testing can also make sure you implement code that behaves the way you
expect, especially if you write the tests first.  Automated tests can be used
to determine that your code is complete, according to some pre-agreed
specification (in this case, the automated tests you wrote up front).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say is, when you first write the tests you
have tests that, when they pass, proves the system works (&lt;em&gt;assuming&lt;/em&gt; your
tests are testing the right things and/or not giving you false positives).
Subsequent passes show that you haven&amp;rsquo;t broken anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what level do &amp;ldquo;tests documenting code&amp;rdquo; actually become useful? And who
is/should the documentation be targeted to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the presentation, my case study is the MongoDB Java Driver.  Our users
were Java programmers, who were going to be coding using our driver.  So in
this example, it makes a lot of sense to document the code using a language
that our users understood.  We started with Java, and ended up using Groovy
because it was also understandable for our users and a bit more succinct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a previous project we had different types of tests.  The unit and system
tests documented what the expected behaviour was at the class or module
level, and was aimed at developers in the team.  The acceptance tests were
written in Java, but in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.symphonious.net/2015/06/05/testinglmax-abstraction-by-dsl/&#34;&gt;friendly DSL-style way&lt;/a&gt;. These were usually
written by a triad of tester, business analyst and developer, and documented to all
these guys and girls what the top-level behaviour should be. Our audience here
was fairly technical though, so there was no need to go to the extent of trying
to write English-language-style tests, they were readable enough for a
reasonably techy (but non-programmer) audience. These were not designed to be
read by &amp;ldquo;the business&amp;rdquo; - us developers might use
them to answer questions about the behaviour of the system, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t
document it in a way that just anyone could understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two different approaches for two different-sized
team/organisations, with different users. So I guess in summary the answer is
&amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo;.  But at the very least, developers on your own team should be
able to read your tests and understand what the expected behaviour of the
code is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you become a team champion? I.e. get authority and acceptance that
people listen to you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In my case, it was just by accident - I happened to care about the tests
being green and also being useful, so I moaned at people until it happened. But
it&amp;rsquo;s not just about nagging, you get more buy-in if other people see you
doing the right things the right way, and it&amp;rsquo;s not too painful for them to
follow your example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are going to be things that you care about that you&amp;rsquo;ll never get other
people to care about, and this will be different from team to team. You have
two choices here - if you care that much, and it bothers you that much, you
have to do it yourself (often on your own time, especially if your boss
doesn&amp;rsquo;t buy into it). Or, you have to let it go - when it comes to quality,
there are so many things you could care about that it might be more
beneficial to drop one cause and pick another that you can get people to care
about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I wanted us to use &lt;code&gt;assertThat&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;assertFalse&lt;/code&gt; (or
true, or equals, or whatever).  I tried to demo the advantages (as I saw
them) of my approach to the team, and tried to push this in code reviews, but
in the end the other developers weren&amp;rsquo;t sold on the benefits, and
from my point of view the benefits weren&amp;rsquo;t big enough to force the issue.
Those of us who cared, used &lt;code&gt;assertThat&lt;/code&gt;. For the rest, I was just happy
people were writing and maintaining tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, pick your battles. You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised at how many people do get on board
with things.  I thought implementing checkstyle and setting draconian
formatting standards was going to be a tough battle, but in the end people
were just happy to have &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; standards, especially when they were enforced
by the build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you report test, style, coverage, etc failures separately? Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We didn&amp;rsquo;t fail on coverage.  Enforcing a coverage percentage is a really good
way to end up with crappy tests, like for getters/setters and constructors
(by the way, if there&amp;rsquo;s enough logic in your constructor that it &lt;em&gt;needs&lt;/em&gt; a
test, You&amp;rsquo;re Doing It Wrong).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally different types of failures are found by different tools, so for
this reason alone they will be reported separately - for example, checkstyle
will fail the build if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t conform to our style standards, codenarc
fails it for Groovy style failures, and Gradle will run the tests in a
different task to these two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s actually important, though, is time-to-failure.  For checkstyle, for
example, it will fail on something silly like curly braces in the wrong place.
You want this to fail within seconds, so you can fix the silly mistake
quickly. Ideally you&amp;rsquo;d have IntelliJ (perhaps) run your checks before it even
makes it into your CI environment. Compiler errors should, of course, fail
things before you run a test, short-running tests should fail before
long-running tests.  Basically, the easier it is to fix the problem, the
sooner you want to know, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our build was relatively small and not too complex, so actually we ran all
our types of tests (integration and unit, both Groovy and Java) in a single
task, because this turned out to be much quicker in Gradle (in our case) than
splitting things up into a simple pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have a reason to report stuff separately, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s much more
important to understand how fast I need to be aware of a particular type of
failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes I find myself modifying code design and architecture to enable
testing. How can I avoid damaging design?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is a great question, and a common one too. The short answer is: &lt;em&gt;in
general&lt;/em&gt; writing code that&amp;rsquo;s easier to test leads to a cleaner design anyway
(for example, dependency injection at that appropriate places). If you find
you need to rip your design apart to test it, there&amp;rsquo;s a smell there somewhere
 - either your design isn&amp;rsquo;t following SOLID principals, or you&amp;rsquo;re trying to
test the wrong things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the common example here is testing private methods - how do you test
these without exposing secrets&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;? I think for me, if it&amp;rsquo;s important
enough
 to be tested
it&amp;rsquo;s important enough to be exposed in some way - it might belong in some
sort of util or helper (right now I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into whether utils or
helpers are, in themselves a smell), in a smaller class that only
provides this sort of functionality, or simply a protected method. Or, if
you&amp;rsquo;re testing with Groovy, you can access private methods anyway so this
becomes a moot point (i.e. your testing framework may be limiting you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another story from LMAX, we found we had created methods just for testing. It seemed a
bit wrong to have these methods only available for testing, but later on down
the line, we needed access to many of these methods In Real Life (well, from
our Admin app), so our testing had &amp;ldquo;found&amp;rdquo; a missing feature. When we came
to implement it, it was pretty easy as we&amp;rsquo;d already done most of it for
testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My co-workers often point to a lack of end-to-end testing as the reason why
 a lot of bugs get out to production even though they don&amp;rsquo;t have much unit
 tests nor integration tests. What, in your experience, is a good balance
 between unit tests, integration tests and end-to-end testing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hmm, sounds to me like &amp;ldquo;lack of tests&amp;rdquo; is your problem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big (and contentious!) topic.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TestPyramid.html&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler has written about it&lt;/a&gt;, Google wrote something I
completely disagree with (so I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to link to it,
but you&amp;rsquo;ll find references in the links in this paragraph), and my
ex-colleague Adrian &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.symphonious.net/2015/04/30/making-end-to-end-tests-work/&#34;&gt;talks about what we, at LMAX, meant by end-to-end tests&lt;/a&gt;. I
hope that&amp;rsquo;s enough to get you started, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty more out there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you go about getting buy in from the team to use Spock?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I cover this in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/groovy_vs_java&#34;&gt;my other presentation on the topic&lt;/a&gt; - the
short version is, I did a week-long spike to investigate whether Spock would
make testing easier for us, showed the pros and cons to the whole team, and
then led by example writing tests that (I thought) were more readable than
what we had before and, probably most importantly, much easier to write than
what we were previously doing. I basically got buy-in by showing how much
easier it was for us to use the tool than even JUnit (which we were all
familiar with). It did help that we were already using Gradle, so we already
had a development dependency on Groovy. It also helped that adding Spock made
no changes to the dependencies of the final Jar, which was very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, further buy-in (certainly from management) came when the new tests
started catching more errors - usually regressions in our code or regressions in
the server&amp;rsquo;s overnight builds. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it was Spock specifically
that caught more problems - I think it was writing more tests, and
better tests, that caught the issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can we do data driven style tests in frameworks like junit or cucumber?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t think you can in JUnit (although maybe there&amp;rsquo;s something out there). I
believe someone told me you can do it in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://testng.org/doc/index.html&#34;&gt;TestNG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there drawbacks to having tests that only run in ci? I.e I have Java 8
on my machine, but the test requires Java 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, definitely - the drawback is Time.  You have to commit your code to a
branch that is being checked by CI and wait for CI to finish before you find
the error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, we found very little that was different between Java
7 and 8, for example, but this is a valid concern (otherwise you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be
testing a complex matrix of dependencies at all).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our case, our Java 6 driver used Netty for async capabilities, as the
stuff we were using from Java 7 wasn&amp;rsquo;t available. This was clearly a
different code path that wasn&amp;rsquo;t tested by us locally as we were all running
Java 8. Probably more importantly for us is we were testing against at least
3 different major versions of the server, which all supported different
features (and had different APIs).  I would often find I&amp;rsquo;d broken the tests
for version 2.2 as I&amp;rsquo;d only been running it on 2.6, and had forgotten to
either turn off the new tests for the old server versions, or didn&amp;rsquo;t realise
the new functionality wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the main drawback is time - it takes a lot longer to find out about these
errors.  There are a few ways to get around this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit often!! And to a branch that&amp;rsquo;s actually going to be run by CI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your build as fast as possible, so you get failures fast (you
should be doing this anyway)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could set up virtual machines locally or somewhere cloudy to run these
configurations before committing, but that sounds kinda painful (and to my
mind defeats a lot of the point of CI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I set up Travis on my fork of the project, so I could have that running a
different version of Java and MongoDB when I committed to my own fork - I&amp;rsquo;d
be able to see some errors before they made it into the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can, you probably want these specific tests run first so they can
fail fast. E.g. if you&amp;rsquo;re running a Java 6 &amp;amp; MongoDB 2.2 configuration on
CI, run those tests that only work in that environment first.  Would
probably need some Gradle magic, and/or might need you to separate these
into a different set of folders.  The advantage of this approach though is
if you set up some aliases on your local machine you could sanity check
&lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; these special cases before checking in. For example, I had aliases to
start MongoDB versions/configurations from a single command, and to set
JAVA_HOME to whichever version I wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any tips for unit tests that pass on dev machines but not on
Jenkins because it&amp;rsquo;s not as powerful as our own machines? E.g. Synchronous
calls timeout on the Jenkins builds intermittently.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Erk! Yes, not uncommon. No, not really. We had our timeouts set longer than I
would have liked to prevent these sorts of errors, and they still
intermittently failed. You can also set some sort of retry on the test, and
get your build system to re-run those that fail to see if they pass later.
It&amp;rsquo;s kinda nasty though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At LMAX they were able to take testing seriously enough to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.symphonious.net/2015/06/24/end-to-end-tests-lmax-update/&#34;&gt;really invest in
their testing
architecture&lt;/a&gt;, and, of course, this is The Correct Answer. Just
often very difficult to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you ask where are tests and dev asks if code is correct? And you say yes.
Then dev asks why you&amp;rsquo;re delaying shipping value, how do you manage that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
These are my opinions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your code is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; complete without tests that show me it&amp;rsquo;s complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your code might do what you think it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to do right now, but given
Shared Code Ownership, anyone can come in and change it at any time, you
want tests in place to make sure they don&amp;rsquo;t change it to break what you
thought it did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tests are not so much to show it works right now, the tests are to
show it continues to work in future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having automated tests &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; speed you up in future. You can refactor
more safely, you can fix bugs and know almost immediately if you broke
something, you can read from the test what the author of the code thought
the code should do, getting you up to speed faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know you&amp;rsquo;re shipping value without tests - you&amp;rsquo;re only shipping
code (to be honest, you never know if you&amp;rsquo;re shipping value until much later
on when you also analyse if people are even using the feature).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing almost never slows you down in the long run. Show me the bits of your
code base which are poorly tested, and I bet I can show you the bits of your
code base that frequently have bugs (either because the code is not really
doing what the author thinks, or because subsequent changes break things in
subtle ways).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you say code is hard to understand and dev asks if you seriously don&amp;rsquo;t
understand the code, how do you explain you mean easy to understand without
thinking rather than &amp;lsquo;can I compile this in my head&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have zero problem with saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m too stupid to understand this code, and
I expect you&amp;rsquo;re much smarter than me for writing it. Can you please write it
in a way so that a less smart person like myself won&amp;rsquo;t trample all over your
beautiful code at a later date through lack of understanding?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By definition, code should be easy to understand by someone who&amp;rsquo;s not the
author. If someone who is not the author says the code is hard to understand,
then the code is hard to understand. This is not negotiable. This is what
code reviews or pair programming should address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is effective nagging like? (Whether or not you get what you want)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mmm, good question. Off the top of my head:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make the people who are the target of the nagging feel stupid -
they&amp;rsquo;ll get defensive. If necessary, take the burden of &amp;ldquo;stupidity&amp;rdquo; on
yourself. E.g. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just not smart enough to be able to tell if this test is
failing because the test is bad or because the code is bad. Can you walk me
through it and help me fix it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; your fair share of the work, if not more. When I wanted to
get the code to a state where we could fail style errors, I fixed 99% of the
problems, and delegated the handful of remaining ones that I just didn&amp;rsquo;t
have the context to fix. In the face of three errors to fix each, the team
could hardly say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; after I&amp;rsquo;d fixed over 6000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things need to be done. Developers are adults and don&amp;rsquo;t want
to be treated like children. Give them a good reason and they&amp;rsquo;ll follow the
rules. The few times I didn&amp;rsquo;t have good reasons, I could not get the team
to do what I wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find carrots and sticks that work.  At LMAX, a short e-mail at the start
of the day summarising the errors that had happened overnight, who seemed to
be responsible, and whether they looked like real errors or
intermittencies, was enough to get people to fix their problems&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; -
they didn&amp;rsquo;t like to look bad, but they also had enough information to get right
on it, they didn&amp;rsquo;t have to wade through all the build info.  On occasion,
when people were ignoring this, I&amp;rsquo;d turn up to work with bags of chocolate
that I&amp;rsquo;d bought with my own money, offering chocolate bars to anyone who
fixed up the tests. I was random with my carrot offerings so people didn&amp;rsquo;t
game the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give up if it&amp;rsquo;s not working. If you&amp;rsquo;ve tried to phrase the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; in a
number of ways, if you&amp;rsquo;ve tried to show examples of the benefits, if you&amp;rsquo;ve
tried to work the results you want into a process, but it&amp;rsquo;s still not
getting done, just accept the fact that this isn&amp;rsquo;t working for the team.
Move on to something else, or find a new angle.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I had a colleague at LMAX who was  working with a hypothesis that
All Private Methods Were Evil - they were clearly only sharable within
single class, so provided no reuse elsewhere, and if you have the same bit
of code being called multiple times from within the same class (but it&amp;rsquo;s
not valuable elsewhere) then maybe your design is wrong. I&amp;rsquo;m still
pondering this specific hypothesis 4 years on, and I admit I see its pros
and cons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; This worked so well that this process was automated by
one of the guys and turned into a tool called AutoTrish, which as far as I
know is still used at LMAX.  Dave Farley talks about it in some of his
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parleys.com/tutorial/continuous-delivery-part-2-2&#34;&gt;Continuous Delivery talks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources:369c5d835fdcc409d637a5ecd272b568&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My talk that specifically looks at the
&lt;a href=&#34;presentation/groovy_vs_java/&#34;&gt;advantages of Spock over JUnit&lt;/a&gt;, plus some
Spock-specific resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; Jay Fields book
&lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/wewut&#34;&gt;Working Effectively With Unit Tests&lt;/a&gt; - if I
could have made the whole team read this before moving to Spock, we might
have stuck with JUnit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go read everything Adrian Sutton has written about testing at LMAX. If not
everything, definitely &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.symphonious.net/2015/06/05/testinglmax-abstraction-by-dsl/&#34;&gt;Abstraction by
DSL&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.symphonious.net/2015/04/30/making-end-to-end-tests-work/&#34;&gt;Making End-to-End Tests Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t make it all the way through Dave Farley and Jez Humble&amp;rsquo;s
excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon
.com/gp/product/0321601912/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789
&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0321601912&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId
=I7ZAO2TETBFJIPHL&#34;&gt;Continuous Delivery book&lt;/a&gt;, do take a look at one of
Dave&amp;rsquo;s presentations on the subject, for example &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/cd-success&#34;&gt;The Rationale for Continuous
Delivery&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/technology-practice-continuous-delivery&#34;&gt;The Process,
Technology and Practice of Continuous
Delivery&lt;/a&gt; - my own talk was
around testing, but I&amp;rsquo;m working off the assumption that you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt;
running some sort of Continuous Integration, if not Continuous Delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Fowler has loads of &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/tags/testing.html&#34;&gt;interesting and useful articles on
testing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract:369c5d835fdcc409d637a5ecd272b568&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What can you do to help developers a) write tests b) write meaningful tests
and c) write readable tests?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trisha will talk about her experiences of working in a team that wanted to
build quality into their new software version without a painful overhead -
without a QA / Testing team, without putting in place any formal processes,
without slavishly improving the coverage percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team had been writing automated tests and running them in a continuous
integration environment, but they were simply writing tests as another tick
box to check, there to verify the developer had done what the developer had
aimed to do. The team needed to move to a model where tests provided more
than this. The tests needed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate that the library code was meeting the requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document in a readable fashion what those requirements were, and what should happen under non-happy-path situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide enough coverage so a developer could confidently refactor the code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover how the team selected a new testing framework (Spock, a
framework written in Groovy that can be used to test JVM code) to aid with
this effort, and how they evaluated whether this tool would meet the team’s
needs. And now, two years after starting to use Spock, Trisha can talk
about how both the tool and the shift in the focus of the purpose of tests
has affected the quality of the code. And, interestingly, the happiness
of the developers.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java at 20</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_at_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_at_20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was asked three simple questions about my thoughts on Java turning 20, and ended up writing a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.voxxed.com/blog/2015/05/the-java-birthday-diaries-part-3-trisha-gee-on-ides-jigsaw-and/&#34;&gt;guest post for Voxxed&lt;/a&gt;.
 No wonder I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find the time to write these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Xtended</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6771.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34; alt=&#34;The 
calm before the storm&#34; title=&#34;The calm before the storm&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the more I go to conferences, the less I write about them.  I could claim lack of time, but
the fact is that all my write-ups will be something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Loved &amp;lt;city&amp;gt;, went to talks that made me
think, met interesting people, gave a talk or two that seemed to go well&amp;rdquo;. Not sure if people get bored of reading
that, but I get bored of writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6803.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Conferences are fun&#34; title=&#34;Conferences are fun&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I&amp;rsquo;m bored of conferences. On the contrary - since I work from home, travelling to new places and
meeting Real Human Beings keeps me sane. Plus conferences are fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6753.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; alt=&#34;The 
setup&#34; title=&#34;The setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I went to a conference on Saturday that makes me feel compelled to write something, and not just because it was
organised by my two fellow &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Sevilla JUG&lt;/a&gt; organisers.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/israkaos&#34;&gt;@IsraKaos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rgdav&#34;&gt;@RGDav&lt;/a&gt; are both doing more Android day-to-day than
server-side Java, so this is an area they&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about. Not content with organising
Android events every other month, they decided they had so many interesting speakers they wanted to have speaking here
in Sevilla that they wanted to run a whole day, single track conference, on behalf of &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/communities/114997118727600981533&#34;&gt;GDG Sevilla&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidxtended.com/&#34;&gt;Android Xtended&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6848.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Android Xtended&#34; title=&#34;Android Xtended&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;As a Java &amp;ldquo;Technical Advocate&amp;rdquo;, I suppose I should keep an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the Android space, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a
huge part of the ecosystem&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/androidxtended#footnote1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to go in any sort
of official capacity (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t speaking, manning a booth, organising or sponsoring), so I could just enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/registration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hola...&#34; title=&#34;Hola...&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, they roped me into doing registrations. Me! I was concerned my Spanish wasn&amp;rsquo;t up for it, but apparently I only
needed two words: &amp;ldquo;nombre&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;talla&amp;rdquo; (for the t-shirt). Oh, and &amp;ldquo;treinta y uno b&amp;rdquo; - there was such demand for the
conference the initial venue wasn&amp;rsquo;t big enough, so it was being hosted at two sites on the same road. Not
surprisingly, some turned up to the wrong one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6813.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@inmaculadaalcon&#34; title=&#34;@inmaculadaalcon&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike a large number of our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/&#34;&gt;MUG&lt;/a&gt; events, all the talks were in Spanish. So feel
free to ignore my analysis if you like - my Spanish comprehension is pretty good, but sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t realise when
I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand something and just make up my own story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;float:left; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6794.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
alt=&#34;@flipper83&#34; title=&#34;@flipper83&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far in the Android space is Getting Started type material - a lot of tutorials and
examples that show you how to achieve a particular goal. There seems to be less of an emphasis on areas that
interest me as an experienced Java person - easy automation of testing, good design practices, craftsmanship etc. Now,
 it may be that because those areas (apart from testing) apply to both back-end Java and Android, there&amp;rsquo;s less of a
 need to re-iterate it in the Android space. Or it may be that I don&amp;rsquo;t see the entry-level Java stuff any more,
 because I don&amp;rsquo;t need it, and I seek out the topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6892.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
 alt=&#34;@JMPergar&#34; title=&#34;@JMPergar&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or it may be that as Android is one of those
 platforms that&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start as a fairly novice developer (because you can write self-contained code with
 a visible UI and get results fairly easily), lots of the focus is on the needs of new developers.  Whatever the
 reason, I had been starting to feel like the Android ecosystem was missing people taking developers beyond that
 initial step of getting something to work and up to the level of creating maintainable code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6880.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@pedro_g_s&#34; title=&#34;@pedro_g_s&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Xtended put my mind at rest. Here was a range of talks that led attendees through the things that will make
them more effective developers - tools and libraries to use; testing approaches; integration with persistence; clean
(code) design for the UI; design patterns and domain driven design to simplify your code, and so on. As an employee
of JetBrains, I was obviously very happy to see both
&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/tools/studio/index.html&#34;&gt;Android Studio&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; mentioned and used throughout as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6863.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@davilagrau&#34; title=&#34;@davilagrau&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as fantastic speakers (they knew their stuff, were clearly practitioners, and all had great individual
presentation styles), there were three mob-programming sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6853.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mob Programming&#34; title=&#34;Mob Programming&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an ambitious attempt to not just preach to
a passive audience, but to involve them in creating real, working code to teach fundamental practices - dependency
injection, testing and Gradle.  An hour is barely enough time to give a practiced demo of real code, to create
something collaboratively with an audience of 30 people was a challenge. But I thought it did give people a flavour
of not just how to use the technologies, but what they were for. I also saw a lot of the audience starting to
realise the power of refactoring using an IDE - I firmly believe the best way to teach the power of a tool is by
pair programming or, at least, using the tool in real use cases in front of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6921.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More collaboration&#34; title=&#34;More collaboration&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mob programming was kinda
like a half day tutorial squished into an hour. I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to hear how the attendees found it. For me, since
this was a full day conference that cost 10, I thought getting three short tutorials as well as five excellent
talks was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good value for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6896.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Happy developers&#34; title=&#34;Happy developers&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6883.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
alt=&#34;Interesting...&#34; title=&#34;Interesting...&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be remiss in talking about the conference if I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention the venue.  We were at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://espaciores.org/&#34;&gt;Espacio RES&lt;/a&gt;, which was pretty easy to get to, and a really nice, airy, comfortable
space&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/androidxtended#footnote2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
And they let us rearrange their whole place just for us. The only downside is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hold more people, which
is a shame, and the reason we had to host on two sites (I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on the other site as I stayed
at RES the whole day, but we&amp;rsquo;re very grateful to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitnami.com/&#34;&gt;Bitnami&lt;/a&gt; for lending us their offices as well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6831.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Collaboration&#34; title=&#34;Collaboration&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did I learn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://espaciores.org/&#34;&gt;Espacio RES&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice space that hopefully we can use more regularly for events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is possible to use Good Practices to write Android code, and Real Developers are doing so for Real Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are very talented and expert technical speakers in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to two conferences in Spain in
the last month, but as they were all in English I think it puts some people off presenting. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see Spanish
talent being showcased, it gives developers here good role models and shows that experts aren&amp;rsquo;t just from outside
Spain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sevilla has a very healthy tech scene with people more than happy to give up a Saturday to learn new things. In
fact, for some set of people, they prefer Saturdays to weekday
evenings&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/androidxtended#footnote3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I have a feeling I&amp;rsquo;m about to lose more weekends in the
future&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;People like Saturdays?&#34; title=&#34;People like 
 Saturdays?&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Xtended was a fantastic event, with great speakers and engaged attendees.  I loved how social
 everyone was during the breaks, how people were happy to chat and share stories, even though most of the attendees
 didn&amp;rsquo;t know each other beforehand. It was brilliantly organised, and although I did see how much work went into
 arranging it, you would never believe from how smoothly it went that this two-venue event was organised by just two
 guys. Well done &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/israkaos&#34;&gt;@IsraKaos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rgdav&#34;&gt;@RGDav&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6927.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Drinks&#34; title=&#34;Drinks&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Although in my experience Android and &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; Java user groups and events tend not to
 overlap much - not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a function of the relationship between Google and Oracle or just because large cities like
 London tend to split groups along technology lines to keep group and event sizes manageable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The downside was there are not a lot of places nearby open for coffee at 8am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; This is completely alien to me as someone who built her career largely in London - you
 do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; host events on a Saturday, except for maybe the annual LJC Open Conference, because many people have a
 long commute into the city. Doing that 5 days a week is plenty, most people don&amp;rsquo;t want to do it on a Saturday as
 well. But they will give up a couple of hours in the evening, as it costs far less in time overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groovy vs Java</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/groovy_vs_java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/groovy_vs_java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Resources for my &amp;ldquo;Is Groovy Better Than Java for Testing?&amp;rdquo; talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VK2sMI5B1pY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/46936375&#34; width=&#34;476&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/spock_is_awesome_seriously_simplified_mocking/&#34;&gt;Mocking in Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/spock_passes_the_next_test__painless_stubbing/&#34;&gt;Stubbing in Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/spock_data_driven_testing/&#34;&gt;Data Driven Testing in Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://spockframework.github.io/spock/docs/1.0/index.html&#34;&gt;Spock Reference Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/wewut&#34;&gt;Working Effectively With Unit Tests - Jay Fields&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Video: &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/80222114&#34;&gt;Making Java Tests Groovy with Spock - Ken Sipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt; All examples from the talk come from the MongoDB Java driver. Some tests have been improved or dropped over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind CFPs - a Postscript</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/blind_cfps_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/blind_cfps_2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since publishing &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/blind_cfps&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of great comments, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write yet
another post to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let me state that I don&amp;rsquo;t think blind CFPs are a complete waste of time - for example, I know that there are
circles in which speakers will refuse to submit if the selection process isn&amp;rsquo;t blind. But what blind CFPs are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;,
is an answer to &amp;ldquo;How do I get more women speakers at my conference?&amp;rdquo;, especially if the problem is not that the
women are being rejected, but that they simply aren&amp;rsquo;t submitting talks - this is the situation I see most frequently
in the conferences I speak at/help organise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;you-re-missing-the-point-of-blind-cfps:43f099050d27fb0647d57b33c7259595&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re missing the point of blind CFPs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to address the point &amp;ldquo;Blind CFPs are to protect the organisers, not simply to improve diversity&amp;rdquo;. OK, great. So
in the case of the conferences that had only two women out of 200 submissions: if you make that process blind, whether you
select both women or not, when there are nasty comments about your lack of women speakers, you&amp;rsquo;re protected - you did
the right things, you had a blind CFP, and just not many women made it through that process. Women simply aren&amp;rsquo;t
writing compelling abstracts and/or aren&amp;rsquo;t picking interesting subjects and/or clearly aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in
presenting at conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AAAARRRGGHHHHHH!!!! Anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protect your arse if you like, that&amp;rsquo;s fine, I see the attacks against organisers and I understand the need to be able to
say you did the right thing. But notice that once you&amp;rsquo;ve protected yourselves, the blame is back on the
minorities for not meeting your criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the purpose of a blind CFP is to protect the selectors, then let&amp;rsquo;s not pretend it&amp;rsquo;s an answer to increasing diversity
of speakers, it&amp;rsquo;s a piece in a larger puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;an-abstract-is-not-a-representation-of-your-talk:43f099050d27fb0647d57b33c7259595&#34;&gt;An abstract is not a representation of your talk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can emphasise this enough: blind CFPs have a very big weakness - there is no direct correlation between
a good abstract and a good talk. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching a bunch of talks online lately, and I watched one with an abstract
that absolutely called to me - here was the missing piece for a technology that I simply can&amp;rsquo;t get my head around. I
gave an hour of my life to that talk, each minute I was wondering when this person would get to the bits mentioned
in the abstract, so I watched it all the way to the end. They never delivered what the abstract promised, and their
meandering style meant I learnt almost nothing from the talk. That&amp;rsquo;s an hour of my life I&amp;rsquo;ll never get back. Good
thing I was playing computer games as well at the time, if I&amp;rsquo;d paid money for that I would have been very peeved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another weakness in this process - if you go to a number of conferences (like I do) you kinda learn which
speakers are doing
which talks.  If I submit my &amp;ldquo;AngularJS, HTML5, Groovy, Java and MongoDB all together - what could possibly go wrong??&amp;rdquo;
talk to a blind process, if there&amp;rsquo;s anyone on the selection committee who&amp;rsquo;s even vaguely involved in the Java or MongoDB
spaces, they&amp;rsquo;ll know that&amp;rsquo;s me. And they can Google the talk and decide whether they like it (or with any luck, the
buzz-word crammed title will do the job and they&amp;rsquo;ll say yes, although probably AngularJS is so 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An abstract is like your presentation in the same way that your CV is like your ability to do your job - there&amp;rsquo;s a skill
to writing good abstracts (or CVs), but mastery of that skill does not necessarily mean mastery of the thing it
represents - the ability to present or the ability to do the job.  I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be sold on a blind process
being a good way to build &amp;ldquo;the best content available for the conference&amp;rdquo; until this disconnect is somehow solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;for-goodness-sake-trisha-the-postscript-is-nearly-longer-than-the-original-post:43f099050d27fb0647d57b33c7259595&#34;&gt;For goodness sake Trisha, the postscript is nearly longer than the original post&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to feedback from a bunch of people, and I have learnt more things (thanks everyone!). I am more sold on
a blind CFP being maybe part of a bigger process. But I do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe it fixes the &amp;ldquo;we need more women speakers&amp;rdquo;
problem, which was the original claim that I wanted to dispute. Conferences have to be &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more active to address
this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I am not sold on an abstract being a fair representation of the quality of a talk. Maybe a more realistic &amp;ldquo;blind&amp;rdquo;
audition would be to give the talk to an audience, like a user group, who rated the talk:
the organisers wouldn&amp;rsquo;t watch the talk, but they could use the ratings to decide. Yes, the user group could also
have biases that affect their rating, but when the speaker gives the talk at the conference, those attendees will also
have their biases too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blindness is not a realistic option, we just have to keep putting women (and other non-white-straight-men) in front of
audiences until it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a novelty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Blind CFPs Really The Answer?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/blind_cfps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/blind_cfps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Off the back of &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/i_am_so_tired_of_it_all/&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt;, I received a number of comments and questions
around blind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/&#34;&gt;CFPs&lt;/a&gt; (Call For Papers - usually to get into a conference you submit to a CFP) for
conferences. I often hear it said that a blind CFP will fix, or at least improve, the diversity imbalance at conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I should caveat this with: this is going to be a blog post based on my experiences and chats with people, and I
have zero science to back this up. Sorry. But I do have some numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of London conferences that I won&amp;rsquo;t name (because I haven&amp;rsquo;t asked their permission not because they&amp;rsquo;ve
done anything wrong) that in some years have received only 2 from around 200 (or more) submissions from women. These
conferences have accepted 100% of the submissions from women, and then been open to criticism for not having enough women
speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blind CFP to remove unconscious bias from the selection committee might have resulted in zero women speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know the next argument is that advertising a blind CFP might encourage a wider diversity of speakers to apply. This
does seem to work in some parts of the industry (I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking to women from tech scenes that don&amp;rsquo;t intersect with mine
and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to see that we have different problems in different segments of the wider development world). But for my
world, which is largely Java, with some forays into Agile, NoSQL, Open Source, and Enterprise, the women I speak to
aren&amp;rsquo;t scared they&amp;rsquo;ll be discriminated against if they put their name on a CFP. Besides, they don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to
lose by submitting and being rejected. They&amp;rsquo;re more afraid they&amp;rsquo;ll be accepted, and then they&amp;rsquo;ll have to give a
presentation! No, the women I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken to in my world don&amp;rsquo;t submit because they don&amp;rsquo;t feel ready, they don&amp;rsquo;t think they
have anything to talk about, and they&amp;rsquo;re worried about the sorts of questions they&amp;rsquo;ll get asked when they&amp;rsquo;re standing up
there. Those fears aren&amp;rsquo;t allayed by having a blind CFP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are any fears of being judged as a woman, it&amp;rsquo;s when we&amp;rsquo;re standing up in front of people at the conference, and
no amount of blindness during the CFP process is going to make us feel better about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, personally, I find the idea of a blind CFP terrifying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firstly, if you have such a problem with judging people based on race or gender that you have to anonymise the
selection process, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want to speak at your conference where my gender will be blatantly on show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secondly, when I was starting out as a speaker, I was new to writing titles and abstracts and expected that they would
not be good enough to get in. With a blind CFP I would never find out why as I could never ask for feedback on my
anonymous abstract. As a novice speaker, I expected my gender would help me be selected, not hinder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thirdly, as an experienced speaker I know my abstract-writing has not really improved, but I know my presenting has,
and I know there are videos of me out there doing a good job as a presenter, &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is my audition tape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was starting out as a speaker, I knew there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough women presenters around. And although I hate the idea
of positive discrimination and hate the idea that men might think I got into my position merely because I&amp;rsquo;m female, I knew
that being a woman made me stand out in all those submissions. And I knew that enough conferences would take a chance on
me, if only to improve their diversity, and that&amp;rsquo;s all I needed to bootstrap my speaking career - once I had spoken at
enough conferences, once I had videos of me doing that, I would find it much easier to get into the next conferences.
And that&amp;rsquo;s worked. And now, as an experienced (female) speaker, I fear blind CFPs as they won&amp;rsquo;t know who I am or what I&amp;rsquo;m
capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s my opinion as a female speaker. But I&amp;rsquo;ve also been fortunate enough to be on the programme committee for a couple
of conferences, and after three years or so of speaking at conferences I know a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of conference organisers.  Let&amp;rsquo;s
assume you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;merely&amp;rdquo; trying to build the best conference you can around your subject whilst not discriminating against
anyone (i.e. let&amp;rsquo;s assume you&amp;rsquo;re not going out of your way to actively promote diversity). How can you do this when you only
have abstracts and titles to go on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am aware of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nber.org/papers/w5903&#34;&gt;studies around blind auditions for orchestras&lt;/a&gt;. And I understand
how tempting it is to try to apply that to our world, since it has had an effect on the number of women in orchestras
(but let&amp;rsquo;s not get too excited here, we&amp;rsquo;re talking about an increase from 5% to 25% over thirty years&amp;hellip;). I think
blind auditions would work really well for coding - we can look at just the code, without knowing anything about the
physical body behind the code, and figure out if that person is good enough for us. We could even do blind pair
programming, using screen sharing and chat (actually that&amp;rsquo;s a great idea, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll patent that!). Because
the thing you&amp;rsquo;ve anonymised (the code) is the output you really care about in a programming job. If you communicate via
chat you can even measure someone&amp;rsquo;s communication skills without judging them physically, another vital skill for
being part of a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a talk abstract is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the output we&amp;rsquo;re looking for.  Sure, a good title and abstract will attract attendees to the
conference and bums on seats in the actual talk. But the output you&amp;rsquo;re looking for is the presenter - their style, their
approach to the topic, their ability to hold attention, their ability to impart information. We&amp;rsquo;re not always looking
for the same things either, an interesting topic presented nervously but logically is fine, as is an entertaining
presenter reminding us of fundamentals we already know (and any other combination of strengths and weaknesses). An abstract
can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how good the presentation is going to be. Evaluating a presentation on a blind abstract would be like
evaluating those musicians on a couple of paragraphs explaining what they&amp;rsquo;re going to play and how they&amp;rsquo;re going to
try to make you feel when they play it - the words could sound great, but the musician might not even be able to play
the instrument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best audition you can have as a presenter is to, well, present. Videos, audio clips, even screencasts. But the
problem with presenting is that it&amp;rsquo;s so freaking obvious that you&amp;rsquo;re a woman (or other variation on
non-white-straight-male).  If you can&amp;rsquo;t objectively evaluate a presentation without taking away the presenter&amp;rsquo;s
physical body (for colour
or gender or whatever), then you&amp;rsquo;ve got real problems. Your audience is going to be faced with that physical body for an
hour of their life, and you can bet they&amp;rsquo;ll be judging them too.  You want to be damned sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve selected a
competent presenter, and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to stand by that choice. Saying &amp;ldquo;oh, well, they didn&amp;rsquo;t seem boring in their
abstract&amp;rdquo; is not going to make the audience feel like you did a good job of the selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another point about non-blind selection processes, other than the process allowing you to select on presentation
ability rather than abstract-writing ability: you can be more active in promoting diversity. I am against &amp;ldquo;affirmative
action&amp;rdquo;, but if the proportion of women submitting presentations is lower than the proportion of women in the field, there&amp;rsquo;s
something missing.  Here are some of the things you can do if you identify a lack of a certain demographic - as usual,
I&amp;rsquo;m going to use &amp;ldquo;women&amp;rdquo;, but you could equally argue this for any demographic, even not-enough-C#-developers or
too-many-startups-not-enough-enterprise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to relevant user groups and communities asking them to submit.  In London for example, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Ladies-Who-Code-UK/&#34;&gt;Ladies Who Code&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/women-who-code-london/&#34;&gt;Women Who Code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://london.girlgeekdinners.com/&#34;&gt;Girl Geek Dinners&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/PyLadiesLondon/&#34;&gt;PyLadies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Rails-Girls-London/&#34;&gt;Rails Girls&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Women-in-Data/&#34;&gt;Women in Data&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekgirlmeetup.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Girl Geek Meetup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/WIGJMeetup/&#34;&gt;Women in Games Jobs&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://girlsintechuk.com/community/&#34;&gt;Girls in Tech&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Geek-Girls-Unite-London/&#34;&gt;Girl Geeks Unite&lt;/a&gt;, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://witi.meetup.com/cities/gb/17/london/&#34;&gt;whole host of women techies meetups&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip; And don&amp;rsquo;t think I psychically
know about all those
because I have two X chromosomes, I found half of those just now, in less than two minutes, by Googling
&amp;ldquo;Girl Geeks London&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Women Tech London&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the faces of the women you do want to have speak (or the women on your programme committee, or both) on your
website - showing these women sends the message that this conference is for women. It should also impact the diversity
of your attendees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to specific women speakers and ask them to present. &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/more_female_speakers&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about this before&lt;/a&gt;,
women speakers are few and far between, and a) they get
booked in advance and b) are busy enough not to have to (or want to) submit via a CFP process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/more_female_speakers&#34;&gt;more ideas here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s more - you don&amp;rsquo;t just have to drain the pool dry of known competent speakers-who-tick-some-diversity-box. With
a non-blind process you can actively improve the submissions you do have, assuming you&amp;rsquo;re not one of the conferences
suffering from a complete lack of submissions from those people. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to increase the number of women
presenting at your conference, if you have women submitting but they don&amp;rsquo;t quite meet your criteria (maybe the abstract
is weak, the title isn&amp;rsquo;t catchy, or maybe the presenter simply isn&amp;rsquo;t quite ready yet) you, as the conference organiser, are
in the perfect position to mentor these people: you can help them re-write their abstracts; you can offer them mentoring
and training for presenting. If there&amp;rsquo;s no record of them presenting but you&amp;rsquo;re interested in evaluating their ability,
you can set them up with a user group to present at - as a conference organiser, you have the network contacts that
new speakers might not. You can run sessions aimed at people who have never done public speaking (I&amp;rsquo;ve run a session
like this four times now, at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; and at Ladies Who Code -
I had &lt;em&gt;over 70&lt;/em&gt; RSVPs for the last London Ladies Who Code session, twice the number of the last LJC session,
so there are plenty of women interested in breaking into this field, who are looking for training, who don&amp;rsquo;t feel ready
to present yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are my points?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A blind process of selection can be applied to something where the output you&amp;rsquo;re selecting for can be effectively
anonymised: music auditions, code, technical writing, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A blind process where you select based on criteria that are not the end result will only be effective
if it&amp;rsquo;s the selection process is biased, or if submissions to the selection process are lower
from discriminated-against-groups because they fear a biased selection process.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those conferences that are getting very tiny numbers of submissions from women (I&amp;rsquo;m picking women as the example
but you can pick any group you want), a blind process could lead to even fewer selected women speakers. Instead of
switching to a blind process, you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to want to check:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the messaging around your conference (remember masculine words like rock star, ninja, competitive, hardcore,
challenging etc &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tum.de/en/about-tum/news/press-releases/short/article/31438/&#34;&gt;put women off applying to jobs&lt;/a&gt;, the same probably applies to technical conferences)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subliminal messages on your website/info (one of the conferences I mentioned, for example, sent out a couple of emails
containing photos of previous years&amp;rsquo; conferences which happened to only show men - this was not even representative of
the conference, but it can have an unexpectedly big effect on the subconscious)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have you showcased the diversity of the conference, or previous years&amp;rsquo; conferences, with photos, interviews, testamonials?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A non-blind submission process allows you to be more active in promoting diversity - instead of hoping that the
submissions are representative of the diversity in your community, and that selecting the most interesting talks
will naturally lead to improved diversity, with a non-blind process you can track exactly how many women are submitting,
address problems in this area early and offer mentoring to those who aren&amp;rsquo;t quite ready yet. Remember that &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2014/08/why-women-dont-apply-for-jobs-unless-theyre-100-qualified/0-qualified/&#34;&gt;women
only apply for jobs they feel 100% qualified for&lt;/a&gt;
and take fewer chances, they might need that extra push.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, no. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that implementing a blind CFP will address the lack of diversity in conference speakers. I
know it helps in some circles, but I personally think that conference selection committees should a) be much better at
identifying their own biases and actively attempting to overcome them b) be active in improving the diversity of
their conference, and c) be offering feedback and mentoring to those who are not quite ready yet in order to improve
the overall ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diversity isn&amp;rsquo;t going to accidentally happen when we stop looking at gender and race and other visible you-don&amp;rsquo;t-belong-here
cues.  Diversity is only going to happen if people fight for it, and if we actively train, mentor, and support those
trying to break through the barriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;postscript:db2f562112b18dc104706e916c34cc92&#34;&gt;Postscript&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/blind_cfps_2&#34;&gt;follow up&lt;/a&gt; based off responses to this post, covering additional questions raised.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m so tired of it all</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/i_am_so_tired_of_it_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/i_am_so_tired_of_it_all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We work so hard to promote equality, to fight for the rights of people who are not middle-class
white men, and time and again it just feels like we&amp;rsquo;re not getting anywhere.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.internationalwomensday.com/&#34;&gt;International Women&amp;rsquo;s
Day&lt;/a&gt; highlights the issues that face women all around the world, and make our
women-in-tech problem
look like a genuine &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/firstworldproblems&#34;&gt;First World Problem&lt;/a&gt;, and yet we can&amp;rsquo;t even get that right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nearly gave up. This weekend I thought, fuck it. I&amp;rsquo;ve done my bit. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been through the phase in my
career where being a woman was a disadvantage and somehow arrived out the other side - in my position, in my job, it&amp;rsquo;s
an advantage, and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to change anything to improve things for my career. I&amp;rsquo;m going to carry on doing my job to the best
of my ability, but I&amp;rsquo;m no longer going to let this diversity thing drain my energy - nothing ever seems to make a difference anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, four (white, middle-class, English-speaking) men who I know well, who
I have seen by their actions are champions of women in technology, who have personally mentored
me in some way or another, have been accused of not thinking about women techies, not encouraging them - have
been accused of sexism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This third year of being on the programme committee for QCon, I could see we had achieved far more to promote diversity
than ever before, but it was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much work to get that far, and there&amp;rsquo;s still &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt; more to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another conference I have great affection for which has never previously suffered badly from a lack of women speakers
received practically
zero submissions for full conference talks from women this year. The submissions that did come in were from the usual
suspects, the speakers who one calls upon when desperately trying to shore up the gender diversity of your speaker line-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sevilla Java User Group, which I started, with my money, which I present at regularly, has had &lt;em&gt;zero&lt;/em&gt; female
developers attend who were not previously friends. Apparently the impact of visible female role models is far smaller than
I imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so much work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s thankless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the men who support the women, they get attacked by both sides - by women, for not
doing enough, or sometimes for simply being privileged white men, by men and women for fighting for something that
doesn&amp;rsquo;t impact them, and by men for betraying their gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the women, it&amp;rsquo;s the same but more so: some women accuse us of not doing enough, some women sneer at what we&amp;rsquo;re doing,
telling us we already have equality, men and women think you&amp;rsquo;re in it just to improve your own life, and the men, well,
many men genuinely don&amp;rsquo;t understand the problems (and it&amp;rsquo;s exhausting to explain), and some are outright hostile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to find men allies.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know about anyone else, but at this stage in my career I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by men
who are all allies. And I can honestly say that any professional struggles I&amp;rsquo;ve had in recent years I can see are suffered
by my colleagues of the opposite sex, so I know they&amp;rsquo;re not because of my gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s only fair that our male allies suffer the same way we do, even though they get even less out of fighting our battles
than we do. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s fair that they are attacked by both genders, and have to put up with unfair, unjust
criticism and accusations. After all, look at some of the vile, hate-filled messages thrown at women leading the charge -
that&amp;rsquo;s abuse. Some of these women fear for their lives.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live that life, and I despair that we live in a
society that can&amp;rsquo;t seem to prevent that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m a bit burnt out. So my friends are finding it tough. But this is a marathon, not a sprint.  And I never did this
for me anyway. I care about diversity because it matters. I try to change the gender balance specifically, because that&amp;rsquo;s an area I
might be able to impact, one I have a chance of understanding. I care about equality, about justice, because
it matters. And I do my tiny part to try and drown out the hate, the anger, the &amp;ldquo;get back into the kitchen, woman&amp;rdquo;
because those things make me feel sick, because &amp;ldquo;you can be whoever you want to be&amp;rdquo; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a lie, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come
with caveats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or energy for large-scale revolutions, but I will carry on trying to make a small difference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By trying to be a role model for anyone who can relate to me, whatever their colour, gender, or sexual orientation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By being visible as a woman techie, who does woman techie things, who&amp;rsquo;s also a human being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By calling out (quietly and personally, at least at first) where I see things that might give the wrong message: e.g.
e-mailing conference organisers to point out they only have white men in their line up; private messaging people to
let them know their comments could be taken the wrong way; pointing out to user group leaders that their meetup
page shows only men at their events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By continuing to give an honest view of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be a female Java developer, especially if these
experiences are different to those of other women - one woman&amp;rsquo;s view does not represent every woman&amp;rsquo;s view, if more
of us tell our different tales, we have a better view of the whole ecosystem (and its inhabitants).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By sharing not only the negatives, but the many positives of working in such a varied and rapidly changing profession.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am tired of fighting, however tiny my efforts are. But I&amp;rsquo;m more tired of inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 8 in Anger</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/java8_in_anger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/java8_in_anger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Content and resources for my new Java 8 in Anger presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page embeds the latest video of this talk (DevoxxUK), and the resources I used to create
the it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;videos:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Videos&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div data-parleys-presentation=&#34;java-8-anger-1&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;height:300px&#34;&gt;&lt;script type = &#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;//parleys.com/js/parleys-share.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parleys.com/play/java-8-anger-1&#34;&gt;Watch on Parleys.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parleys.com/play/java-8-anger&#34;&gt;Devoxx France Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/61448786&#34;&gt;Version recorded at CraftConf&lt;/a&gt; (not quite as easy to see the code)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/java8-tutorial&#34;&gt;First ever version! QCon London&lt;/a&gt; (code has been
simplified a little since then)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;project-code:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Project code&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The full application code on the master branch branch of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/sense/tree/steps&#34;&gt;sense repository&lt;/a&gt;.
This contains some refactorings that have not been demoed yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code created on stage at QCon London is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/sense/tree/qcon&#34;&gt;QCon branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;java-8-java-ee-overview:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Java 8 &amp;amp; Java EE Overview&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://winterbe.com/posts/2014/03/16/java-8-tutorial/&#34;&gt;Java 8 Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617291994/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1617291994&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=KDGWBWOK2S6FVS6F&#34;&gt;Java 8 in Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321927761/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321927761&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=7VJH32FI5ZVEDOMW&#34;&gt;Java 8 for the Really Impatient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/143024626X/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=143024626X&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=R75X5UJWBVYK4SV4&#34;&gt;Beginning Java EE 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lambdas-and-streams:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Lambdas and Streams&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1449370772/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1449370772&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=GGWNXKE672H3G2FY&#34;&gt;Lambdas and Streams&lt;/a&gt; by Richard Warburton,  highly recommended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adam-bien.com/roller/abien/entry/java_8_from_ordinary_for&#34;&gt;Java 8: From ordinary for-loop to an intstream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/ma14-java-se-8-streams-2177646.html&#34;&gt;Processing Data with Java SE 8 Streams, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, by Raoul-Gabriel Urma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617291994/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1617291994&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=QF2A5KBWSZALJJIZ&#34;&gt;Java 8 in Action&lt;/a&gt; also by Raoul-Gabriel Urma, and Mario Fusco &amp;amp; Alan Mycroft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RichardWarburton/lambda-behave&#34;&gt;lambda-behave&lt;/a&gt;, a Java 8 testing framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;javafx:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/javafx/get-started-tutorial/jfx-overview.htm#JFXST784&#34;&gt;Introduction to JavaFX&lt;/a&gt; - invaluable. Short enough to download as PDF and read cover-to-cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building serious JavaFX Applications - Adam Bien: &lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gKU7ZeCNbqU&#34;&gt;video presentation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AdamBien/lightfish&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/javafxinteg-2062777.html&#34;&gt;JavaFX Integration Strategies article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javafx/2/threads/jfxpub-threads.htm&#34;&gt;Concurrency in JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javafx/2/collections/jfxpub-collections.htm#CIHEJJFH&#34;&gt;Using JavaFX Collections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javafx/2/api/javafx/fxml/doc-files/introduction_to_fxml.html&#34;&gt;Introduction to FXML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javafx/2/get_started/fxml_tutorial.htm&#34;&gt;Using FXML to Create a User Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javafx/2/fxml_get_started/fxml_tutorial_intermediate.htm&#34;&gt;Using FXML to create a Table View&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javafx/2/binding/jfxpub-binding.htm&#34;&gt;Using JavaFX properties and binding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/webfolder/technetwork/tutorials/obe/java/BinaryWebSocket/binaryWebSocket.html#section4&#34;&gt;Creating Binary WebSocket Connections with Java EE 7 and JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RichardWarburton/honest-profiler&#34;&gt;honest-profiler&lt;/a&gt;, an Open Source project that uses JavaFX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321927761/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321927761&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=7VJH32FI5ZVEDOMW&#34;&gt;Java 8 for the Really Impatient&lt;/a&gt;, includes a section on JavaFX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;websockets:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Websockets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/jsr356-1937161.html&#34;&gt;JSR-356, Java API for WebSocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://java.dzone.com/articles/java-websockets-jsr-356-jetty&#34;&gt;Java WebSockets (JSR-356) on Jetty 9.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.programmingforliving.com/2013/08/jsr-356-java-api-for-websocket-client-api.html&#34;&gt;JSR 356 - Java API for Websocket (Java Client)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.idrsolutions.com/2013/12/websockets-an-introduction/&#34;&gt;Introduction to Websockets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/arungupta/entry/websocket_client_and_server_endpoint&#34;&gt;Annotated Websocket Clients&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mastertheboss.com/javaee/websockets/websockets-using-encoders-and-decoders&#34;&gt;Websockets: Using encoders and decoders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/webfolder/technetwork/tutorials/obe/java/BinaryWebSocket/binaryWebSocket.html#section4&#34;&gt;Creating Binary WebSocket Connections with Java EE 7 and JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jetty-project/embedded-jetty-websocket-examples&#34;&gt;embedded-jetty-websocket-examples&lt;/a&gt; examples of how to create Jetty Websockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;date-and-time:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Date and Time&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/jf14-date-time-2125367.html&#34;&gt;Java SE 8 Date and Time&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Evans and Richard Warburton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617291994/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1617291994&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=KDGWBWOK2S6FVS6F&#34;&gt;Java 8 in Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321927761/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321927761&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkId=7VJH32FI5ZVEDOMW&#34;&gt;Java 8 for the Really Impatient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;optional:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Optional&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.voxxed.com/blog/2015/02/defence-java-8s-optional-use/&#34;&gt;In Defence of Java 8&amp;rsquo;s Optional: Why and How to Use It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;files:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Files&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/essential/io/file.html&#34;&gt;Reading, Writing, and Creating Files&lt;/a&gt; - much simplified since Java 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;microservices:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Fowler on Microservices: &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/wgdBVIX9ifA&#34;&gt;25 minute video overview&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/microservices.html&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;special-thanks-to:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Special Thanks To&amp;hellip;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com.es/&#34;&gt;Martin Thompson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://insightfullogic.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Richard Warburton&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codingthearchitecture.com/authors/rannett/&#34;&gt;Robert Annett&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://hadihariri.com/&#34;&gt;Hadi Hariri&lt;/a&gt; for
code reviewing and giving great suggestions. Not all suggestions have been implemented yet, so all errors are my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract:1d84e04b0f74d0b3b985e46bf7a82f5d&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Java 9 is just around the corner, and yet many of us developers have yet to use Java 8 features in an application. The
goal of this presentation is to move beyond slide-sized examples of streams and lambdas, and to show how to build a
fully working end-to-end application using as few external dependencies as possible, and the latest version of Java.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this session, Trisha will build a Java 8 application live. This application will consume a real-time feed of high
velocity data, contain services that make sense of the data, and present it in a JavaFX dashboard. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ll
encounter Java 8 streams, lambdas, new ways of working with collections, and bump into the new date and time API.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
