<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Conferences on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/conferences/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, Backwards Compatibility? (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOW recorded me, yet again, talking about the adventure that is the design of the new Java Driver for MongoDB.  This is the same talk I
gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;,
with some updates based on our Journey So Far.  In it, I cover the architecture of the new driver and some of our current thoughts
around where we want the API to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yow.eventer.com/yow-2013-1080/what-do-you-mean-backwards-compatibility-by-trisha-gee-1398&#34;&gt;See the video here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events 2014</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I updated you on my travel plans, so now I&amp;rsquo;ve had some more conferences confirmed,
I thought I would pass the information on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been really lucky to have been selected for some great conferences this year.  I was asked to do a few more,
and it was genuinely painful to say no to everything, but it seems the laws of space and time cannot be broken,
and so I&amp;rsquo;ve been forced to select a tiny subset of all the places I&amp;rsquo;d like to go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 May: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/presentation/HTML5,%20Angular.js,%20Groovy,%20Java,
%20MongoDB%20all%20together%20-%20what%20could%20possibly%20go%20wrong?&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;m giving the same live coding presentation from QCon London,
although knowing me I expect there will be some tweaks, changes, additions, and maybe improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22-23 May: In New York City, since I&amp;rsquo;m more or less in the area.  Gimme a shout if you want to meet for a drink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25-28 May: &lt;a href=&#34;http://speakerconf.com/&#34;&gt;SpeakerConf&lt;/a&gt; Barcelona.  And while I&amp;rsquo;m in the area&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29 May: Barcelona JUG - &amp;ldquo;HTML5, Angular.js, Groovy, Java, MongoDB all together - what could possibly go wrong?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-5 June: New York City, probably (wait, am I going to be at home at all??)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23 July: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2014/public/schedule/detail/35444&#34;&gt;OSCON&lt;/a&gt; - live coding again!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;28 Sep - 2 Oct: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/speakers/index.html#gee&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt; woohoo!  I love having this opportunity to visit San
Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple of other events I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to work out the details for, but I think this is 2014 all booked up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2014</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2014</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2014</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. My 4th QCon London.&amp;nbsp; That’s not bad.&amp;nbsp; And every time, it’s a different experience (if you must, see my blogs for&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2013/03/qcon-day-one.html&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2012/03/qcon-london-2012.html&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;, and even 2007 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2007/03/qcon-initial-thoughts.html&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2007/03/qcon-todo-list-inspired-by-conference.html&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; - how cute was I? &amp;ldquo;agile seems like a jolly good idea; automated testing appears to be important&amp;rdquo;)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I can’t even tell you what I did on the first day, I was mostly panicking about my presentation - I was inspired after my trip to New York last month to change my talk at the last (responsible?) minute and do a live coding session, something much more technical than my recent talks.&amp;nbsp; I’ll leave the details for a separate blog post though, when the video comes out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thing that stands out for me from Wednesday though was Damian Conway programming &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway&#39;s_Game_of_Life&#34;&gt;Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life&lt;/a&gt; in Klingon.&amp;nbsp; Yeah.&amp;nbsp; Just find the video and watch it, the man is a genius.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; msallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; oallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/12947751623/player/f7e8167be5&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The Thursday keynote was inspiring too from a totally different point of view - Tim Lister of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DY5A8X2/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00DY5A8X2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&#34;&gt;Peopleware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00DY5A8X2&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt; fame shared stories from his career, and I came away from that really happy I work as a technologist, but with an increased desire to learn off other amazing people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; msallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; oallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/12966704755/player/7193594b96&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;On Thursday I hosted the&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/sets/72157641948363514/with/12970259753/&#34;&gt;Not Only Java&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;nbsp;track - I’m on the programme committee for QCon, and this year we wanted to cover&amp;nbsp;leading edge technologies (as always) but we didn’t want to slice things into strict technology silos [interruption: argh! the person in front of me nearly destroyed my laptop by suddenly moving their chair back! Why do people bother in economy on a morning flight?]. &amp;nbsp;So I wanted the Java track to be more representative of what today’s Java programmers care about - for the programmers of course, but also because I know there are architects and team leads at QCon who might not realise how things have moved on with the language, and how much polyglot programming we do these days.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com.es/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt; kicked it off with a great history lesson on the progress (or occasionally,&amp;nbsp; lack of it) in Java.&amp;nbsp; He begged us to study and understand Set Theory, to use async design, to think of the users of our APIs, and, most of all, to design nice, clean code.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Next up, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EvaAndreasson&#34;&gt;Eva&lt;/a&gt; took us through the fundamentals of Garbage Collection - this might not seem like a cutting edge subject these days, but it’s one of the most misunderstood subjects for Java programmers.&amp;nbsp; Eva gave us a really great, understandable view of the different types of garbage collectors, how they work, and their pros and cons.&amp;nbsp; She left us with a call to arms to not simply let other people try and solve this problem, but to get stuck in and contribute ourselves, via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/&#34;&gt;OpenJDK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; msallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; oallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/12970531704/player/e2c2f63b43&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After lunch was my nerve-wracking live coding session, putting together a full stack end-to-end web app using AngularJS, HTML5, Java and MongoDB.&amp;nbsp; It only went wrong twice, and people seemed to like it.&amp;nbsp; I’ll post the video in another blog post as soon as it&amp;rsquo;s publicly available. &amp;nbsp;Code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito&#34;&gt;available on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;We’ve been playing with the open spaces idea at QCon.&amp;nbsp; The Java one only had a few people in it, but that gave everyone a chance to speak at least.&amp;nbsp; We covered Java 8 (the Good and the Bad); other JVM languages; and UIs for Java (Javascript or GWT?).&amp;nbsp; And I plugged the work the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; does in London, of course.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;After this &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodil.org/&#34;&gt;Bodil&lt;/a&gt; blew me away creating a My Little Pony game using &lt;a href=&#34;https://rx.codeplex.com/&#34;&gt;RX&lt;/a&gt; in the browser.&amp;nbsp; ‘Nuff said.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/speakjava&#34;&gt;Simon Ritter&lt;/a&gt; gave us a view of the Java 8&amp;nbsp; features most likely to impact the way Java developers think about software design - lambdas and streams.&amp;nbsp; I thought this was a really great introduction to the concepts if you haven’t seen them before, and with concrete examples that showed how we should be using them. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re not already looking at lambdas and streams, you should be - even if you&amp;rsquo;re not going to be using Java 8 yet, it&amp;rsquo;s worth getting a heads up on how it&amp;rsquo;s going to impact our programming style.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I’m very pleased with the way the Java track turned out on the day - every speaker was first class, a wide range of topics was covered, and I, for one, learnt something in every presentation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;To finish off the day, Emma Langman gave an awesome keynote about how people are the messy bit of your system, and how they’re never rational and you shouldn’t expect them to be.&amp;nbsp; I also highly recommend this talk, especially if you’re a techy and you’ve found yourself in some sort of management or team lead position.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Sadly I couldn’t stay for day three of the conference, I had to fly off to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2014/03/the-joy-of-coding.html&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding&lt;/a&gt; to re-give the live coding presentation there.&amp;nbsp; Because, if you’re going to do something terrifying and doomed to failure, you might as well do it twice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;QCon is an expensive conference, especially compared to the developer-friendly prices of something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.co.uk/&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;, but for getting a big picture of where the industry is, of things you might be missing, for learning hard core technical skills and understanding the important of the fluffy-people-stuff, and finally for meeting a wide range of people from developers to CTOs, I think you&amp;rsquo;d be hard pushed to find something better in London. &amp;nbsp;IMHO (and remember, I did disclose I&amp;rsquo;m on the programme committee). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And although it&amp;rsquo;s really hard work putting together the programme for a track like this, and although both times I&amp;rsquo;ve said I&amp;rsquo;m Never Doing It Again, when it goes this well it makes you want to do it all over again. &amp;nbsp;After a break. &amp;nbsp;A looong break.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Coding</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_joy_of_coding</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_joy_of_coding</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-O7Z5io5SP0o/Uxs4eHZsx3I/AAAAAAAANPE/nTBXmPG-9ow/s1600/IMG_20140307_165203.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-O7Z5io5SP0o/Uxs4eHZsx3I/AAAAAAAANPE/nTBXmPG-9ow/s1600/IMG_20140307_165203.jpg&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34;&gt;Dick Wall -&amp;nbsp;The Tao, of the Joy, of Coding&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I’m on a plane (there’s a surprise) on my way back from &lt;a href=&#34;http://joyofcoding.org/&#34;&gt;The Joy of Coding&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; It’s the title that attracted me to this conference, and it was a great little one day event with awesome people like Dan North, Erik Meijer and Dick Wall presenting.&amp;nbsp; What I liked about the themes is they were broadly technology agnostic, pulling back to a level which made me remember why I’m a developer. &amp;nbsp;It inspired me to do more research and more thinking, and less panicking and trying to write code.&amp;nbsp; That might seem odd, as someone who goes to as many conferences as I do should get loads more research and thinking time than most developers living under the whip, but I seem to spend so much time bouncing from thing to thing I don’t get space to just sit and think, or to read things in any depth.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The conference organisers made it easy to focus on the bigger things - the venue was great, with a nice space for mingling with people but nooks and corners for doing work or for video conferences.&amp;nbsp; The hotel they chose was one of the best I’ve stayed at - the room had a sauna in it.&amp;nbsp; A sauna!&amp;nbsp; I spent the evening using every toiletry they provided, and moving between the sauna, the steam/shower cabinet and the jacuzzi bath.&amp;nbsp; I won’t pretend I did a lot of thinking, but it was a really awesome way to top of a crazy week, and I feel almost sane.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;So if I’m going to leave you with one thing from my experience at the Joy of Coding, it’s to Stop.&amp;nbsp; Stop and think.&amp;nbsp; Stop and ask.&amp;nbsp; Stop and read.&amp;nbsp; What are you doing?&amp;nbsp; Why are you doing it?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;And most of all, do you feel Joy when you’re coding?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-AObxzgL1rtA/Uxs4ft_YZMI/AAAAAAAANPM/XlRuZ97bRSM/s1600/IMG_20140307_190444.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-AObxzgL1rtA/Uxs4ft_YZMI/AAAAAAAANPM/XlRuZ97bRSM/s1600/IMG_20140307_190444.jpg&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PS There are some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/joyofcoding/sets/72157642055047693/&#34;&gt;really great photos&lt;/a&gt; from the conference on Flickr.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you notice I&#39;m a woman? Should I care?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/should_you_notice_im_a_woman_should_i_care</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/should_you_notice_im_a_woman_should_i_care</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, following on from my observations of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2014/02/so-fosdem.html&#34;&gt;being an outsider&lt;/a&gt; at FOSDEM because I&amp;rsquo;m not an open source developer, I do have another story to tell where my female-ness is actually relevant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to give specifics, but it&amp;rsquo;s not to name and shame or anything like that, it&amp;rsquo;s just that anonymising it will probably erase some of the subtleties. &amp;nbsp;But I&amp;rsquo;m not telling this to make anyone feel bad, because this is not an oh-poor-me story, this is just the way it goes sometimes and I want to share what it feels like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At JFokus (a conference I really enjoyed, where I got a chance to spend time with some awesome people) I was on a panel (well, game-show really) about static vs dynamic languages. &amp;nbsp;Not unusually, I was the only woman on the panel. &amp;nbsp;Also not unusually, one of the reasons I agreed to take part is to do my bit in demonstrating that women have technical knowledge too (in my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s important where possible to avoid a stage full of white men of a particular age, and I&amp;rsquo;m in a position to be able to do something about that). &amp;nbsp;And, as per usual, I was a bit nervous about this in case the only woman on the panel also turned out to look stupid, but hey, looking stupid is one of the risks of this job.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During the session, my gender was mentioned twice - once with &amp;ldquo;ladies first&amp;rdquo;, and once to specifically point out that our static-languages team was somehow superior because we had both genders represented (well of course we&amp;rsquo;re better, &lt;i&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m&lt;/i&gt; on the team). Note that neither of these was derogatory at all - both were, in fact, positive towards me, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t troubled or offended by them. I&amp;rsquo;m used to people noticing and commenting on my gender. &amp;nbsp;I got used to it in the same way you get used to your commute to work, or dealing with merge conflicts - it&amp;rsquo;s something you do, it&amp;rsquo;s not always comfortable, but it&amp;rsquo;s no one&amp;rsquo;s fault and they&amp;rsquo;re not out to get you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really process how the gender-mentions made me feel until after, at which point I was drained from giving yet another new talk that day, as well as the surprisingly physical panel discussion. But afterwards, when I was back in my hotel room packing for yet another plane journey, I was thinking &amp;ldquo;is it normal?&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;Was it inevitable that someone was going to notice/point out that I&amp;rsquo;m female? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Was it down to my choice of clothing? &amp;nbsp;I debated long and hard with myself about wearing what was definitely a ridiculously short skirt for a session like that, but in the end I decided I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wear jeans like everyone else, and wearing tiny skirts is something I find fun. But I did think I&amp;rsquo;d be behind a table and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too obvious. &amp;nbsp;Should I worry that much about what I wear? &amp;nbsp;I used to plan what to wear for work, I used to love dressing up for going out with friends, so over-thinking my clothes for a conference is part of who I am.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And one of the reasons to wear the skirt is because I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself wearing jeans and t-shirts more than ever. &amp;nbsp;I think the combination of travelling a lot (I &lt;i&gt;hate&lt;/i&gt; packing, so packing a couple of pairs of jeans and a bunch of t-shirts makes life easy) and being part of a tech company where that&amp;rsquo;s basically our uniform has lead to extreme laziness in my clothing choices, and I want to change that. &amp;nbsp;Who wants to look like everyone else? &amp;nbsp;Not me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So back in that hotel room, at the end of a long day, knowing I have to get up at 5am the next morning to get on a plane to New York, I felt drained. &amp;nbsp;I felt&amp;hellip; vulnerable? But if I dig down to find out what&amp;rsquo;s really making me feel not-cool, it&amp;rsquo;s not because a couple of people noticed I was a girl. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s because I was tired, because I was on display, because I had been worried about my choice of clothes, because drawing attention to yourself is not terribly British, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if my new talk was any good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to blame impostor syndrome, or something similar. And maybe this is what impostor syndrome feels like. But I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure every conference speaker, whatever their gender, race, sexual orientation, age, has felt this way. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s because I have two X chromosomes and I&amp;rsquo;m in a male-dominated environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what conclusions to draw from this experience. &amp;nbsp;I did want to share it so that other people know what it feels like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Possible conclusions:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re tired, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to blame the first thing that springs to mind for your lack of shiny-happy feelings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot on your plate, seemingly-innocuous (even those driven by positive intentions) comments or actions can increase your stress levels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t think too much. &amp;nbsp;It can drive you mad.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel like an outsider?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/feel_like_an_outsider</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/feel_like_an_outsider</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;So, FOSDEM.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I&#39;ve heard great things about this conference, so I was pretty exited to go&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PmLM8wpvxns/UvaWZpqWFeI/AAAAAAAAMxI/dqKWFf_PH4M/s1600/JavaDevRoom.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PmLM8wpvxns/UvaWZpqWFeI/AAAAAAAAMxI/dqKWFf_PH4M/s1600/JavaDevRoom.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The Java dev room&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Now I know people talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&#34;&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt; whenever they mention the woeful lack of diversity at tech conferences.&amp;nbsp; Interestingly, I felt like an impostor at FOSDEM - not because I&#39;m a woman (there were quite a few techy women around at FOSDEM, more than I expected) but because I&#39;m not an open source person.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I mean, I am, technically - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; and the Java driver are both open source, and I have real live code on github.&amp;nbsp; But I didn&#39;t get there via the open source community, I was hired to do a specific job that happens to be open source (for which I am extremely grateful).&amp;nbsp; So although I knew the MongoDB folks I was there with and a lot of people who were running or speaking in the Java room, I didn&#39;t feel really at home in this conference.&amp;nbsp; I think I feel more comfortable with the ones aimed at enterprise Java developers (by which I mean Java people who work producing software for companies) because this is more similar to my background - I understand the attendees and I think I know what they want.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;It&#39;s also possible since I&#39;ve been to a lot more of the enterprise-aimed conferences that I used to feel just as awkward there, and I&#39;ve become much more comfortable now I&#39;ve been to many.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Which leads me to another observation: when I first went to JavaOne, in 2011, I felt extremely conspicuous as a woman.&amp;nbsp; I mean, I didn&#39;t do much to help, my skirts and shorts are occasionally… not really enterprise-developer-length.&amp;nbsp; But I felt like everyone noticed me and I felt the pressure to assert early on in every new conversation that I was, in fact, a developer and not a booth babe or a recruiter.&amp;nbsp; But these days, I feel much more comfortable.&amp;nbsp; And do you know what&#39;s really helped with that?&amp;nbsp; Being a speaker; having my face on the website.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t have to prove I&#39;m a developer, I was asked to speak at that conference - if the conference organisers think I belong there, then I belong there.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;So… what.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Well, we can do things to combat this I-don&#39;t-belong-here feeling -&amp;nbsp;I&#39;m pretty sure we&#39;ve all been there, regardless of gender, race, background etc. &amp;nbsp;To be honest, us geeks probably feel this more than most humans.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Conferences and user groups and meet ups and so forth can all make life a little easier for those feeling this.&amp;nbsp; At the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;, for example, we started having greeters at the door for our social events, to try and make everyone feel welcomed and to introduce people to each other.&amp;nbsp; I also liked what YOW did - they had a really informal social event at the end of the first day of the conference (with free booze, yay!) which made it relatively easy to mingle with other people.&amp;nbsp; FOSDEM, with its lack of free food and drink gave us less opportunities to mingle with people other than your own friends, although I did like the canteen area for random encounters.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;But it&#39;s not just down to organisers of groups or events to solve this problem for us. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ve found that if you do feel like you don&#39;t belong, there&#39;s a way to get over that, and it&#39;s not to withdraw.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s to get more involved.&amp;nbsp; Find the groups you feel most comfortable with (for me, it started at the LJC), find the medium that you&#39;re most comfortable with (in person meet-ups, e-mail, IRC, Twitter, whatever), and join in.&amp;nbsp; Have conversations.&amp;nbsp; Meet people.&amp;nbsp; Once you start to make friends you start to feel like you belong, and when you start to feel like you belong you can step up and do more.&amp;nbsp; You might even find yourself accidentally propelled into speaking at an international conference, and who knows where you find yourself after that?&amp;nbsp; Although I appreciate that&#39;s not for everyone.&amp;nbsp; The point is, find your comfort zone for entry and gradually push yourself more - as you find yourself more accepted and respected, you&#39;ll feel less like an outsider. &amp;nbsp;At the very least, you&#39;ll have friends to talk to at these sorts of events.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;And don&#39;t be put off by a couple of bad experiences - you don&#39;t have to go back to that group, those people, that thing, but don&#39;t assume that all groups or events are like that. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ve been to a number of events, techy or otherwise, that I didn&#39;t feel at home with. &amp;nbsp;If, after two tries (in person, I&#39;ll give e-mails lists or chat rooms many more chances), I still don&#39;t get on with it, I try somewhere else.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;There are still going to be times when you&#39;re not in your comfort zone, but this is probably healthy - pushing yourself a little leads to different opportunities.&amp;nbsp; And in my case, it reminded me what it was like to be an outsider, a newbie.&amp;nbsp; And that gives us greater empathy for people in that situation.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YOW</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/yow</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/yow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;December disappeared in a rush of vacation and a fleeting tour of Australia. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that it&amp;rsquo;s the eve of Christmas Eve already, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to feel Christmassy when you&amp;rsquo;re getting sunburnt on a boat and seeing people in swim-suits wearing santa hats. &amp;nbsp;A mid-winter festival (complete with trees and fake snow) just feels very odd in summer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PWSc0RE99iQ/UrhWxezIRSI/AAAAAAAAMB8/wQSmg4lwVl8/s1600/Cliff.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PWSc0RE99iQ/UrhWxezIRSI/AAAAAAAAMB8/wQSmg4lwVl8/s400/Cliff.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;I cannot take Christmas seriously in this weather&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yowconference.com.au/&#34;&gt;YOW!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a unique conference, in that it&amp;rsquo;s the same agenda in three different cities: Melbourne, Brisbane and Sydney. &amp;nbsp;It seems to me that this is a great way to attract speakers from a long way away (and &lt;i&gt;everywhere&lt;/i&gt; is a long way away from Australia) but make it cost effective - although you have to shuttle the speakers between the cities, you have the speakers for nearly two weeks and get the material three times in the three different locations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-bVUihtZxvfY/UrhXL-fc8cI/AAAAAAAAMCE/J9RjMWAhOjY/s1600/1Coogee.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-bVUihtZxvfY/UrhXL-fc8cI/AAAAAAAAMCE/J9RjMWAhOjY/s400/1Coogee.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;I suffered a lot for this conference&amp;hellip;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;As a speaker, it&amp;rsquo;s awesome - not only do you spend the better part of the month in the sun when your hemisphere is nearing mid-winter, but you also have the opportunity to really get to know the other speakers - you&amp;rsquo;re sharing bus journeys, flights and dinners together for a week and a half. &amp;nbsp;Also, because you&amp;rsquo;re at the same conference three times, you have the chance to see a lot more of the talks. &amp;nbsp;I admit I missed most of them in Melbourne because I was re-writing and practicing both my talks (note to self - next time, only commit to one talk), but by Sydney I saw the talks that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally get around to - talks on technologies I&amp;rsquo;m not currently using and probably won&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to. &amp;nbsp;But it was great to see other approaches to problems, and the variety of presentation styles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xSTWWRVPSqA/UrhXgAkENRI/AAAAAAAAMCM/7wR39QH1mWI/s1600/1Sydney+night.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xSTWWRVPSqA/UrhXgAkENRI/AAAAAAAAMCM/7wR39QH1mWI/s400/1Sydney+night.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since I saw most of the talks, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give a run down of those I watched (now I feel bad I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to see everyone&amp;rsquo;s, if I missed you it&amp;rsquo;s not because I don&amp;rsquo;t love you):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef9f36950e81dc55000027?track=Keynote&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Computing Like the Brain: The Path to Machine Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jeff Hawkins (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/numenta&#34;&gt;@numenta&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Jeff talk on this subject twice before - an earlier version of the talk at Strangeloop 2012, and then the keynote at GOTO Aarhus. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s a really fascinating approach to machine learning that&amp;rsquo;s different to traditional Artificial Intelligence approaches. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s waaay beyond my comprehension level, but reminded me why I studied AI at university. &amp;nbsp;If you get a chance to see it, I recommend it. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/video#5&#34;&gt;video available of the Aarhus talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51fbdfff9bd61fe46d000015?track=Agile+Practices&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Safety Not Guaranteed: How Successful Teams Ignore the Rules to Create Successful Products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jeff Patton (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/jeffpatton&#34;&gt;@jeffpatton&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A thought-provoking talk on how agile teams succeed. &amp;nbsp;Mostly it talks about how a process is not going to save you, that you need to find your own approach from all the practices that are available. &amp;nbsp;I liked the message because it&amp;rsquo;s very &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004J4XGN6/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004J4XGN6&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&#34;&gt;Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;-ish, and I think the approach of getting feedback and learning from it is the best way to succeed. &amp;nbsp;My take-home points:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Change from a delivery-focussed organisation to a learning organisation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re on time, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wrong&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When we think &amp;ldquo;process&amp;rdquo; we rarely think collaboration and team&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Those guys aren&amp;rsquo;t high-fiving because they hit a deadline.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;       &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef7df4950e81d4a3000006?track=Big+Data+%2F+NoSQL&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;A Little Graph Theory for the Busy Developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Jim Webber (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/jimwebber&#34;&gt;@jimwebber&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not using Neo4J or other graph databases, it&amp;rsquo;s worth seeing this talk just to understand what sort of problems graphs are good at solving. &amp;nbsp;Also to see how graph theory could have predicted the first world war (not sure if this was funnier or more awkward when Jim presented this in Berlin&amp;hellip;). &amp;nbsp;A great talk if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in Data Structures or the NoSQL space. &amp;nbsp;Not so good when Jim feels compelled to make Mongo Is Web Scale jokes because he sees yours truly in the front row. &amp;nbsp;Will we never get over that? &amp;nbsp;Jim&amp;rsquo;s a great presenter and therefore this theoretical talk is very approachable.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Take home points:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;With graph databases your query emerges from the structure of the graph itself&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It seems like another interesting way of modelling your domain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most databases are tuned for size because traditionally size impacts the cost of querying&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In a graph database, query latency is proportional to the size of the graph you want to explore (not to the whole database).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51f9f4b43549b6d556000003?track=Languages+%26+VMs&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Beyond JVM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Charles Nutter (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/headius&#34;&gt;@headius&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Quite an in-depth talk about how the JVM could evolve to support more than simply Java-the-language. &amp;nbsp;Interesting at an abstract level for us Java developers to see how our language is not the be-all and end-all, and get a glimpse of things we might need to care about in the future. &amp;nbsp;Not too many take-home points for the every day developer, but definitely interesting for those more interested in how a language is built and what goes on behind the scenes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;       &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/5298136074c18eb641000084?track=Big+Data+%2F+NoSQL&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;NoSQL &amp;amp; NewSQL - The Empire Strikes Back?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Dave Thomas (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/daveathomas&#34;&gt;@daveathomas&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A look at the whole landscape - past, present and future - of RDBMS/SQL, NoSQL, NewSQL. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s a good way to step back and see what&amp;rsquo;s going on there, not to blindly follow the new trends. &amp;nbsp;The thoughts that occurred to me:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;NoSQL solutions might not be the silver bullet solution, but by offering lots of different persistence options we&amp;rsquo;re challenging perceived best-practices and having conversations around how to store and access our data&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SQL was never actually evil.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Joins suck; the O/R Impedance Mismatch; two phase commits are expensive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Map/reduce is the best way to query NoSQL stores?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef95f49ff771eff9000020?track=DevOps&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Five Years of DevOps: Where are we now?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Michael Nygard (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mtnygard&#34;&gt;@mtnygard&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Michael gave a really great talk on where the DevOps movement started, what it&amp;rsquo;s all about, and tackled some of the fears and obstacles that people and organisations face that can prevent them doing things in a more DevOps-y way (and problems that you keep seeing when you separate Dev and Ops). &amp;nbsp;I saw a lot of things in this talk that resonated with my experiences, and it was another example of how the hard stuff in our jobs is all about the people and the politics, not the technologies.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What if you measured Ops on the number of features going into production, and Dev on the stability of production?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Performance is a feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll never teach yourself out of a job, the more you teach, the more people will rely on you&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A failure-inducing system is a system that lets people fail. &amp;nbsp;Don&amp;rsquo;t blame the people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your development tools and environment are part of production, because they are on the critical path to production, and should be treated as such.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ece0f7eb4e68a11c000008?track=Service+%2F+API+Design&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;The SOLID Design Principles Deconstructed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Kevlin Henney (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kevlinhenney&#34;&gt;@kevlinhenney&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Given my interest in Software Design this year, this was a talk that was close to my heart. It looked at each of the SOLID principles, where they came from, what they are, helped us understand why we need to care about them (or not). &amp;nbsp;It became clear to me that as we become more experienced, as we grow, we need to continually re-visit the things we think we know, or the basics of what we&amp;rsquo;re trying to do, as you&amp;rsquo;ll find things there that surprise you - things you thought you understood, or things that you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand before and now have more context for. &amp;nbsp;In particular, I learnt another argument against using inheritance willy-nilly (one of my current favourite bug-bears)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Writing software is like writing fiction.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Experts say &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo; because they know a number of rules which might be applicable.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t change &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/PublishedInterface.html&#34;&gt;published interfaces&lt;/a&gt; because other people are dependent upon your code (pretty much the entire basis of my Backwards Compatibility talk), but if you own the code you can change it to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51f116466b93322f4900000f?track=Service+%2F+API+Design&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Creating Observable APIs with Rx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Ben Christensen (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/benjchristensen&#34;&gt;@benjchristensen&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Netflix are doing some really amazing stuff with architecture, design and code, and what I love the most is that they&amp;rsquo;re willing to share it with the rest of us. Rx and reactive programming are big buzz words at the moment, and the event-driven, asynchronous approach is something that we embraced at LMAX and is now, to my mind, an &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo; way to create scalable systems.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I liked Ben&amp;rsquo;s visualisation of the events in the system using marble diagrams, and I liked that he showed us code and walked through it. &amp;nbsp;There were a number of things to get your head around in the talk, and I personally would like to see it again to see what I missed first time around. &amp;nbsp;Definitely worth watching if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this way of coding, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a paradigm that will be used more and more.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51fbdf7d9bd61f5a2a00000c?track=Peopleware&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Hiring (or Growing) the Right Agile Coach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lyssa Adkins (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lyssaadkins&#34;&gt;@lyssaadkins&lt;/a&gt;) and Michael Spayd (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mspayd&#34;&gt;@mspayd&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why it never occurred to me that you could create a framework for professional development for agile coaches. &amp;nbsp;Lyssa and Michael have done just that, and having something a bit more formalised helps figure out what a coach needs to do in order to develop further. &amp;nbsp;Agile coach, scrum master, iteration lead&amp;hellip; all these titles do not currently tell anyone how good you are at the job or what your strengths and weaknesses are. &amp;nbsp;The Agile Coach Competency Framework seems like a good starting point for conversations around: the coaches you have; the coaches you need; your current skills as a coach; the direction you want to go in as a coach. &amp;nbsp;If you need to hire or develop an agile coach, or if you are a professional in this space, this is worth looking at.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef8426950e81d4a300000b?track=Concurrency&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Disruptor 3.0: Details and Advanced Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mike Barker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikeb2701&#34;&gt;@mikeb2701&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was so pleased to hang around with my old LMAX colleague during YOW that I totally failed to take the time to see all of this talk. &amp;nbsp;Depending upon the city it either clashed with mine or was immediately before. &amp;nbsp;However, it&amp;rsquo;s a must-see for fans of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/disruptor&#34;&gt;the Disruptor&lt;/a&gt;, Mike goes into detail about what&amp;rsquo;s in the latest version of the Disruptor, how and why these things work. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be watching the video when it&amp;rsquo;s online.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef9cf09ff771058e00001b?track=Keynote&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Angle Brackets, Curly Braces, JavaScript &amp;amp; Assembler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;Scott Hanselman (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shanselman&#34;&gt;@shanselman&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A funny, polished, brilliant keynote. &amp;nbsp;Honestly I can&amp;rsquo;t remember anything about it other than something-something-Microsoft-cloud, and push things down to the client because there&amp;rsquo;s power there, but don&amp;rsquo;t let that put you off - I did not write notes, I simply sat and enjoyed every minute of it. &amp;nbsp;It was a great performance, and a reminder of how much practice it takes to become a truly good keynote speaker.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/52760f3d4bca24015d000007?track=Visualisation&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Programming In Time - Live Coding for Creative Performances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;Andrew Sorensen (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/digego&#34;&gt;@digego&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I have only one word in my notes for this talk:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Awesome.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It was the best presentation of the conference. &amp;nbsp;Different to anything I&amp;rsquo;d seen before, engrossing, creative, fun. &amp;nbsp;Sure, watch the video, but if you get a chance to catch this at any other conference, I highly recommend seeing it in person.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51f1179a36d9dd4fac000012?track=Agile+Testing+%26+Specifications&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Handling Uncertainty with Behaviour-Driven Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Liz Keogh (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/lunivore&#34;&gt;@lunivore&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I nearly didn&amp;rsquo;t go to this talk, because we did BDD at LMAX and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to lead us towards this at MongoDB and I know all this stuff blah blah blah. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did go - not only is it nice to have your opinions confirmed and the concepts you try to live by repeated to you again, but there were things in here that should help me push the BDD approach more.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;One of the things I remember Liz for is explaining the use of the word &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2010/07/lean-software-and-systems-conference.html&#34;&gt;Lean conference at Bletchley in 2010&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;In this talk I was struck once again how important the words we use are: should, given/when/then, and so on, giving us a framework for thinking about a problem. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I wanted to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/spock&#34;&gt;move towards Spock&lt;/a&gt;, because it forces the use of some of these words.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I wrote lots of notes:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assume you got it wrong&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is there a context in which the event will create a different outcome? (Your account is empty, the ATM is out of cash, you have a pre-approved overdraft)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t think of the software that will solve the problem, assume it will be done by pixies (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.lspace.org/mediawiki/index.php/Iconograph&#34;&gt;Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s Iconograph&lt;/a&gt;), forcing us to stop thinking of solutions when we&amp;rsquo;re trying to outline the problem.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not all user stories are about the user, they might be about other stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acceptance criteria vs scenarios - &amp;ldquo;Can you give me an example?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ask why a change needs to be made or why something is a bug, if I&amp;rsquo;ve messed up this feature I might have messed up something else&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Testers do think differently to developers, they have a process of deliberate discovery&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;BA/Dev/Tester huddle - the three amigos&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If a project has no risks, don&amp;rsquo;t do it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complicated/Complex/Chaotic/Simple projects/systems. &amp;nbsp;Some types of systems don&amp;rsquo;t lend themselves well to BDD&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All the risk is in Complex problems, and this is also likely where the value is. &amp;nbsp;This is the area that developers tend to like to live.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Afterwards I questioned Liz on her separation of Devs and Testers in the talk - this seems contra to the current trend of hiring developers-in-test or other moves to make QAs and developers one-team-one-dream. &amp;nbsp;She pointed out that it&amp;rsquo;s less of a job description and more of a role that people take in a team. &amp;nbsp;Then she suggested I was currently in a tester role, not developer, as my mindset is very much focussed around proving our code quality rather than jumping in and implementing features. &amp;nbsp;I think it was meant as a positive thing&amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;       &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51f10bf536d9ddae2800000b?track=Architecture+%26+Security&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Practical Considerations For Microservice Architectures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sam Newman (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/samnewman&#34;&gt;@samnewman&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;ldquo;Microservices&amp;rdquo; is another one of these buzz words doing the rounds at the moment. &amp;nbsp;There was a lot of discussion amongst the speakers about how micro is micro, and one definition I liked was &amp;ldquo;a microservice is a service that does one thing and one thing only&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp; In Sam&amp;rsquo;s talk I got an idea of why microservices are a Good Thing, and how you might go about moving in that direction. &amp;nbsp;There was practical advice on things you should be doing if you&amp;rsquo;re using this kind of architecture:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Align your services with your organisational structure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microservices let you deploy independently and move faster, and you can run each service in whichever technology / language is right for the job&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Standardisation vs autonomy - standardisation between services, autonomy within.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pick conventions and stick with them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Try not to support distributed transactions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You need to get better at monitoring&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can create tracer messages that flow through the system&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create templates that do the right thing, make it easy for people to do the right thing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51f109ba6b9332a9d4000008?track=Visualisation&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Google Earth Engine: Enabling Science with Novel Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mike Dixon&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I saw this because I&amp;rsquo;m interested in geolocation and geo-stuff at the moment, but this talk wasn&amp;rsquo;t really about the sort of thing I&amp;rsquo;m playing around with. &amp;nbsp;It was (to my mind) really interesting material though - using satellite images from the past few decades to spot patterns and predict things. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s really nice to see applications of technology that could potentially impact the whole world, rather than just things that make money for companies. &amp;nbsp;My Dad, who&amp;rsquo;s a geography teacher, would have loved this talk.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef87399ff771873d000010?track=Cloud+At+Scale&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Architecture at Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;Adrian Cockcroft (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/adrianco&#34;&gt;@adrianco&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Really interesting talk, always to a packed room, about how Netflix has created a scalable architecture. &amp;nbsp;As I said earlier, I&amp;rsquo;m really impressed with what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in their chaos monkeys and primates. &amp;nbsp;I definitely recommend seeing this presentation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;       &lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/523bffa776f3b7024900017c?track=Cloud+At+Scale&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Move Fast and Ship Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Joel Pobar (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/joelpob&#34;&gt;@joelpob&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qViqqm6GLK0/UrhXuLGHn3I/AAAAAAAAMCY/kQXI7qDhy98/s1600/1Facebook.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qViqqm6GLK0/UrhXuLGHn3I/AAAAAAAAMCY/kQXI7qDhy98/s320/1Facebook.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A look under the covers of how Facebook ships things. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s a very interesting contrast to the Netflix, microservices approach. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s great to see the different approaches at the same conference, maybe it gives people an idea of the pros and cons of each way forward. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What I particularly liked from Facebook was that the teams seem to be set a goal, and then they&amp;rsquo;re free (to some extent) to pick what to work on in order to meet that goal. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s definitely an experimentation side to things (very Lean Startup again), a lack of fear of trying new things, some stuff will work and some won&amp;rsquo;t, that&amp;rsquo;s life. &amp;nbsp;But at the end of the day there&amp;rsquo;s a definite measurable that will tell you if you&amp;rsquo;re doing the right thing or not. &amp;nbsp;On the VM team, the aim is to get CPU cycles down, that&amp;rsquo;s it. &amp;nbsp;This is a very different approach to having a backlog of stories that&amp;rsquo;s prioritised by the business. &amp;nbsp;Interesting and useful stuff in this talk.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef98ef9ff771873d000042?track=Adopting+FP&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned from Adopting Clojure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jay Fields (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/thejayfields&#34;&gt;@thejayfields&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I went to this talk because I chatted to Jay a number of times throughout the travelling circus, and I liked him - I have almost zero interest in Clojure at this moment in time. &amp;nbsp;But I&amp;rsquo;m really glad I went, because I learnt loads of stuff that&amp;rsquo;s relevant for my day job (who knew?). &amp;nbsp;This presentation is basically about how to introduce a new language into a company/team, and he&amp;rsquo;s able to show the process over a period of several years, which in our industry is a life-time - many talks are around the latest, shiniest thing a company has introduced. &amp;nbsp;He speaks frankly about the cost of introducing a new language, gives some good advice on the approach to take, and personally made me wonder if I might have bitten off more than I can chew by sneaking Groovy into the Java driver via Spock and Gradle.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t force people to use a different editor AND a different language - if you take away both comfort zones you&amp;rsquo;ll meet resistance&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep the other tools in place too - ant, maven, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose non-production code to try it out on&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose code that showcases the power of the language, its strengths&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose something that you&amp;rsquo;re willing to keep in the old language, in case it all goes horribly wrong and you have to go back&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;ve introduced a new language, you&amp;rsquo;ve just given yourself a second full-time job - supporting that language, training people, etc. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You need to know everything - you are the expert. &amp;nbsp;Read everything.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get a budget for training and support&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s practical to get your career sorted before playing with new technologies&amp;rdquo; (I wrote that down and now don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting point)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so many things you can do by innovating and adopting a new language.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51fbdd9b2e4c941eff00000c?track=Agile+Practices&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Focusing the Core Domain: Domain-Driven Design Case Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Eric Evans (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ericevans0&#34;&gt;@ericevans0&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I always love meeting people who&amp;rsquo;s books I&amp;rsquo;ve read (or at least, started). &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve been really interested in the Domain Driven Design stuff since the guys were banging on about it at LMAX, and I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to use some of the concepts to drive the design of the new Java driver for MongoDB. This presentation was a specific (anonymised) case study of applying Domain Driven Design. &amp;nbsp;My main take away point is that &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; plunging into development, that asking questions, that waiting, is sometimes the best thing you can do. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51ef94039ff771873d00003d?track=Mobile+Development&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Mobile Web Whirlwind Tour of PhoneGap, Cordova &amp;amp; Topcoat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;Brian LeRoux (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/brianleroux&#34;&gt;@brianleroux&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not doing mobile development at the moment, so this is another talk I went to because I met Brian at the various speakers events and wanted to see his talk. &amp;nbsp;It was another talk I really enjoyed - very well presented, technical, code-y, entertaining. &amp;nbsp;And it also blew away my preconceptions about PhoneGap, an opinion I had formulated during my very short stint working at ThoughtWorks three years ago. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re in the mobile space, or even in web development, definitely worth watching. &amp;nbsp;If not, then maybe just give it a watch to see what&amp;rsquo;s happening out there.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re web developers, we don&amp;rsquo;t need tests&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cadence and project heartbeat really important&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Performance first&amp;rdquo;, but actually it&amp;rsquo;s about the people&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find one thing and do it well&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Measure everything&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build a real app and extract out the components, instead of doing enterprise architecture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Help pages with example code templates: &amp;ldquo;developers copy and paste, at least this way they&amp;rsquo;ll be copying the right stuff&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51f1191a6b9332a9d4000018?track=Agile+Practices&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;What colour is your backlog?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Philipe Krutchen (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/pbpk&#34;&gt;@pbpk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UGW8aUr1o5Y/UrhXvYDsPEI/AAAAAAAAMCg/7F2oRxYDicQ/s1600/1Philippe.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UGW8aUr1o5Y/UrhXvYDsPEI/AAAAAAAAMCg/7F2oRxYDicQ/s320/1Philippe.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Scrum-type methodologies tend to focus on user stories and feature delivery. &amp;nbsp;This presentation talks about physically colouring the different types of work that you have in your backlog (tech debt, bugs, stories, architecture) and understanding how to prioritise each of them. &amp;nbsp;This talk is worth seeing if you are in a Scrum-ish environment, and you have a backlog of stories. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to find time to address tech debt, this is probably applicable too. &amp;nbsp;For me, the take-away point was simply having visibility of the different types of work - often the backlog only contains stories, and the other stuff is missing. &amp;nbsp;From there, you&amp;rsquo;re in a better position to work out how to prioritise things.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/52725f4c403edc223500004f?track=Mobile+Development&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;No App is an Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Stewart Gleadow (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/stewgleadow&#34;&gt;@stewgleadow&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;More and more people are talking about APIs, especially as we now have lots of different ways of getting to data/applications, even if you just think web/phone/tablet. &amp;nbsp;Stew gives very solid advice on how to build APIs so that you can correctly separate back- and front-end, and create (specifically) great iOS apps. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s a good intro to what REST really means too.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Different devices don&amp;rsquo;t have to share the same API if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well for them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;On Objective C: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like ugly Ruby, or beautiful Java&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;From day one send the information about the client version, the handset etc. to the server&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You must worry about backwards compatibility because there&amp;rsquo;s a very long tail on app upgrades&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Libraries that bind your JSON have tight coupling&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can ship client code that checks if a feature is available on the server and ignore it if not - that lets you turn on the feature at the server-end&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Encourage upgrades to the new version, by doing things like &amp;ldquo;if you had version 347 you could use this feature&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The phone application is the hardest thing to change so it should not be your integration point&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You need an anti-corruption layer, your phone should not be pointing to the internal systems. &amp;nbsp;This will be your mobile API, and can include caching and security&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If your logic is in the client, it&amp;rsquo;s in the place that&amp;rsquo;s hardest to change.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--b3R8z-bE5s/UrhYAwsplXI/AAAAAAAAMCo/xjAzpJdjsI0/s1600/1Sydney.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--b3R8z-bE5s/UrhYAwsplXI/AAAAAAAAMCo/xjAzpJdjsI0/s400/1Sydney.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And then there&amp;rsquo;s my talks. &amp;nbsp;Like I said, I was foolish enough to say yes to giving two of them, but the great thing was I got the chance to do a fluffy talk and a technical talk.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;       &lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/5289a82d0e428edc09000311?track=Peopleware&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;Career Advice for Programmers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Dave Thomas saw me give a &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/video#36&#34;&gt;talk with this title at Aarhus&lt;/a&gt;, and asked me to present it at YOW. &amp;nbsp;I was really pleased to get this chance, because conferences often find it hard to excuse a talk that might suggest you get a new job when your employer probably paid for your ticket.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t that happy with the Aarhus version, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest - I was trying to squeeze everything I&amp;rsquo;d learnt about managing my career over the last 15 years into an hour&amp;rsquo;s talk, and I failed horribly. &amp;nbsp;I re-wrote it almost entirely for YOW - it&amp;rsquo;s clear there is a lot of stuff I&amp;rsquo;d love to talk about that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to cover, but hopefully this talk is more broadly useful for everyone.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;YOW might not have been the best audience for it, as most people had my level of experience or more, and a number of people said &amp;ldquo;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d known that 10 years ago&amp;rdquo;, but my experience seems to tally with other people&amp;rsquo;s, so maybe it will be helpful to more people over time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kinda weird to stand there and talk about all the choices you made to get to where you are, the mistakes you&amp;rsquo;ve made and explain some of the choices. &amp;nbsp;Especially weird if some of my ex-employers ever see the talk. &amp;nbsp;But I did learn a lot of things the hard way, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t end up here by accident, I want other developers (especially those in the early stages of their career) to learn things the easy way.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a.confui.com/public/conferences/517fce8207933939cd000001/locations/517fce8207933939cd000002/schedule/topics/51fbdf382e4c947d3600000d?track=Service+%2F+API+Design&amp;amp;framehost=http://melbourne.yowconference.com.au&#34;&gt;What do you mean, backwards compatibility?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/p/public-appearances.html&#34;&gt;given a talk with this title&lt;/a&gt; a number of times this year. &amp;nbsp;It morphed from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;original version&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;into two different talks - &amp;ldquo;Design is a Process, not a Document&amp;rdquo; and a more MongoDB-focussed one, which I reused the original title for. &amp;nbsp;This newer, MongoDB-focussed one is what I gave at GOTO Berlin, and I decided to use this for YOW as it&amp;rsquo;s a technical (ish) talk that goes into some detail about MongoDB, and they do pay my rent.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The really great (or possibly, bad) thing about YOW is that because it&amp;rsquo;s the same conference at three venues, only a few days apart, it gives you a chance to put your Lean Startup knowledge into practice - you can experiment, get feedback, and improve. &amp;nbsp;Like the GOTOs/QCons, they have a Green/Yellow/Red feedback system from the audience so you can get a feel for how they liked your talk (the Aussies are a bit non-committal, they were keen on the Yellow button - commit one way or another!! (or don&amp;rsquo;t, I don&amp;rsquo;t want more reds)). &amp;nbsp;So decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing&#34;&gt;A/B test&lt;/a&gt; my talk - at Melbourne, I gave the GOTO Berlin one; at Brisbane, the original one with updated code and design diagrams. &amp;nbsp;Since the Brisbane one got a higher score, I went with that with some minor tweaks for Sydney. &amp;nbsp;The upshot is, people like hand-drawn pictures of monsters, and are less keen on understanding the internals of MongoDB. &amp;nbsp;That&amp;rsquo;s useful to know.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br class=&#34;Apple-interchange-newline&#34; /&gt;But the talks aren&amp;rsquo;t the only things that make a conference. &amp;nbsp;And YOW got the other stuff right too:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-tw7VJOelqZI/UrhYDYgURFI/AAAAAAAAMCw/7sGUtQo8QnQ/s1600/1Catamaran.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-tw7VJOelqZI/UrhYDYgURFI/AAAAAAAAMCw/7sGUtQo8QnQ/s320/1Catamaran.jpg&#34; width=&#34;265&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;li&gt;I loved the drinks receptions in the evenings, that&amp;rsquo;s a great place for people to come and ask you questions about your talk, stuff they might not want to share in front of everyone. &amp;nbsp;Note to attendees - if you do see a speaker at a drinks/network/mingle event, feel free to chat to them. &amp;nbsp;We&amp;rsquo;re there for you guys, and we&amp;rsquo;re only people ourselves and like the company. &amp;nbsp;At many events, the speakers know very few people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sydney had an outdoor eating area, which was awesome - if you&amp;rsquo;re going to spend weeks in a conference hall, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get outside for food.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There was a, um, misunderstanding about appropriate dress code for one of the vendors. &amp;nbsp;The conference organisers were on this immediately, and, to their credit, the vendor acted swiftly with no fuss. &amp;nbsp;A great example of how to handle this sort of thing at tech conferences.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having all the travel and accommodation, particularly for this complicated trip, arranged by very capable and approachable people made the speakers&amp;rsquo; lives really easy, and I think that helped us to be more prepared and relaxed for our talks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A speaker&amp;rsquo;s excursion (on a boat!) at the weekend was an amazing way to bond with the other guys.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;I loved YOW, I hope I can go again.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAX London &amp; MongoDB Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__mongodb_tutorial</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__mongodb_tutorial</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous years, JAX London would have been an easy, local conference to go to. This time it took me most of Sunday to get
there, and not because of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://metro.co.uk/2013/10/27/its-ok-to-take-the-morning-off-work-if-storm-hits-michael-fish-says-so-4162862/&#34;&gt;Super Storm&lt;/a&gt;.  Still, that gave me the day to finish off the tutorial I was running there on
Monday morning. Not that I would be so unprofessional as to leave preparing things until the last minute,
oh no&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as in previous years, the main benefit of this conference for me was meeting most of the usual suspects from the London Java
Community. For example, presenting were: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/andy-piper&#34;&gt;Andy Piper&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/barry-cranford&#34;&gt;Barry Cranford&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/james-gough&#34;&gt;Jim
Gough&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/peter-lawrey&#34;&gt;Peter Lawrey&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon
.com/speakers/sandro-mancuso&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/simon-maple&#34;&gt;Simon Maple&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/martijn-verburg&#34;&gt;Martijn Verburg&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/john-oliver&#34;&gt;John
Oliver&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/john-stevenson&#34;&gt;John Stevenson&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon
.com/speakers/richard-warburton&#34;&gt;Richard Warburton&lt;/a&gt;. The Community Night in particular also drew a lot of LJC members (including some
 first-timers) to JAX, and it was a really good &amp;ldquo;networking opportunity&amp;rdquo; (i.e. chance to have free drinks,
 catch up with friends and make new ones). I really enjoyed hanging out with everyone at JAX this year,
 I was tempted to write the names of everyone I spoke to and had fun with because it really made my conference,
 but I think that would make a very boring blog post. But if I spoke to you at JAX, you made my journey from Spain worthwhile,
 thank you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As well as the LJC-types, there were some other really big name speakers too,
 including MongoDB&amp;rsquo;s Chairman &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/dwight-merriman&#34;&gt;Dwight Merriman&lt;/a&gt;. Highlights for me
 were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Sipe&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spockframework.org/&#34;&gt;Spock&lt;/a&gt; talk. I saw this at GeeCON and that&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;/tags/spock/&#34;&gt;I started using
Spock&lt;/a&gt; to test the MongoDB Java driver, but it was great to see it again and pick up some extra tips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ted Neward&amp;rsquo;s talk at the community night about being a CTO at a startup. It was really interesting,
and nice to see a realistic view of the difficulties of that role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Governor&amp;rsquo;s keynote on how Java got its Mojo back. I like seeing facts and figures to back up a viewpoint,
and as you&amp;rsquo;d expect from the founder of an analyst firm, this talk was full of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As James mentioned during his talk, the audience at JAX was, as in previous years, somewhat passive. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why,
 as around 50% of the audience came from outside the UK so we can&amp;rsquo;t even blame English reticence. And in a conference full of
 outspoken LJC-types, it seems an odd thing to have an unresponsive audience. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the venue,
 the main hall in particular seems to lend itself to sitting quietly in the audience and expecting to be entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented four times at JAX, because, well, on home turf one ends up doing more than one expects.
 - Firstly, a tutorial on the new Java driver for MongoDB (more on this later);
 - Secondly, a clinic for novice speakers. This was a lot of fun, and I think it was useful for everyone. I&amp;rsquo;d love to run
 this again (I probably will at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ljcopenconference/&#34;&gt;LJC Open Conference&lt;/a&gt;). The aim
 is to give new speakers confidence, not focus on details like building a slide deck.
 - Thirdly, the third time out for my &amp;ldquo;Design is a Process, not a Document&amp;rdquo; presentation. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively interactive
 presentation, which I don&amp;rsquo;t think worked so well at JAX, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fun presentation to give.
 - Finally, not only did I get roped into being on the panel for &amp;ldquo;How to start a community&amp;rdquo; at the community night, I ended up, somehow,
  moderating it. That was fun, it was the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been a moderator, it&amp;rsquo;s a role I usually avoid as moderators ought to
  limit the amount of talking they do, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound fun to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorial materials are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/mongodb-java-tutorial&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
provided a lot of guidance on how to get started online, but the exercises are there, and the slides which present the concepts and
suggest the order to tackle the tests in. If people use these materials, please feel free to give me feedback on them,
but be nice - they were designed for an in-person tutorial, not an online one. But it is a good way to get a feel for the new
MongoDB Java API (in its current, unfinished, state).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, JAX London - great speakers, and a good conference to meet not only Londoners, but a lot of international people too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RpASMopn-iA/UnjQz9Tss-I/AAAAAAAAL8c/21JMVGxFuT8/s1600/DSC_1075.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RpASMopn-iA/UnjQz9Tss-I/AAAAAAAAL8c/21JMVGxFuT8/s320/DSC_1075.jpg&#34; width=&#34;211&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So, I thought a few months ago that my blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2013/09/javazone.html&#34;&gt;would become more of a travel blog&lt;/a&gt; than a tech blog because of the amount of conferences I was going to. &amp;nbsp;Turned out that I was so busy writing / updating / practicing talks and workshops and, er, travelling, that I never got around to doing retrospectives on the events I&amp;rsquo;d been to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So, JavaOne, again, my third year there. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll always have a fondness for it - because of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com.es/&#34;&gt;Martin Thompson&lt;/a&gt;, it was the first conference I presented at. &amp;nbsp;I know people always start with &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not what it used to be&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;why isn&amp;rsquo;t it in the Moscone?&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;But not having ever been in the good ol&amp;rsquo; pre-Oracle days, I don&amp;rsquo;t have that to compare it to.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I do have the previous two years to compare it to, however. &amp;nbsp;This year, I think the quality of the presentations was much better compared to the previous two years (although I can&amp;rsquo;t accurately speak for last year as I spent the whole time running between my presentations and other LJC presentations). &amp;nbsp;I learnt something in all the talks I went to this year, in particular:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/524f3d38e4b0c4f11ec57602/about&#34;&gt;Designing with Lambda Expressions in Java&lt;/a&gt; - Venkat doesn&amp;rsquo;t simply cover the syntax of lambdas, but how they encourage us to use different design patterns to those we commonly use. Very informative.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/5251c164e4b0a43ac1212459/about&#34;&gt;Lambda: A Peek under the hood&lt;/a&gt; - Brian Goetz goes into detail of how lambdas are actually implemented. &amp;nbsp;Not something an everyday developer needs to know in order to use them, but extremely useful if you want to understand things like their performance, and why they&amp;rsquo;re not simply syntactic sugar. &amp;nbsp;Despite thinking I understood this stuff, I still had to watch this twice (once at JavaOne and once at GOTO Aarhus) before I could say I understood it. &amp;nbsp;Totally worthwhile making the effort.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/524f0463e4b0ab14e307d7bc/about&#34;&gt;Making Java Groovy&lt;/a&gt; - A great, engaging talk about how Groovy and Java can live side by side, and showcasing some of the nice features of Groovy. &amp;nbsp;I found this particularly helpful now we&amp;rsquo;re using Spock and Gradle, and learnt some new tricks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/5250370ee4b0c4f11ec57641/about&#34;&gt;MongoDB for Hibernate/JPA developers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Obviously Justin is my colleague, so I should give him a shout out. &amp;nbsp;But what I like about this talk is that it does what it says on the tin - introduces MongoDB for those of us who are/were used to working with out databases in a particular way.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6LKajHbAm6Y/UnjSZ7_2QlI/AAAAAAAAL8o/8XA5AVvEYP4/s1600/DSC_0626.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6LKajHbAm6Y/UnjSZ7_2QlI/AAAAAAAAL8o/8XA5AVvEYP4/s320/DSC_0626.jpg&#34; width=&#34;211&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I also liked Martijn &amp;amp; Ben&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2013/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=3802&#34;&gt;Lean Startup Ninja&lt;/a&gt; talk, even if they weren&amp;rsquo;t terribly complimentary towards MongoDB. &amp;nbsp;The talk doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be on Parleys yet, but keep an eye out for it - it&amp;rsquo;s a nice, realistic view of the trials and tribulations of running a startup.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These great sessions were really a bonus for me. &amp;nbsp;The main reason to go to JavaOne in my opinion is to meet people - it&amp;rsquo;s west-coast, and I don&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to get to California very often. &amp;nbsp;You see or meet those who are working to advance Java-the-platform and Java-the-language, and there&amp;rsquo;s a big focus on community so you also get to meet as many of the Java User Group leaders as can make it out there. &amp;nbsp;In addition, there&amp;rsquo;s the folks working hard on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://java.net/&#34;&gt;java.net&lt;/a&gt; website and those involved in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jcp.org/en/home/index&#34;&gt;JCP process&lt;/a&gt;, deciding the standards of the language. &amp;nbsp;Although there&amp;rsquo;s some overlap between all these groups, by spending some time with all of them you get to meet a really wide range of people. You get to hear what people are working on, what&amp;rsquo;s coming down the line, and often get a chance to influence that too by giving your opinions (nicely, of course!).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Of course there&amp;rsquo;s the parties too, although I&amp;rsquo;ve been threatened with being removed from the invite list of the Zero Turnaround party next year since I failed to show up this time. &amp;nbsp;My favourite was the JCP party - great food, and amazing views of the city.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2MEmpzgCoGE/UnjTq0XVQlI/AAAAAAAAL8w/hiLFac_YcuQ/s1600/DSC_0924.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2MEmpzgCoGE/UnjTq0XVQlI/AAAAAAAAL8w/hiLFac_YcuQ/s400/DSC_0924.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WVlQ2KcG6xQ/UnjQAnkURoI/AAAAAAAAL8U/G5LjQYrY3Qo/s1600/MongoDB.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WVlQ2KcG6xQ/UnjQAnkURoI/AAAAAAAAL8U/G5LjQYrY3Qo/s400/MongoDB.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some other conference going on at the same time, over in Moscone. Something called Oracle Open World. A few of us snuck over there to take a look at the massive MongoDB stand there (in the heart of Relational-Database-World!). &amp;nbsp;Open World is a scary place filled with people in suits, looking to sell or be sold to. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s also massive. &amp;nbsp;We chatted to our mates there and then ran off to eat burritos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-L5YJHRqiYsM/UnjTtx8lgkI/AAAAAAAAL88/2dZrxdLcvMU/s1600/DSC_0935.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;263&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-L5YJHRqiYsM/UnjTtx8lgkI/AAAAAAAAL88/2dZrxdLcvMU/s400/DSC_0935.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A bunch of us also got a chance to go to the Google offices in San Francisco. We slid on their slide, tried Google Glass, got photos taken in their photo booth, ate their food and drank their drink. &amp;nbsp;I was pleased to see it wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything like The Internship (a film I tried to watch on the plane on the way over and could not finish - I was really disappointed with the enforcement of industry stereotypes, and the portrayal of elitism. &amp;nbsp;But maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just me). They also have amazing views of the bay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CmZqbfcPgd4/UnjhRjjaxaI/AAAAAAAAL9I/WLlZrYDEITQ/s1600/DSC_0704.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;211&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CmZqbfcPgd4/UnjhRjjaxaI/AAAAAAAAL9I/WLlZrYDEITQ/s320/DSC_0704.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;In Summary&lt;/b&gt;, JavaOne is as relevant as it ever was. &amp;nbsp;The themes of this year were definitely Java 8 (lambdas in particular), alternative JVM languages (which now seem to be used enough in mature systems to be viable for more conservative organisations), &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/nashorn/&#34;&gt;JavaScript on the server&lt;/a&gt;, and as always there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of noise around front end and web, although I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure Java has a really nice, easy way to create a web application. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;JavaOne is still the place to go to hear what&amp;rsquo;s in the pipeline, to meet the people working on this pipeline, and to influence the future of Java.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Oh, and I gave a talk:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;290&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/share.html#play/524f26a3e4b0a43ac1212393&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;420&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;lt;br /&amp;amp;gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life on both sides of the interview table</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InfoQ has posted the video of Dan North and I opining on the subject of hiring. &amp;nbsp;Most of the talk is spent on how to be a good interviewer, and touches on how to market your company to prospective hires. &amp;nbsp;We spend less time on how to do well as an interviewee, but in theory if you know what&amp;rsquo;s going through the interviewer&amp;rsquo;s mind, you should be in a much better position to take control of the interview and shine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/job-interview-tips#.UiBS9_WZJyU.blogger&#34;&gt;Hire Education - Making Interviews Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of funny because we talk a lot about hiring at ThoughtWorks (where we both worked, and which has one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/hardest-tech-company-job-interviews-2012-8&#34;&gt;toughest interview processes&lt;/a&gt; in the industry) and LMAX, which learnt a lot off ThoughtWorks and shaped its own process for a smaller company that has different goals. &amp;nbsp;Yet neither of us work at those places now. &amp;nbsp;Still, we share stories from many of the places we&amp;rsquo;ve worked (or chose not to work), and if there&amp;rsquo;s one take-home point, it&amp;rsquo;s that hiring (and being hired) is not a simple thing to do well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne Shanghai</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_shanghai</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_shanghai</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Zw5OLhNC2_0/UfkleToCp7I/AAAAAAAALqs/pP-pjChpfUg/s1600/DSC_0250.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Zw5OLhNC2_0/UfkleToCp7I/AAAAAAAALqs/pP-pjChpfUg/s400/DSC_0250.jpg&#34; width=&#34;267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;I was expecting this&amp;hellip;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;So, I was in China last week. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s not really what I expected, but then my knowledge of China comes almost entirely from visiting various Chinatowns and watching martial arts movies, so I guess I wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that well prepared for a modern Asian city like Shanghai.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-LLo9NO2T6ug/Ufkc1_QLrDI/AAAAAAAALoI/hDFjCD1qmf4/s1600/DSC_0100.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;424&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-LLo9NO2T6ug/Ufkc1_QLrDI/AAAAAAAALoI/hDFjCD1qmf4/s640/DSC_0100.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;and found this instead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The city is, in my opinion, clean, modern, and attractive. &amp;nbsp;I was surprised by American-looking early skyscrapers, and really surprised that the city overall felt more European than American - with Marks &amp;amp; Spencer, Tesco, Carrefour, H &amp;amp; M, Zara, Costa Coffee, as well as the inevitable McDonalds, KFC and Pizza Hut.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-QhI7Bb7KFpA/Ufkc2Y6SxDI/AAAAAAAALoU/mwPo9VG81Vc/s1600/DSC_0116.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;428&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-QhI7Bb7KFpA/Ufkc2Y6SxDI/AAAAAAAALoU/mwPo9VG81Vc/s640/DSC_0116.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Some of the architecture reminded me more of New York than Europe or Asia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I felt like they had the option to take the best of all worlds - the modern, high tech and sometimes downright weird influence of Japan; a care for heritage from Europe; the consumer choice of the US; and food from all over China and the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EaMzViVxXg8/Ufkc6YcbAQI/AAAAAAAALqA/bVpTqW2HJWc/s1600/DSC_0555.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;428&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EaMzViVxXg8/Ufkc6YcbAQI/AAAAAAAALqA/bVpTqW2HJWc/s640/DSC_0555.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;OK, I didn&amp;rsquo;t eat here, but I did love the food in Shanghai&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The food was awesome and, by my London-standards, very reasonably priced. &amp;nbsp;Our hotel was amazing, and also a good price for such luxury (although it was in the arse end of nowhere, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter when taxi journeys to the centre of Shanghai were around £3.00). &amp;nbsp;Road users were mental (although there are probably many worse places I haven&amp;rsquo;t visited them yet) and we got into the habit of not looking out of the cab windows when we travelled.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z-mEw4eDm9k/Ufkh1_15luI/AAAAAAAALqM/jQ_tAAj1y-Q/s1600/DSC_0234.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z-mEw4eDm9k/Ufkh1_15luI/AAAAAAAALqM/jQ_tAAj1y-Q/s640/DSC_0234.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Apparently road accidents kill 300 people a day in China.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;I did miss Twitter and Facebook while I was out there, and the WiFi availability was limited. &amp;nbsp;Also, maybe I&amp;rsquo;m paranoid, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how much to trust the WiFi. &amp;nbsp;But I found myself quite pleased to be separated from the interwebs for a bit - it was peaceful and relaxing. &amp;nbsp;I even did more work than I expected, probably because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t replying to e-mails all the time or thinking of what to tweet next.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oqapZA6WGUI/Ufkc5L2G7hI/AAAAAAAALpg/blm4iEKfz8I/s1600/DSC_0291.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oqapZA6WGUI/Ufkc5L2G7hI/AAAAAAAALpg/blm4iEKfz8I/s640/DSC_0291.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The conference itself was a weird mix of the familiar with the massively unfamiliar - familiar, because it &lt;i&gt;felt&lt;/i&gt; like a JavaOne - the branding, the badges, the signage. &amp;nbsp;Unfamiliar because I don&amp;rsquo;t speak Chinese - most of the signs and documentation were in Chinese, and not all the stewards spoke English. &amp;nbsp;The attendees in particular were not expected to speak English (which is totally understandable of course! Conferences should cater for the local population), which made it more difficult to feel like a part of the event. &amp;nbsp;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before that the more I come to these events, the less I feel like an outsider as one of the rare women. &amp;nbsp;But as a blonde-haired European woman I did feel a little&amp;hellip; conspicuous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oOKZpQA9aiM/Ufkc24I2QvI/AAAAAAAALoo/KDA5LT4htD8/s1600/DSC_0217.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;428&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oOKZpQA9aiM/Ufkc24I2QvI/AAAAAAAALoo/KDA5LT4htD8/s640/DSC_0217.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;It was an Oracle conference. &amp;nbsp;In case you&amp;rsquo;re not sure.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Oracle probably like the fact that the event is small enough that Open World and JavaOne can be in the same place at the same time, but to me it feels a bit odd. &amp;nbsp;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t easily find the content that was applicable to me as a Java developer, and I really don&amp;rsquo;t see much crossover between the two conferences - I can&amp;rsquo;t see what I, as a developer, would get out of &amp;ldquo;How to use Oracle blah blah more effectively&amp;rdquo;.  And I can&amp;rsquo;t see the suited business types enjoying &amp;ldquo;Effective Scala&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s less obvious than at the SF conference(s), but there&amp;rsquo;s a very distinct difference between the JavaOne attendees (emphasis on the casual part of business casual) and the Oracle people (do they sleep in their suits?).  I didn&amp;rsquo;t envy the latter at all - wearing a full suit and tie in 40°C heat and humidity you could drown in must be extremely uncomfortable.&amp;nbsp;Speaking of clothes, all the women are dressed in summery, pretty clothes (except the business-suited Oracle types), and looked like normal human beings, and the geek guys were wearing less badges of geekness (geek t-shirts, jeans etc).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This did seem to be a great conference to get people from all over Asia and even the antipodes together.  There was buzz in the air, an excitement to be learning stuff and meeting people. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s the (relatively) small size of the conference, its youth or its geography, or maybe simply me projecting my excitement at being in a place I&amp;rsquo;d never been to before, but there was less cynicism than in the western conferences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HnWFwFqbyUs/Ufkc3GqPjCI/AAAAAAAALos/zOoIsSqSzCs/s1600/DSC_0221.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HnWFwFqbyUs/Ufkc3GqPjCI/AAAAAAAALos/zOoIsSqSzCs/s640/DSC_0221.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Awesome to see the LJC get a shout out in China!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;In terms of presenting, this was an entirely new experience for me. &amp;nbsp;The slides had all been translated into Chinese&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve already mentioned I don&amp;rsquo;t speak, so this meant I had to have my laptop out with my English notes on, as well as the slides on the main screen. &amp;nbsp;I had two remotes, one in each hand, and I advanced both sets of slides at the same time. The fact that the slide on the screen was also on a monitor in front of me made it relatively easy to make sure I had both in sync, but it did require a bit of extra cognitive power. &amp;nbsp;I felt lucky that most of my slides are practically content-less - if my presentations followed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://presentationpatterns.com/glossary/#bullet-riddledcorpse&#34;&gt;Bullet-Riddled Corpse pattern&lt;/a&gt; a) the poor translator would have had to work harder and b) it would have been more difficult to work out which slide I was on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RGTON8Wogt0/UfkjPmpqg5I/AAAAAAAALqc/p8bTKu5qiRg/s1600/2013-07-23+16.28.37.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RGTON8Wogt0/UfkjPmpqg5I/AAAAAAAALqc/p8bTKu5qiRg/s640/2013-07-23+16.28.37.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Half of my massive audience&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;In addition, my presentation was being interpreted in real time as I spoke. &amp;nbsp;I was worried about the interpreter - I know I speak too fast, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if Chinese is one of those languages where it takes more words to say the same thing&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. &amp;nbsp;So I needed to make sure I slowed down, spoke clearly and coherently, and left longer pauses. &amp;nbsp;These are things you should do as a presenter anyway, but it always feels a little unnatural. &amp;nbsp;And in fact the more you present, the easier it is to forget this, especially if you get good feedback on your talks.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;To deal with both these different things (Chinese slides and real time interpretation), I had to be prepared earlier than normal and I practiced more than normal. &amp;nbsp;I wanted to get the timing right so I would be comfortable slowing down. &amp;nbsp;I wanted it to be 40 minutes (in a 60 minute slot) to give me 10 mins for questions and 10 mins buffer for allowing me to slow down and/or cope with any disasters. &amp;nbsp;I needed to run through with the Chinese slides so there weren&amp;rsquo;t any nasty surprises.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In the end, I thought it went very well. &amp;nbsp;The preparation made me feel much more comfortable and confident. &amp;nbsp;Slowing down had an additional benefit - not everyone opted for the headphones &amp;amp; interpreter, so me not speaking at 100 miles an hour gave them a fighting chance of following along. &amp;nbsp;The audience seemed very reluctant to ask questions in public, so I skipped my usual audience-participation bit, but the fact that I hit 40 minutes exactly gave people loads of time to come up to me afterwards and ask me questions, and I did have quite a big line of people as I was packing up. I think this is a Good Thing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Fortunately (for me) the session was not recorded in any form, so you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see whether it really was any good or not. &amp;nbsp;But here are the slides, in case you speak Chinese (sadly my Keynote to Powerpoint conversion didn&amp;rsquo;t quite work, so some of the code falls off the bottom).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/24790295&#34; width=&#34;476&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Note that my caveats are in Chinese, but the caveats are that the new API for the MongoDB Java driver will almost definitely NOT look like that, it&amp;rsquo;s just indicative of the direction we were looking in when I wrote that presentation.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although I was more nervous about this session than recent sessions, I&amp;rsquo;m really pleased I did it. &amp;nbsp;I highly recommend this to other speakers as a way to force you out of your routine and to think about your presentation style (something we probably all stress about anyway, but this forces you to look carefully at it).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And Shanghai overall&amp;hellip; as you can probably gather from the start of this blog, I liked it a lot. &amp;nbsp;I had a nice, mostly relaxing, fun time there. &amp;nbsp;I loved the modern-ness of it, like the ridiculously fast MagLev that takes a mere 7 minutes to travel the 30km to the airport.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N4uxMHHBqP8/Ufj39c6HFlI/AAAAAAAALnk/LkqJmrUtQYM/s1600/MagLevSpeed.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N4uxMHHBqP8/Ufj39c6HFlI/AAAAAAAALnk/LkqJmrUtQYM/s320/MagLevSpeed.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The Shanghai MagLev is &amp;ldquo;the world&amp;rsquo;s fastest train in regular commercial service&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I liked the alienness, after countless European and American cities. &amp;nbsp;I did not like not being able to speak the language, or the fact that taxi drivers don&amp;rsquo;t want to take you to the Expo area where our hotel was. &amp;nbsp;I liked the many touches of familiarity and the atmosphere. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;d definitely go back.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WCwgvIYVSPc/Ufk0x8cl66I/AAAAAAAALq8/56LFQqYJwfg/s1600/DSC_0227.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WCwgvIYVSPc/Ufk0x8cl66I/AAAAAAAALq8/56LFQqYJwfg/s640/DSC_0227.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Pollution makes awesome sunsets&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zKRXrTupRYE/Ufk0x683cTI/AAAAAAAALrA/QOdN4Mu0rXQ/s1600/DSC_0064.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;428&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zKRXrTupRYE/Ufk0x683cTI/AAAAAAAALrA/QOdN4Mu0rXQ/s640/DSC_0064.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s whetted my appetite for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt; so I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to San Francisco in September. See you there?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&amp;nbsp;&lt;/sup&gt;I was surprised to hear everyone talking about &amp;ldquo;Chinese&amp;rdquo; when even in my ignorance I know there are many types of Chinese language, but doing my research I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt there is a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Chinese&#34;&gt;Standard Chinese&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Which makes sense. &amp;nbsp;You learn something new every day&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&amp;nbsp;&lt;/sup&gt;Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trisha&#39;s World Tour 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/trishas_world_tour_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/trishas_world_tour_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick update on my scheduled events this year. &amp;nbsp;Please feel free to suggest your MUG or JUG or other tech group as somewhere for me to visit on this Grand World Tour if I&amp;rsquo;m in your city.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;17-21st June - In New York - woohoo! &amp;nbsp;Getting to know &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/evanchooly&#34;&gt;Justin Lee&lt;/a&gt;, the newest member of the Java team, doing some pair&amp;nbsp;programming&amp;nbsp;(hopefully) and meeting people at the MongoDB Masters&amp;rsquo; Summit on Thursday.&lt;br /&gt;24th June - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stacresearch.com/spring2013LON&#34;&gt;STAC Summit&lt;/a&gt;, London - I&amp;rsquo;m not presenting, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be there &amp;ldquo;networking&amp;rdquo; (a.k.a. drinking)&lt;br /&gt;27th June - &lt;a href=&#34;http://thettn.tv/headlines/trisha-gee-27th-june-2013-video.aspx#.UYzlwv35XAE.blogger&#34;&gt;Technology Transformation Network&lt;/a&gt;, London. &amp;nbsp;Tiny bit concerned about this event now (don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone) because I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to run break out sessions on how to approach design, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can do this alone&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;1-5th July - In Dublin, hoping to talk to a MUG or JUG while I&amp;rsquo;m there. &amp;nbsp;Invite me!&lt;br /&gt;22-25th July - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/events/apac/cn/en/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne Shanghai&lt;/a&gt; (CON1148). I&amp;rsquo;ve never been east of Europe before, very exciting.&lt;br /&gt;August - Going to be in Seville (Spain), and a weekend in Madrid.&lt;br /&gt;11-12th Sept - &lt;a href=&#34;http://jz13.java.no/&#34;&gt;JavaZone&lt;/a&gt;, Oslo, hopefully.&lt;br /&gt;16-20th Sept - Hopefully working from the Palo Alto office, so if there&amp;rsquo;re are any events in Silicon Valley or San Francisco that week, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;22-26 Sept - &lt;a href=&#34;http://javafx.steveonjava.com/congrats-to-the-1st-javaone-invitees/&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt;, San Francisco.&lt;br /&gt;30th Sept - 2nd Oct - &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/aarhus-2013/presentation/Career%20Advice%20for%20Programmers&#34;&gt;GOTO Aarhus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;17-18th Oct - &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2013/speakers/&#34;&gt;GOTO Berlin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;28-30th Oct - &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/&#34;&gt;JAX London&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;December - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yowconference.com.au/index.html&#34;&gt;YOW Melbourne, Brisbane, Sydney&lt;/a&gt; - Australia.  I&amp;rsquo;ve never been to Oz, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait!&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s that. &amp;nbsp;The only two other events I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating this year are Devoxx and the London Java Community Open Conference. &amp;nbsp;I think I&amp;rsquo;m maxed out.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Summary of GeeCON, Krakow</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_summary_of_geecon_krakow</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_summary_of_geecon_krakow</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in Krakow, Poland for &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.geecon.org/&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Which was excellent! &amp;nbsp;I find it really
interesting that conferences all have their own personalities, that they are not all the same.
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QGi20Kv1QL0/UZyWDc9hzVI/AAAAAAAALj0/ZlJ-1o1rLBk/s1600/2013-05-18+19.35.58.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QGi20Kv1QL0/UZyWDc9hzVI/AAAAAAAALj0/ZlJ-1o1rLBk/s320/2013-05-18+19.35.58.jpg&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
GeeCON had its own distinct personality. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re a Java/JVM person based in Poland, I would highly recommend it - more than 90%
of the attendees were Polish (probably the remainder were largely speakers) so this conference is very much for you. &amp;nbsp;The quality
of the speakers was really good too, I learnt a lot off many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a speaker&amp;rsquo;s point of view, there were some cultural things which took a bit of getting used to. One of the good things was that the
audience was very keen on asking questions, they were much more interactive than a typical London audience (for example). However,
I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to quite short questions, and I found that the audience liked to give a lot of detail in their questions and frequently
ask more than one at once - this meant that all the speakers really needed to allocate a lot more time for Q &amp;amp; A than expected. One
of the other things I found unusual was the number of people who would walk in and out of the room during sessions - this wasn&amp;rsquo;t just
everyone fleeing my session (I hope!), I saw it happen in all the talks, even the keynotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;My stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day I was on a panel about diversity in IT, which was basically about women programmers (again). It was a good panel to be
on, actually, because there were a range of opinions, including downright disagreement, which made for a more interesting discussion.
Sadly it left the audience with too little time to contribute though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day I was presenting &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean, backwards compatibility?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;,
which elicited a lot of responses from the audience. &amp;nbsp;I think I got the balance right between providing food for thought for any
Java programmer, and enough of a look into what we&amp;rsquo;re considering for the new MongoDB Java driver,
that it felt like I satisfied the two audiences - those who are interested in MongoDB with Java,
and those who&amp;hellip; aren&amp;rsquo;t (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t my experience as a speaker which really made GeeCON for me. &amp;nbsp;For the first time in ages I felt like I learnt
something as an attendee. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that&amp;rsquo;s because a) I only had one presentation to prepare so I had time for a lot of
sessions b) we have some specific problems we&amp;rsquo;re trying to solve on our code right now that we&amp;rsquo;re looking for answers to or c) the
conference inspired it, but I came out of a lot of sessions excited about things to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first take-away point is to try &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/spock/&#34;&gt;Spock&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told for ages that I need to give it a
 go, but the session really sold it to me. &amp;nbsp;It seems to have features that will solve specific things we&amp;rsquo;re looking at right now,
 including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplifying mocking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annotating tests with properties (e.g. &lt;code&gt;@Slow&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running the same test with different sets of data, instead of having to copy-paste the test a bunch of times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting of failures, particularly power assert and &lt;code&gt;@Unroll&lt;/code&gt;, make diagnosing failures much simpler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using BDD terms as keywords (given/when/then) means the tests really do document themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m totally sold on it. &amp;nbsp;I was concerned, because we&amp;rsquo;re writing an open source Java library and I want the unit/integration tests
to be understandable to Java developers, and I worried that adding Groovy tests might make the learning curve steeper. &amp;nbsp;But I think
it&amp;rsquo;s an idea worth playing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Asynchronous IO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one of the things we&amp;rsquo;re working on is trying to figure out the best way to provide an async Java driver. &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.geecon
.org/speakers/erik-onnen&#34;&gt;Erik Onnen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s talk around performance network programming on the JVM was really interesting. &amp;nbsp;Most
usefully, it compared sync to async communication, outlining the pros and cons, and how you can do it on the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Build the right thing before you build the thing right&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first keynote was about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pretotyping.org/&#34;&gt;Pretotyping&lt;/a&gt; - Patrick Copeland from Google was talking
about ideas and innovators, and blowing away the myth that all it takes to make money is a single great idea. He highlighted how
really great ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily successes, and some ideas that sound great don&amp;rsquo;t feel right in practice. Pretotyping is a
way to test things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pgXRSN4oq0k/UZyVTqpUoFI/AAAAAAAALjk/1evlD4F4nYY/s1600/2013-05-15+10.30.13.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right;
margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pgXRSN4oq0k/UZyVTqpUoFI/AAAAAAAALjk/1evlD4F4nYY/s320/2013-05-15+10.30.13.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Would you use it / do it?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How would you interact with it?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is it socially acceptable to use it in the
circumstances?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s very low tech, very low effort (think post-its and note pads, not HTML prototypes) it facilitates fast failure (therefore
reducing the cost).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session was videoed, so hopefully it will be available to see. If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of An Idea, I highly recommend this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Many users = anthropology, not user experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/&#34;&gt;Joel Spolksy&lt;/a&gt;, the man who inspired me to start this very blog (well,
earlier incarnations of it) talked about the experiences of growing stack exchange. This was interesting because it was not about
the technology, but about subtle things you can do to influence user&amp;rsquo;s behaviour - for example, reputation rewards &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; behaviour,
and a better reputation means you are trusted to do more on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was another inspiring talk if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in creating a product or company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-P-ejmRc3bsg/UZyUtEyArWI/AAAAAAAALjc/qP2tXp-nZkY/s1600/2013-05-18+20.09.07.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em;
margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-P-ejmRc3bsg/UZyUtEyArWI/AAAAAAAALjc/qP2tXp-nZkY/s400/2013-05-18+20.09.07.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I also met a lot of really interesting people who gave me a lot to think about. I&amp;rsquo;ve come back more motivated than ever to work on my various projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Krakow is beautiful, and GeeCON is a good learning experience. &amp;nbsp;Go next year if you can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 is looking a lot busier than I planned...</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/2013_is_looking_a_lot_busier_than_i_planned</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/2013_is_looking_a_lot_busier_than_i_planned</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, despite promising myself that I would only do one event a month for the rest of this year, looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a bit busier than that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what I&amp;rsquo;m up to (or, even better, hoping to see me talk or meet me), here are my confirmed engagements:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;15-17 May - &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.geecon.org/conference-day-two&#34;&gt;GeeCon&lt;/a&gt;, Poland&lt;br /&gt;18-20 June - &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/amsterdam-2013/presentation/A%20Fluent%20API%20for%20Java%20and%20MongoDB&#34;&gt;GOTO Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; - whole day tutorial on the new (unfinished) MongoDB Java driver.&lt;br /&gt;24th June - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stacresearch.com/spring2013LON&#34;&gt;STAC Summit&lt;/a&gt;, London - something MongoDB-shaped (i.e. not Java-specific)&lt;br /&gt;27th June - &lt;a href=&#34;http://thettn.tv/headlines/trisha-gee-27th-june-2013-video.aspx#.UYzlwv35XAE.blogger&#34;&gt;Technology Transformation Network&lt;/a&gt;, London&lt;br /&gt;1-5th July - In Dublin, hoping to talk to a MUG or JUG while I&amp;rsquo;m there.&lt;br /&gt;22-25th July - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/events/apac/cn/en/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne Shanghai&lt;/a&gt; (CON1148). So excited to go to China!&lt;br /&gt;August - Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going to be in Spain a couple of times (Madrid/Seville).&lt;br /&gt;11-12th Sept - Love to go to JavaZone, Oslo. &amp;nbsp;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;br /&gt;22-26 Sept - &lt;a href=&#34;http://javafx.steveonjava.com/congrats-to-the-1st-javaone-invitees/&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt;, San Francisco.&lt;br /&gt;30th Sept - 2nd Oct - &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/aarhus-2013/presentation/Career%20Advice%20for%20Programmers&#34;&gt;GOTO Aarhus&lt;/a&gt; - very pleased I can make it this year!&lt;br /&gt;17-18th Oct - &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2013/speakers/&#34;&gt;GOTO Berlin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;28-30th Oct - &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/&#34;&gt;JAX London&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;December - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yowconference.com.au/index.html&#34;&gt;YOW Melbourne, Brisbane, Sydney&lt;/a&gt; - Australia. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve never been to Oz, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve either clicked through those, or you&amp;rsquo;ve already been stalking my talks, you&amp;rsquo;ll see I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually made up my mind what to call this year&amp;rsquo;s main presentation:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;What do you mean, Backwards Compatibility?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Design is a process, not an artefact&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Design is a process, not a document&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is mostly because when I signed up for some of these conferences, I thought I was going to be talking about how hard it was to write backwardly-compatible libraries (which it is). &amp;nbsp;But when I wrote the presentation, it turned out to be about software design. &amp;nbsp;And then I found out artefact/artifact can be spelt two ways, ho hum.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure yet if this will actually be the same (but evolving) talk under two different guises, or if they are two subtly different talks. &amp;nbsp;I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see what I end up writing the week before I&amp;rsquo;m due to present &amp;ldquo;Design is a process, not a document&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx UK 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_uk_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_uk_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was the first Devoxx UK, bringing the brand from Belgium and, more recently, France. And I think it was a HUGE success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, disclaimers first - I was on the programme committee, so I might say that the whole thing was awesome. Although in all
honesty, even being slightly involved in the organisation of a conference is a lot of work, and you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the back of it
(and I didn&amp;rsquo;t do half as much as some people). Note to self - never speak at a conference you&amp;rsquo;re on the programme committee for,
it&amp;rsquo;s too much work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=90440057274722849&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/download/attachments/6392384/DevoxxUK-2013.jpg?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1364404914960&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/download/attachments/6392384/DevoxxUK-2013.jpg?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1364404914960&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a speaker and attendee though, Devoxx was really brilliant - great speakers, interesting content, awesome friendly atmosphere,
good venue, parties with free drink and good opportunities to speak to people. There were downsides: limited coffee availability,
no free croissants, um&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m really struggling to think of anything else, and none of those are show-stoppers (especially when the
venue is in Islington, so you can step outside and get whatever you want).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All throughout the run up to the conference we
kept hearing it was a conference &amp;ldquo;for developers, by developers&amp;rdquo; until I was nearly sick of it. But it was a mantra that kept us
on track when we were deciding on content, and it really came through on the two days of the conference. Pretty much everyone on
stage was, or had been, a developer, the talks were a good balance between &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; stuff for our day jobs and &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; stuff for
techies &amp;lt;insert joke about some being &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;. The future track excited us with things like like hacking
on the Raspberry Pi, and the rest of the conference had a good mix of Java SE, EE, methodology and Other Stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the highlights were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Kevlin+Henney&#34;&gt;Kevlin Henney&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s keynote, reminding us that Developers Are Human. Who knew?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Sandro+Mancuso&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s walkthrough of OO principals,
and how they apply to us in our actual day jobs. Sandro did a good job of taking quite a dry topic,
that many of us dozed through at university, and showing us why we already use these principals and how understanding them
will make us better programmers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Mazz+Mosley&#34;&gt;Mazz Mosley&lt;/a&gt; had an entertaining talk about the Dark Side of Agile,
walking us through the agile practices in The Government and highlighting many of the unanswered questions that teams have after
switching to agile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Colin+Vipurs&#34;&gt;Colin Vipurs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s talked about Test Driven Development from the trenches -
he managed to give a good intro for those who might not have done it in practice, but for those who may have been doing it for a while,
this a) was a good reminder of good practice and b) gave a good insight into why we do it. On top of that,
he had solid advice on how to write better tests, that we could all take home with us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Martin Thompson&lt;/a&gt; gave the talk I was attempting to give at JAX London last
year - what is performance and how do we achieve high performance in Java? Where I failed,
Martin really rocked it.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving that to the professionals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be rude of me not to mention this point - what a diverse conference! We had developers of all shapes and sizes,
from the suits to the mohawks, of all colours, and (by technical conference standards) lots of women. Watch the video below and I think
you can see it. I was so proud to have been a part of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;and meeting everyone. What an awesome conference for networking! Of course, there was a large number of London Java
Community people there (speaking, volunteering, and attending), and quite a few familiar faces from Devoxx Antwerp - it was brilliant to
see them in London. But I was also very pleased to run into people I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with in the past, some I haven&amp;rsquo;t see for ages,
and some I still see regularly. And I met dozens of new, interesting people - you guys really made the conference for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was giving my new presentation,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;What Do You Mean, Backwards Compatibility?&lt;/a&gt;. In this talk I share
some of the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had in helping to develop the new MongoDB Java driver. This is not really a MongoDB talk,
although there are some examples from the new driver, it&amp;rsquo;s more a talk about design, and how we as developers make design decisions
every day, something I don&amp;rsquo;t think we recognise very much. I am hoping to give this presentation a number of times this year,
so if you missed it there will be another opportunity to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, my take-away theme from a conference is probably influenced by the sessions I attended,
so is as much a function of what I think is important right now as it is an indication of what themes are emerging in the industry. But
I came away from Devoxx feeling like there&amp;rsquo;s a desire to focus on the basics - the OO principals that have been around for years; the
good design practices that have been written about many times; and, most of all, a reminder that developers have a difficult job - we
don&amp;rsquo;t simply turn requirements into code, we are constantly doing tricky stuff like system design,
and even trickier stuff like working with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved Devoxx UK, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alone in feeling a bit empty when it was all over. To re-live a tiny amount of the event,
or get a good feel of what it was like, watch this video by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/62905094&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/62905094&#34;&gt;Devoxx UK 2013 - Long mellow version&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Devoxx events, the talks will be available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/#home&#34;&gt;Parleys&lt;/a&gt;. If you watch nothing else, watch Kevlin&amp;rsquo;s keynote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
