<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jetbrains on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/jetbrains/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jetbrains on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/jetbrains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being a Developer Advocate at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandatory initial exclamation about how little I have blogged here lately.  Over a year without
updates, oh dear!  But a) I have been blogging quite a lot for the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/author/trishagee/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/upsource/author/trishagee/&#34;&gt;Upsource&lt;/a&gt; blogs, and b) I had another
baby, which kept me quite busy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on that topic (more or less) I get a lot of questions about my job: what&amp;rsquo;s involved in the
job, what&amp;rsquo;s it like working for JetBrains, what does a Developer Advocate do, what&amp;rsquo;s it like
working remotely etc etc.  Given I also rather generously&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; recently offered to answer
people&amp;rsquo;s questions about my job, I thought the most scalable way was to write-once-read-many,
i.e. write it in a single blog post for everyone to read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Adventures</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/new_year_new_adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/new_year_new_adventures/</guid>
      <description>Just over two years ago, I embarked upon a journey as a developer / evangelist for a company who was then called 10gen (who got fed up of saying &amp;ldquo;the MongoDB people&amp;rdquo;, and transformed into MongoDB Inc). My goals for this role were: to learn what it was like working for a company that produced a technology product; to discover what impact working in an open source fashion has; and to level up my advocacy skills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
