<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Drafts on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/drafts/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/drafts/how_to_write_a_cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/drafts/how_to_write_a_cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title
It needs a compelling (and ideally, short) title. Conference attendees will likely glance at the timetable and not necessarily read all
the abstracts - have keywords in the title that will grab the attention. Maybe indicate the level required.  Good examples are things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scala for Java Developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intro to [Technology X]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Technology X]: Beyond the Basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How [Company Y] scaled to [some insane metric]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Martijn&amp;rsquo;s current talk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 million transactions a second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AngularJS, Java, Groovy, MongoDB working together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Needs to explain:
 - Who the talk is aimed at
 - Vaguely what it&amp;rsquo;s going to cover&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each conference has a different set of fields to fill in for the talk submissions.  For some, it all has to be in the abstract,
for others, they&amp;rsquo;ll ask for a behind-the-scenes look at the talk, or a structure of how you&amp;rsquo;re going to present it.  For your talk,
whether you&amp;rsquo;ve written it yet or not, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is it aimed at?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will they learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which buzz words will grab attention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What story will you tell?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past performance
 - Get videoed. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not fantastic, you&amp;rsquo;re miles ahead of an unknown already
 - Get a named event on your CV. Pair if necessary.
 - have a blog if you don&amp;rsquo;t have videos
 - LinkedIn
 - Twitter
 - Be linked to A Name: a company, a person, a conference, a user group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/drafts/more_female_speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/drafts/more_female_speakers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month at Devoxx I was in a session discussing what we can do to encourage more diversity in our speakers (specifically,
although not limited to, increasing the number of women speakers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to outline the things I remember being discussed, although as usual we did not find the answer to the problem,
only identify some issues and explore some options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Firstly, what stops people from stepping up to speak?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to say&lt;/strong&gt;
This is the very first thing any developer says when you ask them why they haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about presenting at conferences or user groups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I be role model?&lt;/strong&gt;
 - Token
 - Don&amp;rsquo;t want to represent all women, what if I fuck up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I can&amp;rsquo;t answer the questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###What can conference organisers do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specifically invite the people you want presenting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure your women presenters early.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Recognise that there are relatively few women presenters on &amp;ldquo;the circuit&amp;rdquo;, and understand that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; wants them to speak at their
conference. This rare breed, the female technical presenter, gets booked up &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt; in advance.  They&amp;rsquo;re probably as in-demand as your
keynote speakers, and can probably devote less time to appearing at conferences than those who have made it to keynote-standard (I&amp;rsquo;m
making a sweeping generalisation that your techy women have day-jobs as developers and your keynote speakers are either professional
presenters or at least can argue presenting as a critical part of their job).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you have a limited resource (experienced women presenters) that&amp;rsquo;s in high demand. You need to reach out directly to them,
invite them, and secure them well in advance of your conference.  Many big conferences, for example JavaOne and QCon,
will invite speakers six months in advance. If you give women speakers a month&amp;rsquo;s notice before your conference or event,
they simply are not going to have the space in their schedule at that late notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Showcase your diversity on your website&lt;/strong&gt;
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already heard of microagressions, go and read what that means before you get any further.  There&amp;rsquo;s a very simple thing you
need to do with your website, whether you&amp;rsquo;ve opened for CFP or you&amp;rsquo;re trying to get attendees to register - make sure the photos on your
website show the type of diversity you want to encourage.  Only yesterday I was looking at the website of a big conference,
who I know for a fact are working &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard to ensure diversity, not just with gender but race, age,
and where possible in less physically obvious dimentions. The conference is many months off, so the only photo they have on the website
is a background photo of the exhibition hall from some previous year, crammed full of attendees - white, male attendees,
as far as it&amp;rsquo;s possible to tell.  It&amp;rsquo;s extremely subtle. You might not even notice, as the photo is behind the headers and text of the
site. But I noticed. And you can be sure the sub-concious of every person who went to the website to either submit a proprosal for a
talk, or is considering asking their employer to pay for the registration, also noticed.  Not the concious mind,
because that would be able to shrug it off.  But the subconcious of a non-white and/or non-male person notices and plants the subtle seed
of &amp;ldquo;this conference is not for me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, conference and event organisers - if you want more women applying to speak at your conference,
show more women on your website.  If you want a more diverse audience, show more diverse faces.  If you&amp;rsquo;ve invited your women presenters
early and secured them early, show their photos on the site - this sends a strong message to other women that their talk proposals will be
taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run warm up nights to try out new speakers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be so damn picky&lt;/strong&gt;
 - New speakers need to be encouraged
 - Existing speakers might not have the luxury of creating new content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leave space for new speakers&lt;/strong&gt;
 - &amp;hellip;and don&amp;rsquo;t just have 7 slots for a pro speaker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look at your swag&lt;/strong&gt;
Not just guys t-shirts.  Cupcakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give feedback&lt;/strong&gt;
You can&amp;rsquo;t tell every individual why they were rejected, but you could look at all the rejected submissions and give broad indications of
the type of CfPs that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be specific about what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a beginner&amp;rsquo;s track (not just for the speakers, for the content)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What other things can we try?
&lt;strong&gt;User groups can grow talent&lt;/strong&gt;
 - Practice writing CFPs
 - Help each other
 - Presentation skills
 - Lightning talks, book club, fishbowl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women&amp;rsquo;s user groups are instrumental&lt;/strong&gt;
 - Devoxx France, more women speakers at Devoxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Advice for budding speakers
 - Just Do It
 - The more you do it, the more comfortable you&amp;rsquo;ll be
 - If you&amp;rsquo;re a speaker, imposter syndrome is better
 - Everyone&amp;rsquo;s afraid, it&amp;rsquo;s not just you
 - Every developer wants to learn
 - The audience is on your side
 - Start Small (user groups)
 - Be technical. But you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be super smart
 - Bootstrapping
 - Pair
 - Ask for mentors
 - Ask for feedback
 - &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; is perfectly acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
