<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opinion on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in opinion on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developers want to be heard</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/developers_want_to_be_heard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/developers_want_to_be_heard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaadvent.com/2014/12/developers-want-to-be-heard.html&#34;&gt;piece for the Java Advent Blog&lt;/a&gt;,
about how developers aren&amp;rsquo;t just communing with the computer, they also need to feel listened to by real human beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaadvent.com/2014/12/developers-want-to-be-heard.html&#34;&gt;Read it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overheard: Agile truths</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/overheard_agile_truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/overheard_agile_truths/</guid>
      <description>After attending a number of conferences and events, and performing numerous interviews, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to hear the same things again and again. Since Dan North challenged all my assumptions at QCon, I&amp;rsquo;m reluctant to outright ridicule them, but I will put forward my personal opinion.
Note: these are things I have heard from multiple sources, so with any luck I am not breaking the sanctity of the confessional interview.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never pair programmed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve frequently worked with a partner on critical production problems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2011: Roundup</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup/</guid>
      <description>Having been back in London for a few days I&amp;rsquo;ve had some time to digest the madness that was last week.
My lasting impression of JavaOne is almost entirely positive. Granted, it was my first major conference, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just not jaded yet. But let me tell you what I loved about it (yes, I did cover some of these in my last post):
First and foremost, the people. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember meeting a single grumpy person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On How Not To Target Girl Geeks</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/on_how_not_to_target_girl_geeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/on_how_not_to_target_girl_geeks/</guid>
      <description>(First, let me say this post contains opinion, stereotyping and sweeping generalisations. But that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the point. Also I don&amp;rsquo;t pretend for one moment to speak for all girl programmers, I can only speak for myself)
When I first started this blog, I wanted to just post &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; technical information. I wanted to prove that there are girls out there doing &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; programming.
I specifically didn&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about my gender.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
