<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Opinion on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/opinion/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overheard: Agile truths</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/overheard_agile_truths</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/overheard_agile_truths</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After attending a number of conferences and events, and performing numerous interviews, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to hear the same things again and again. &amp;nbsp;Since &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/tastapod&#34;&gt;Dan North&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://qconlondon.com/london-2012/presentation/Decisions,%20decisions&#34;&gt;challenged all my assumptions at QCon&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m reluctant to outright ridicule them, but I will put forward my personal opinion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Note: these are things I have heard from multiple sources, so with any luck I am not breaking the sanctity of the &lt;strike&gt;confessional&lt;/strike&gt; interview.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never pair programmed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve frequently worked with a partner on critical production problems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I find this fascinating. &amp;nbsp;If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that needs to be fixed as fast, as correctly, as efficiently as possible, it&amp;rsquo;s a production issue. &amp;nbsp;And when there is one, &amp;ldquo;everyone&amp;rdquo; knows that two heads are better than one, even The Business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If this is the case, why is it so hard to sell pair programming as the default state of affairs?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is it because creating new features is seen as just typing, where the bottleneck is access to the physical keyboard? &amp;nbsp;Is it because fixing defects when the pressure &lt;i&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/i&gt; on is suddenly easier for one person on their own without help?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This state of affairs is interesting to me as it implies that when&amp;nbsp;proverbial&amp;nbsp;hits the fan, the instinctive thing to do is to work collaboratively. &amp;nbsp;Why don&amp;rsquo;t we do it more often?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;We use Test Driven Development to get coverage&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seems weird to me to write your tests first to get coverage. &amp;nbsp;If unit test coverage is your most important metric (and &lt;a href=&#34;http://craftedsw.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/code-coverage-is-side-effect-and-not.html&#34;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://goodenoughsoftware.net/2012/03/21/code-coverage/&#34;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TestCoverage.html&#34;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; covered why this might not be the case), I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why you would write your tests first. &amp;nbsp;Seems to me that you&amp;rsquo;d get better coverage writing the tests &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; the code. &amp;nbsp;That way you can be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve covered every eventuality.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To me, the statement implies two assumptions which I would challenge:&lt;br /&gt;a) The primary value of writing your tests first is to meet your coverage requirements&lt;br /&gt;b) Coverage is a meaningful metric&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TDD/BDD has a number of benefits (&amp;hellip;and now I&amp;rsquo;m reluctant to list them here in case people repeat them back to me in an interview). &amp;nbsp;Good coverage will probably be a side effect of being forced to write your tests first, but I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced that&amp;rsquo;s the best thing that will come out of using TDD.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;I only test first when I know what I want to code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve overheard people saying that they test first when they know what the code is going to look like. &amp;nbsp;So you dive straight into the code when you &lt;i&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/i&gt; know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing???&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course there is a place for this - spikes, prototyping, getting a feel for a new library, so on and so forth. &amp;nbsp;But I feel that for most code that you write in your day job, you probably have a business requirement and possibly (probably?) a less firm idea of how you&amp;rsquo;re going to code it. &amp;nbsp;To me, this translates into writing the test first (which documents what you want to deliver, which you already know) and then getting that to pass (which is writing the code, which is the bit you might not know). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you know exactly what the code is going to look like a) I would question that statement and b) what&amp;rsquo;s the point of the test?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are the real answers?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/qcon-london-2012.html&#34;&gt;QCon&lt;/a&gt; I saw on Twitter a number of complaints because the presentations there gave opinions, guidelines, and, worst of all, a lot of &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;But people seemed to want The Answers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In my opinion, what developers get paid for is working out the &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo; parameters and selecting an approach, technical or process-wise, that works for their situation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So although I have strong opinions on all the above subjects, and although LMAX has specific approaches to both pair programming and automated testing, sadly I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into lots of details about those.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mostly because I&amp;rsquo;m still interviewing candidates, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give away the correct answers&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2011: Roundup</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having been back in London for a few days I&amp;rsquo;ve had some time to digest the madness that was last week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My lasting impression of JavaOne is almost entirely positive. &amp;nbsp;Granted, it was my first major conference, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just not jaded yet. &amp;nbsp;But let me tell you what I loved about it (yes, I did cover some of these in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/10/java-one-initial-observations.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RlwrbbMeTWI/TpWq7Aw_7OI/AAAAAAAAIQ0/UiDjINFvXjo/s1600/bruno.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;219&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RlwrbbMeTWI/TpWq7Aw_7OI/AAAAAAAAIQ0/UiDjINFvXjo/s320/bruno.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First and foremost, the people. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember meeting a single grumpy person. Everyone I spoke to was there to get the most out of the experience, regardless of how many times they&amp;rsquo;d been previously. &amp;nbsp;In my experience, techies are not conditioned to be socially comfortable, yet&amp;nbsp;introductions were made and&amp;nbsp;the conversations flowed easily.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Of course it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just the attendees who were friendly, the staff and organisers were approachable and helpful, and it was nice to have people hanging around to direct you.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;One of the (few) advantages of having the event over multiple hotels was the outdoor space between them. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that it rained, &amp;nbsp;but I really liked being able to hang around outside. &amp;nbsp;I especially liked that they had provided power points for your laptop, so you didn&amp;rsquo;t have to be cooped up indoors to update your blog. &amp;nbsp;I also thought that having to walk between the venues was good exercise, given I didn&amp;rsquo;t make it to the gym last week. However I can see why people want to move the event back to one central location.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UOsWpFnYjSw/TpWrGSgqheI/AAAAAAAAIQ8/Hx8nyX5S3uA/s1600/martijn.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UOsWpFnYjSw/TpWrGSgqheI/AAAAAAAAIQ8/Hx8nyX5S3uA/s200/martijn.jpg&#34; width=&#34;177&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I personally found the sessions less useful than the networking. &amp;nbsp;I mostly attended the high-performance / concurrency sessions, but I probably should have been to ones about things I &lt;i&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/i&gt; know (e.g. other JVM languages). &amp;nbsp;My favourite session was &lt;a href=&#34;http://martijnverburg.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martijn&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Diabolical Developer session, but then I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of stand-up comedy. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Another favourite was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://javaposse.com/&#34;&gt;Java Posse&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;live podcast. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed to admit that I&amp;rsquo;ve never listened to one before (my excuse: I don&amp;rsquo;t listen to podcasts at all because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a long commute to work, which would be the ideal time). &amp;nbsp;I thought it was great how everyone felt like a part of the Java Posse and not a passive audience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8az7qiRldX8/TpWro5J2Z2I/AAAAAAAAIRM/fCD-liE8g9o/s1600/javaposse.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8az7qiRldX8/TpWro5J2Z2I/AAAAAAAAIRM/fCD-liE8g9o/s320/javaposse.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I really felt that Oracle was trying its best to invoke the spirit of community. &amp;nbsp;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s because when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in sessions or having random conversations, I was in Java User Group or &lt;a href=&#34;http://jcp.org/en/home/index&#34;&gt;Java Community Process&lt;/a&gt; events. &amp;nbsp;It seems pretty clear to me that the inclusion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://soujava.org.br/&#34;&gt;SouJava&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt; in the JCP EC has shaken things up a bit. &amp;nbsp;But then, I would say that - I&amp;rsquo;m biased. &amp;nbsp;But the vibe I was getting across the whole conference was that having the community involved in this key decision-making organisation is a step forward. &amp;nbsp;I would even go so far as to claim that it inspired a number of other players to seriously consider getting on board rather than complaining from the sidelines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vuIJB2I4Elo/TpWrcuMqwoI/AAAAAAAAIRE/M8Y6MkPZW6E/s1600/jduchess.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;145&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vuIJB2I4Elo/TpWrcuMqwoI/AAAAAAAAIRE/M8Y6MkPZW6E/s320/jduchess.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On a related note, I really enjoyed the final &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/ocom/groups/systemobject/@mktg_admin/documents/webcontent/videoplayer-ocom.html?bctid=1176404830001&amp;amp;playerID=single-social&amp;amp;size=events&#34;&gt;keynote on community&lt;/a&gt;. To me, that was an indication that Oracle takes our participation very seriously. &amp;nbsp;I liked that it was split into a lot of different interviews and panels, all quite short, which showcased the variety of the Java platform community. &amp;nbsp;I came out of that feeling pretty warm and fluffy about the future of our technology, and proud to be an active part of it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Stuff I was not so bothered about:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Vendor keynotes. &amp;nbsp;Pretty dull to be honest. &amp;nbsp;I understand why they had them but after the first one I didn&amp;rsquo;t turn up to any more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The other bad points I already mentioned in the last post.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Personal highlights:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aovhDAhVoKI/TpWryE1AKMI/AAAAAAAAIRU/vnwMqPGquSQ/s1600/intro-to-disruptor.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;154&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aovhDAhVoKI/TpWryE1AKMI/AAAAAAAAIRU/vnwMqPGquSQ/s200/intro-to-disruptor.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Picking up the Duke&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/ocom/groups/public/@ocom/documents/digitalasset/512339.jpg&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- note: only seems to work in Firefox for me) for &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/&#34;&gt;the Disruptor&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ll shut up about it at some point, let me have my moment of glory.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Co-presenting a session on the Disruptor with &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;He invited me to stand up with him when we realised I could go to the event, and I was terrified of the thought. &amp;nbsp;So I did it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Meeting and being interviewed by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jduchess.org/&#34;&gt;JDuchess&lt;/a&gt; ladies. &amp;nbsp;The video doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be available, so maybe I was rubbish, but it was a cool thing for me all the same.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Talking about the Disruptor for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.oracle.com/javaspotlight/entry/java_spotlight_episode_51_live&#34;&gt;Java Spotlight Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the Oracle news guys (again, I can&amp;rsquo;t find the content for this yet).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had a really brilliant time, and would love to repeat the experience again as soon as possible!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On How Not To Target Girl Geeks</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/on_how_not_to_target_girl_geeks</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/on_how_not_to_target_girl_geeks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(First, let me say this post contains opinion, stereotyping and sweeping generalisations. &amp;nbsp;But that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the point. &amp;nbsp;Also I don&amp;rsquo;t pretend for one moment to speak for all girl programmers, I can only speak for myself)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When I first started this blog, I wanted to just post &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; technical information. &amp;nbsp;I wanted to prove that there are girls out there doing &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; programming.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I specifically didn&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about my gender. &amp;nbsp;I wanted to prove by silence that gender is incidental to what I do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work that way, does it? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Firstly because one of the first things I get asked by guys when I meet them in this industry is &amp;ldquo;why aren&amp;rsquo;t there more girl programmers?&amp;rdquo; (that&amp;rsquo;s after they ask &amp;ldquo;do you work in HR?&amp;rdquo; followed by &amp;ldquo;are you a real programmer?&amp;rdquo; - I&amp;rsquo;m not joking, this happened this week).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And secondly because I&amp;rsquo;m pretty passionate about the gender issue. &amp;nbsp;To be specific: I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about &lt;i&gt;diversity&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;m more qualified to bang on about gender rather than something like race, sexuality, age etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: large;&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s started you off again this time?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;got me thinking by asking &amp;ldquo;Is there anything we can do to attract more girls to the events?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thing is, the reason people (boys) keep asking this question is because they &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; more girls in the industry / at events. &amp;nbsp;They &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; them to feel involved and included. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve said it before, but I mean it - I&amp;rsquo;ve never come across malicious sexism at work. &amp;nbsp;Yes there is subconscious sexism. &amp;nbsp;But the boys want the girls to come and play. &amp;nbsp;Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they? &amp;nbsp;How many boys really want to work in a team which has 12 developers and only one is a girl? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But think about it: who is the worst person to ask why girls don&amp;rsquo;t like being developers?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yep. &amp;nbsp;A girl developer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because we love it. &amp;nbsp;We&amp;rsquo;re here because we like programming, we like our jobs, we&amp;rsquo;re good at it. &amp;nbsp;We weren&amp;rsquo;t stopped by sexism (assumed or real), by boys clubs, by not having female role models, by&amp;hellip; well, any of the myriad of reasons posited as to why girls don&amp;rsquo;t become programmers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have no idea why a girl wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to be a programmer. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s brilliant! &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s problem-solving, logical and creative, you&amp;rsquo;re usually surrounded by intelligent people who are striving toward the same goal as you, and you get to meet a lot of boys :-)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, back to the question at hand: how do we appeal to girls, as a user group and ultimately as an industry?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are lots and lots of ideas kicking around this area, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to start by ranting about the things I think we&lt;i&gt; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/i&gt; be doing. &amp;nbsp;This, of course, is totally my opinion so helpings of salt might be required.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: large;&#34;&gt;No Pink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I get so angry about this!! &amp;nbsp;As if the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/theguardian/2009/dec/12/pinkstinks-the-power-of-pink&#34;&gt;pinkification&lt;/a&gt; of our little girls wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad enough, &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; (I have no idea who) think that they can inflict this upon grown-ups too!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why, WHY, would a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.womenintechnology.co.uk/&#34;&gt;website that is aimed at professional technical women&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;be branded in childish hues of the hated colour? &amp;nbsp;I didn&amp;rsquo;t even click on a single link, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what service it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to provide, because I was so disgusted by the colour palate I closed the browser.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;In particular&lt;/i&gt;, if your target demographic is the somewhat unusual creature the girl-geek, or at least the lady technologist, what makes you think that ultra-feminine colour is going to appeal to us? &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technology.timesonline.co.uk/tol/news/tech_and_web/article7011125.ece&#34;&gt;Apparently&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;The November 2009 Times/Lady Geek Female Appeal Study showed that only 9% of women want technology to be feminine, let alone pink.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What do you think, that your average (female) maths graduate is going to decide Computing Is For Me Because It&amp;rsquo;s Pink? &amp;nbsp;Really?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I worry about this: are these &lt;a href=&#34;http://techettes.com/&#34;&gt;sites&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobiles.co.uk/pink-mobile-phones.html&#34;&gt;phones&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luuux.com/technology/pink-psp-women&#34;&gt;consoles&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carpages.co.uk/smart/smart-fortwo-13-12-05.asp&#34;&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt;) designed by men, and that&amp;rsquo;s what they think women like? &amp;nbsp;Or were they designed by women who really believe that&amp;rsquo;s what ALL women like?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please. &amp;nbsp;Stop it. &amp;nbsp;Now. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;embarrassing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: large;&#34;&gt;Be careful about your role models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fwd.five.tv/gadget-show&#34;&gt;gadget show&lt;/a&gt;, for example. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually watch it, I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, because I really don&amp;rsquo;t need someone tempting me to spend money on things I don&amp;rsquo;t require. &amp;nbsp;But as an example of this point it&amp;rsquo;s perfect - just the picture at the top of the page says it all to me: two reasonably attractive women (I know not everyone floats your boat but they&amp;rsquo;re not ugly), token black guy and two white guys who certainly don&amp;rsquo;t float my boat. &amp;nbsp;If only one of them was gay, their diversity tick sheet would be perfect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am not for one second suggesting any of these guys don&amp;rsquo;t know their stuff. &amp;nbsp;That is not the point at all. &amp;nbsp;I just wonder - if one of the women looked like someone&amp;rsquo;s mum, would they have got the job? &amp;nbsp;The&amp;nbsp;subconscious&amp;nbsp;message here is that yes, it&amp;rsquo;s totally fine to be a girl and a geek. &amp;nbsp;But you still have to look good too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s another message there - if you&amp;rsquo;re a guy and you&amp;rsquo;re into technology, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be hot. In fact, the role models we see are definitely on the Not Hot end of the scale. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://politicolnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/Bill_Gates_718639.jpg&#34;&gt;Bill Gates&lt;/a&gt; anyone?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So girls get a double-whammy - I have to know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about and look good (whilst also trying to prove that girls who look good have brains); and there are no hot guys in the industry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hmm, no thanks, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll get a job in marketing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: large;&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t assume all women are the same&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In fact don&amp;rsquo;t assume anything about the girls you want to attract. &amp;nbsp;Actually, assume they&amp;rsquo;re people. &amp;nbsp;Like you. &amp;nbsp;And geeks. &amp;nbsp;Like you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For example. &amp;nbsp;I actually do like shoes and clothes. &amp;nbsp;But plenty of my fellow girl-geeks are about as bothered about that stuff as their male counter-parts. &amp;nbsp;So trying to appeal to girls with iPhone apps that help you pick you next pair of Jimmy Choos might not be the approach you want to take. &amp;nbsp;You&amp;rsquo;ll attract a subset of women, sure, but they might not be the ones you want.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Imagine if you wanted to get more guys into programming, and you decided to do it by using football as the hook. &amp;nbsp;Yes, you&amp;rsquo;d get certain guys interested. But I&amp;rsquo;ve met more guys who are utterly disinterested in football in IT than I&amp;rsquo;ve met girls who dislike it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not all the same. &amp;nbsp;We&amp;rsquo;re interested in all sorts of different stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: large;&#34;&gt;Be very very careful about women-only events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My personal feelings are that there should be no need for all-girl conferences or all-girl line-ups. &amp;nbsp;To me, it implies that girls want something different to boys, and that girls only listen to other females.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think there are places for these sorts of things, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re aiming it at girls who might be more uncomfortable with guys around (e.g. some sort of mentoring). &amp;nbsp;So I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say flat-out they&amp;rsquo;re wrong.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just I think it&amp;rsquo;s not the right angle to attack the problem. &amp;nbsp;And you&amp;rsquo;re segregating based on one dimension only, but as I said we&amp;rsquo;re all different and we all have different problems. &amp;nbsp;The issues a non-white (am I allowed to say that?) lady might face could be different to those a middle class white girl like me has to deal with. &amp;nbsp;And do you want all-black conferences, and all-gay conferences, and so on and so forth? &amp;nbsp;Why are we special? &amp;nbsp;Why are we allowed to exclude the boys? &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s sexist.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, as a girl-geek, I get a bit freaked out when I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by women, even if they&amp;rsquo;re all geeks like me. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m much more comfortable talking to a guy, they tend not to try to read between the lines of everything you say or wonder if you&amp;rsquo;re bitching about them behing their back &amp;lt;/gross generalisation&amp;gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Diversity is about being inclusive, not exclusive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: large;&#34;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lots of the girl-geek, women-in-IT movement often appears to me&amp;nbsp;as if women are &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; and need different treatment. This&amp;nbsp;is not helping our cause&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;at all&lt;/i&gt;. It causes resentment amongst our&amp;nbsp;male peers&amp;nbsp;and it puts off women who don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;nbsp;define themselves by their gender - people like the girls who are already in our industry. We like&amp;nbsp;technology, we love programming, and we&amp;rsquo;re good at our jobs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;So. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why there aren&amp;rsquo;t more girls in programming. &amp;nbsp;And I don&amp;rsquo;t have the answers as to what will tempt them in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But, just for me, next time you&amp;rsquo;re creating an advert or a website or something aimed at geek-girls, can we have more hot guys please?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
