<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devoxx on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/devoxx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devoxx on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/devoxx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agile&#43;&#43;: When Agile Goes Well</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/agile_when_agile_goes_well/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/agile_when_agile_goes_well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you see anything about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lmax.com/&#34;&gt;LMAX&lt;/a&gt; - the Disruptor, Continuous Delivery, or even the selection criteria for hiring developers, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that LMAX is pretty keen on &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemanifesto.org/&#34;&gt;Agile&lt;/a&gt;. However, no-one&amp;rsquo;s documented the Agile process there, as far as I know. Although I personally had it on my todo list, I never had the motivation, the hook to do it. And I realised eventually that&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s a process that would work very well for another team, in another company, working in another business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Devoxx 2012</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/summary_of_devoxx_2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/summary_of_devoxx_2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/53695846&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/53695846&#34;&gt;Devoxx 2012&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devoxx topped off a crazy two months of conferences.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people talk about the conference season in the past, and been slightly (OK, very) jealous of all that jet-setting.  I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, however, to a slight feeling of relief that my focus until Christmas is pretty much going to be coding.  I hope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview by the Oracle Technology Network at Devoxx</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx/</guid>
      <description>Tori Wieldt from the Oracle Technology Network interviewed me at Devoxx. Because I was there to be on the Why We Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Target Women panel, the interview is just another platform for me to air my views on this subject again. 
Yes, I am actually wearing pink&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Shouldn&#39;t Target Women</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/why_we_shouldnt_target_women/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/why_we_shouldnt_target_women/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from Devoxx, having had lots of food for thought. In particular, my panel on Why We Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Target Women generated a lot of discussion and I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to process it all.
Martijn Verburg; Regina ten Bruggencate; Trisha Gee; Antonio Goncalves; Claude Falguière; Kim Ross The panel went really well, we got decent interaction from the audience, and of course my fellow panel members were awesome. I managed to restrain myself from using the opportunity as my own personal soap box and allowed other people to speak occasionally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx: The story so far</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_story_so_far/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_story_so_far/</guid>
      <description>Stephan wearing the Brazilian flag at the opening keynote
 European conferences are different (and cool) because you get to hear even more languages spoken than you usually do in London (apparently the most diverse city in the world for spoken languages). I think the idea of a Paris Devoxx with 75% of the talks in French is brilliant - I&amp;rsquo;m always banging on about diversity, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect developers to learn in English only.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
