<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Advocacy on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/advocacy/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Conferences Do To Attract More Women Speakers?</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/more_women_speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/more_women_speakers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;ve been speaking at (mostly Java) conferences for a while (six years now), I get asked to
present at a lot of conferences.  &lt;em&gt;Obviously&lt;/em&gt; all these conferences are mostly interested in my
terribly educational talks, but it&amp;rsquo;s also because I&amp;rsquo;m a technical woman and there aren&amp;rsquo;t very
many technical women speaking at conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, conferences want to do the right thing - they want a diverse line up of
speakers, they want to attract diverse attendees. Often this is not as easy as it may seem, and
frequently conferences are Twitter-shamed for not having enough women speakers. When it gets to
this point (and often before), conferences frequently ask me for advice on
speakers they could invite, and how to attract more women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do at this point have to roll my eyes somewhat though.  It&amp;rsquo;s an additional bit of workload that
my male peers do not have to do: they are not asked to recommend suitable women speakers; they
are not asked what a conference should be doing to improve diversity.  And let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that
one of the reasons why I have made it to this point in our male industry is by having some
combination of luck, selective blindness and an unusual attitude which means that I&amp;rsquo;m probably not
qualified to speak on behalf of all the other women developers/speakers out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. To save myself some time in the future, here&amp;rsquo;s my blog post version of
stuff-that-I-can-think-of-that-might-help. This is not scientific. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch more stuff out
there on the internet (including
&lt;a href=&#34;https://continuousdelivery.com/2013/09/how-we-got-40-female-speakers-at-flowcon/&#34;&gt;one from Jez Humble&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/samsung-internet-dev/help-someone-has-pointed-out-my-conference-has-diversity-issues-c1162a1e8d4c&#34;&gt;help, my conference has diversity issues&lt;/a&gt;),
please do Google for more.  The following suggestions come from my experience as a) a speaker b)
a programme committee member of QCon London, DevoxxUK and DevoxxUS and c) just a normal person
who thinks about these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Have a Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many many things have been written about this, I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to rehash them. You need one, if
you don&amp;rsquo;t have one go and research this and put one in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Consider Diversity as a Key, Cross-Cutting Concern of Your Conference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You couldn&amp;rsquo;t have a
conference without researching venues; without figuring out the catering; without doing analysis
of costs. If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about diversity, about improving the industry, or even just about not
being attacked on Twitter, you have to consider diversity right from the start, and you have to
consider it in the context of almost every other decision: Does the venue have step-free access?
Can the caterers provide a range of non-alcoholic drinks rather than just the standard beers? Do
the dates clash with some major religious festival? Or football event? (for example).
Considering people with different needs, cultures, interests is something that you need to take
seriously at every step. Diversity is not something you can just tack on at the last minute.
This Is Hard.  It helps if your organisers/program committee members are diverse, as others will
think of things you have not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Your Website and Marketing Material Should Represent the People You Want to Attract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make
sure that on your website and in your emails/tweets, photos of attendees and speakers
represent the range of people you want to come. Don&amp;rsquo;t just put up a handful of photos
from last year&amp;rsquo;s conference without looking very closely at who is, and who is not, shown in
these photos.  From a gender diversity point of view, my rule of thumb is that every photo should
have at least one female-looking person visible in it, ideally closer to 50%. Other measures of
diversity that may be visible in photos include race and age, but
it can also be things like dress code - the first DevoxxUK attracted people with pink mohawks,
goths, men/women in suits, as well as the usual tshirt-and-jeans brigade.  It was wonderful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To showcase diversity in photos/images, you can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show your organisers/programme committee. In my experience there are usually women in amongst
the organisers, having photos of them on the site in a visible place is a good way to suggest to
women that if they submit a talk they will be evaluated by people like them. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m
focusing on gender, but this can apply to other dimensions too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select photos from previous conferences that include women (I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that the new
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&#34;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; may prevent you from
posting photos of people publicly without their consent, so be careful here). Make sure they&amp;rsquo;re
not booth babes (Note: Do Not Allow Booth Babes. By all means, women should work on
sponsor booths, but they should be employees of the company, not women hired in to look a
particular way to sell the product). Ideally in these photos the women should look like they are
being included, e.g. in groups talking to people, not standing alone to one side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showcase your diverse speakers.  This is a catch 22 of course, because you want to showcase
diversity in order to attract speakers to submit, so you can&amp;rsquo;t show diverse speakers before
you&amp;rsquo;ve had speakers submit&amp;hellip; You can show speakers from previous years; you can show your
keynote speakers (hint: it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to have at least one woman giving a keynote and you
should secure them well before the CFP closes so you can show them off); you can invite selected
speakers early who won&amp;rsquo;t go through the CFP and show them on the site (see next
section)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just about photos, it&amp;rsquo;s also logos/imagery and language.  If you have characters, make
sure they&amp;rsquo;re not all men/masculine. If you have a theme, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s open to all.  I really
loved
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/devoxx-uk-2015-stephan-janssen/&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&amp;rsquo;s League of Extraordinary Developers&lt;/a&gt;,
it showed a range of diverse characters, not
just gender and race but implied we&amp;rsquo;re not all the same and we have different strengths and
skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also check the language you use. There have been a number of studies
that show that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/hbsworkingknowledge/2016/12/14/how-to-take-gender-bias-out-of-your-job-ads/#490276c71024&#34;&gt;language in job adverts can subtly imply male vs female
roles&lt;/a&gt;. But even easier
than that, make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t assume attendees will be a &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rdquo; and don&amp;rsquo;t use words like &amp;ldquo;guys&amp;rdquo; -
you may have seen this used in a gender neutral way but many people feel it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; gender
neutral and implies &amp;ldquo;men&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Invite Women Speakers Early, and Personally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women speakers are very much in demand.  There
are more conferences than women speakers, and we get booked up well in advance (my next 9-12
months are usually already booked up).  If you want to
ensure you have a decent proportion of women speakers, you need to reach out to us personally,
early, and ideally offer us a guaranteed speaking slot. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of being asked to submit
to a CFP, I get invited to enough conferences that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to go to more, and going through a
CFP adds a lot of variability. For experienced speakers who you know you&amp;rsquo;re likely
to accept anyway, consider offering them a guaranteed slot.  For less experienced / new speakers,
invite them to submit.  But whoever you&amp;rsquo;re reaching out to, at least (please) put their name on the
email.  One of the conferences suffering from a lack of women speakers at the moment invited me
with a standard email addressed to &amp;ldquo;Dear madam&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m usually strict about replying to requests
but I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to reply to this one as they didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to customise their
request to me.  On this topic, what I want to see in an invitation email (and maybe other people
 are different) are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the first paragraph: which conference (with link); date; city; very very short description
of the conference (&amp;ldquo;community run Java conference&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Europe&amp;rsquo;s biggest devops conference&amp;rdquo;,
something that gives me a rough idea of technology and community); what do you want me to
speak about (either a specific talk, or a more general topic).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you cover travel/accommodation, put that somewhere near the beginning of your email, this
can make it much easier for a speaker to say &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to your conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other useful information can go in the later paragraphs: approx number of attendees; who else
is presenting / has presented in the past; interesting activities during the conference / in
the city.  None of this stuff is mandatory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bit of flattery / how you know about me is always welcome. Oh but don&amp;rsquo;t be creepy &lt;em&gt;shudder&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Find Women&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, right? Not so much.  But please, don&amp;rsquo;t just email the first woman speaker
who comes to your mind and say &amp;ldquo;please come and speak, and also if you could find us all the other
women speakers we need that would be great too&amp;rdquo;. By all means ask for recommendations (from all
speakers actually, it&amp;rsquo;s freaking exhausting being a woman speaker because we do a lot of work in
this area, connecting people up and pointing them in the right direction and plenty of
experienced male speakers are better at this than me). But this is a numbers game - there aren&amp;rsquo;t
many women speakers and those that do this regularly are very in demand, you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to
invite a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of women to stand a chance of having a diverse line up. Here are some suggestions
based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past to find women speakers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google &amp;ldquo;Women in&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Java, Data, Blockchain, whatever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at big conferences in this space from the last two years, spot the female-ish faces and
make a list of them. When asked for Java/JVM recommendations, I check JavaOne,
DevoxxUK/Belgium, JavaZone, JFokus and maybe Google &amp;ldquo;Java conferences&amp;rdquo; to find the others I&amp;rsquo;ve
forgotten. For broader topics I look at QCon London because I know they always
work hard on diversity and have had a bunch of really fantastic women speakers in the past. I
sometimes check out the GOTO conferences for the same reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for local user groups who could help.  You can search Meetup.com
for &amp;ldquo;Women code&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Lady developers&amp;rdquo; and variations on that theme.  Find the groups in the area
local to the conference, and reach out really nicely to them to ask if they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind
circulating the details of your CFP amongst their members.  Remember to provide them with
information about why their members want to speak
(all travel covered/opportunities to meet various people/mentoring provided, whatever). If you
can see previous speakers at these groups, you could add them to your list of women to reach
out to personally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/callbackwomen&#34;&gt;Callback women&lt;/a&gt; to retweet the CFP details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the networks of women speakers, like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://articulate-network.lanyrd.com/&#34;&gt;Articulate Network&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fempire/women-tech-speakers-organizers&#34;&gt;this list of women speakers&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenwhokeynote.com/&#34;&gt;Women who keynote&lt;/a&gt;.  Google
for these lists too, there&amp;rsquo;s loads of them. Sadly these resources are not very centralised.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Provide Travel and Accommodation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to attract/grow new
speakers. You may not have budget to apply this to everyone, but if you really want to have diverse
speakers you may need to set aside some budget to pay for them.  In my first year of presenting I
was doing it more or less on my own (vacation) time because I had a real job as a real
developer, and I could only speak at conferences who would cover my costs.  This is even more
tricky for self employed people as they&amp;rsquo;re also losing money by attending your conference.  Be
aware that not everyone a) is a professional advocate (and even when we are it&amp;rsquo;s easier to say
yes to a conference if our employer doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay) b) is employed by a forward-thinking
employer who is happy to let employees go to conferences or c) has paid vacation time they are
willing/able to use. Be aware that for some people this cost might be more than just
the cheapest flight and cheapest hotel for one person - one conference paid for me,
my partner and my (at the time) one-year-old to travel halfway around the world so I could speak at
the conference. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take that time away from my family so they brought the whole family,
I would not have been able to speak there otherwise.  Another conference this year is paying
for all four of us to travel, plus a family hotel room - I&amp;rsquo;m currently breastfeeding and I can&amp;rsquo;t
leave the baby for very long, and if I&amp;rsquo;m going to bring the baby I need to bring the husband to
take the baby while I&amp;rsquo;m talking, which means we also need to bring the toddler, because she&amp;rsquo;s
a bit young to leave at home alone for a weekend.  I don&amp;rsquo;t always need all these costs covering,
I&amp;rsquo;m not always breastfeeding, and even after the first was born there were plenty of times I could
travel alone.  But if you want to improve your diversity you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to consider these
sorts of cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Provide rehearsal space&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is quite time consuming and relies on having people willing
to watch the rehearsal and give feedback.  I actually mean &lt;em&gt;virtual&lt;/em&gt; space here, I&amp;rsquo;ve given my talk
via hangouts to the track lead for QCon New York to get feedback on a new talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying
 to attract new talent, consider involving one or more local user groups and running a speaker
 training session. The London Java Community has done this a couple of times. You need to select
 the people who will provide mentoring / feedback &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; carefully.  They need to be aware of the
 type of gendered words that are frequently used for women and avoid them (would
 you ever use the word &amp;ldquo;feisty&amp;rdquo; for a man? No, you would not); they
 need to be aware that women get
 &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/04/how-gender-bias-corrupts-performance-reviews-and-what-to-do-about-it&#34;&gt;critical personality feedback&lt;/a&gt;
 instead of actionable feedback.
 The feedback to help mentor new speakers, particularly women speakers, needs to be well thought
 out (not &amp;ldquo;you seem nervous&amp;rdquo;, maybe &amp;ldquo;is there some section of the content
 that makes you uncomfortable&amp;rdquo;, for example). These mentors need to be experienced speakers.
 Ideally they should also be diverse, but if this is not possible then men who are experienced at
championing women will be OK (my mentors were all men).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also run community nights, these
aren&amp;rsquo;t sessions aimed at training the speakers, but user group events where you can have
prospective speakers present their talk. Obviously this works if a) the speaker is local and b)
you have links with appropriate local user groups.  But this is a good way to grow the community,
 and to try out speakers without having to judge them through a CFP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Have lightning talks on the agenda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks can be a very mixed bag of quality and can introduce complexity to your scheduling.
But they&amp;rsquo;re also a good way to get inexperienced speakers
into the conference, and to give them an opportunity to be videoed (and have conference speaking
on their CV) so they can break into speaking properly.  As an attendee I like lightning talks -
the topics are often varied, and ones I often wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother watching a whole hour of, and I&amp;rsquo;ll
tolerate poor content/poor delivery for 10 minutes without complaint.  You will need to consider
your cost/benefit here though, I doubt you&amp;rsquo;ll want to pay expenses to ship a whole family of four
over to your conference for the sake of a 10 minute talk, these seem to work best in encouraging
local developers to speak at your conference.  Again, ties with local user groups will be key here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;Be Open to Flexible Scheduling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, I really do, that your conference is really hard to
schedule. Not just the
actual dates, but who presents in which room at what time.  This is super difficult, and most
speakers understand this and will accept the vague &amp;ldquo;your talk will be one of these three days&amp;rdquo;
notice. Many speakers who are just starting will probably love to be there for the whole
conference, I certainly did! But this is really hard for people who can&amp;rsquo;t get the time off work
or away from their family. It&amp;rsquo;s also less exciting when you&amp;rsquo;ve already seen many of the talks
you care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started doing this, my work was peeved if I took three days off to travel to a
conference.  Now, I&amp;rsquo;m peeved if I take three days away from my family.  There&amp;rsquo;s a really hard
balance for us speakers to strike, especially when
 we book our own travel: we either need to book early to get cheap travel, in which case we
 don&amp;rsquo;t know when our talk is so we have to be there for the whole conference; or we book as soon
 as we know the date and time of the talk, in which case someone is going to be stung with higher
  travel costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering diversity also means understanding that not everyone lives in or near a city
with a major airport. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get spoilt in London, Paris, Madrid, Amsterdam, because
there are so many flights to so many places from there.  But because I&amp;rsquo;m
travelling from somewhere that isn&amp;rsquo;t a major airport,
  direct flights to many conference locations are rare, and if they exist are almost always only
  on a couple
  of days the week and at horrible times, so my ability to get to and from the conference is
  limited. This either adds one or two days either side of the conference waiting for the
  right flight (so days and days away from the family for a one hour talk), or means I have a very
  small window during your conference that I can be there. What would make my life easier is one of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me my time slot as soon as possible.  Oh, and do tell me.  Most conferences don&amp;rsquo;t
bother, I have to check the schedule when it&amp;rsquo;s posted on the website which is often only a
couple of weeks before the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow me to suggest the best dates/times for me. I know it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to accommodate
everyone, but for those of us with difficult schedules and/or who want to limit time away from
home/work, I would really like to be able to say &amp;ldquo;I can only do this conference if I can talk
Monday afternoon&amp;rdquo; and not sound like a diva.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;Consider Diversity Scholarships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some conferences offer discounts/free tickets for underrepresented groups.
I feel a bit torn on this topic personally because I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of positive discrimination and
this looks a bit like that.  But if you have offered something like this, it may attract
speakers from underrepresented groups as well, because you are doing something proactive. If you
consider this idea please do your research in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_10&#34;&gt;Swag isn&amp;rsquo;t Just for Boys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started going to conferences I got really annoyed
that all the free t-shirts were &amp;ldquo;unisex&amp;rdquo;, i.e. male.  I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about this any more
because I&amp;rsquo;d like to wear clothes that I&amp;rsquo;ve actually chosen and paid for that actually fit me.
But it does annoy a lot of women
speakers and attendees, and it&amp;rsquo;s always noticeable when a conference goes out of
its way to have women&amp;rsquo;s shapes and sizes. But don&amp;rsquo;t make them a different colour/logo, this just
says &amp;ldquo;hey women, you&amp;rsquo;re like a totally different species and we&amp;rsquo;re going to make you stand out&amp;rdquo;.
Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that in 100% of the cases where I&amp;rsquo;ve had a different colour the men have been
totally jealous of my much more attractive women&amp;rsquo;s cut top, what matters is you don&amp;rsquo;t want to
make the minorities stand out even more than they already do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just t-shirts either. For each bit of swag, think &amp;ldquo;would I give this to my sister / gay
friend / muslim co-worker?&amp;ldquo;. Not everyone at the conference is a beer-drinking, youngish,
straight, white, single male. And even those who are can be offended by swag that stereotypes
what they should be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_11&#34;&gt;Consider having a blind CFP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written in the past that I&amp;rsquo;m really not sure about this
as a solution, but other sectors and other conferences have had success with this.  Perhaps if
you combine this with actively reaching out to women and giving them guaranteed speaking slots,
maybe this will address the weaknesses of both the invitation and the CFP processes. Do your
research, see how you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_12&#34;&gt;Note for women speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all that advice for conference organisers, I&amp;rsquo;d really like to say something to the women
speakers out there. As usual, my advice applies to men too, but I want to talk specifically to the
ladies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conference invites you to speak and you have no intention of going, please respond with a
&amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; as promptly as possible.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been on both sides of the
invitation (inviting speakers to speak and being invited) and as an inviter it is very very
frustrating not to hear anything back from a valued speaker, especially if there&amp;rsquo;s a slot held
for this speaker that needs to be filled. As a speaker, every time I&amp;rsquo;ve said &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;
within a few hours of getting the email, I almost always get a very nice response
saying &amp;ldquo;thanks for the quick reply&amp;rdquo;.  Saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; quickly is not ever going to be considered
rude, it&amp;rsquo;s actually very helpful to the organisers.  Waiting a while because you want to phrase
it in a nice way, or
simply never getting around to responding because you mean to think the offer through and/or
spend some time on the reply (and I am &lt;em&gt;the worst&lt;/em&gt; at this in most of my email) puts the
conference into limbo - yes, they will have invited plenty
of other speakers so they&amp;rsquo;re not just dependent upon you, but if half of them don&amp;rsquo;t take the
time to respond the organisers don&amp;rsquo;t know if they need to reach out to more people or not. And
as a speaker it&amp;rsquo;s a bit embarrassing to respond a week or more later with a &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; only to have the
 conference say &amp;ldquo;er, sorry, we didn&amp;rsquo;t hear from you so we&amp;rsquo;re all full now&amp;rdquo;. This has happened to
 me. I felt bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you know you&amp;rsquo;re not going, say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; straight away (&amp;ldquo;thanks for the invite, really pleased
you&amp;rsquo;re interested in having me, but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I can&amp;rsquo;t make it&amp;rdquo;, or something, doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be
long winded and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to justify why you&amp;rsquo;re not going).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about it
but you have to work out details/check with work/run it past your partner/research costs,
respond telling them you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about it, and give a rough date of when you&amp;rsquo;ll get back to
them (&amp;ldquo;thanks for the invite, it looks really interesting, I can&amp;rsquo;t commit right now because
I&amp;rsquo;ve got some stuff to work out, if I don&amp;rsquo;t get back to you by the end of next week please give
me a nudge&amp;rdquo;). If you&amp;rsquo;re having some trouble working out the details (maybe the flights are too
expensive, maybe work won&amp;rsquo;t give you the time off) update the conference with this information
because they might be able to do something (give you money towards travel; send you some useful
blurb to wave at your boss about why this is a good business investment for them, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously if it&amp;rsquo;s a yes just respond straight away with yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t, please, just fail to respond.  I know you&amp;rsquo;re super busy, I know you have an inbox stacked
full of more important things you haven&amp;rsquo;t got around to.  Set up a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/inbox/answer/7107959?hl=en&#34;&gt;Google template&lt;/a&gt; (or equivalent) and it
will take seconds to reply, and it&amp;rsquo;s one more mail you can get out of your inbox.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard a lot
of frustration from conference organisers that the women they contact never reply, and because human
nature is the way it is, it leaves organisers feeling demotivated and makes them less likely to
reach out to other women.  I know this isn&amp;rsquo;t your fault, but it is something we can all help to
improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_13&#34;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are probably loads and loads of things I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned.  And it&amp;rsquo;s possible that
conference organisers could do all of these things and still not reach the numbers they want. But I
can practically guarantee that if, as an organiser, you don&amp;rsquo;t do any of these, you aren&amp;rsquo;t going
to get many women speakers at all. Please, read all of these items again, and for your next
conference create a tick-list of all the
 things you&amp;rsquo;re going to do, and all the things you need to check at each stage (like the imagery
 and language of your marketing material).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Developer Advocate at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandatory initial exclamation about how little I have blogged here lately.  Over a year without
updates, oh dear!  But a) I have been blogging quite a lot for the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/author/trishagee/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/upsource/author/trishagee/&#34;&gt;Upsource&lt;/a&gt; blogs, and b) I had another
baby, which kept me quite busy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on that topic (more or less) I get a lot of questions about my job: what&amp;rsquo;s involved in the
job, what&amp;rsquo;s it like working for JetBrains, what does a Developer Advocate do, what&amp;rsquo;s it like
working remotely etc etc.  Given I also rather generously&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; recently offered to answer
people&amp;rsquo;s questions about my job, I thought the most scalable way was to write-once-read-many,
i.e. write it in a single blog post for everyone to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Also, if you&amp;#39;re vaguely contemplating a move into an advocacy-type role and interested to find out what&amp;#39;s involved (and/or if it will suit you) feel free to Tweet/DM/e-mail me with questions and I&amp;#39;ll do my best to brain-dump my experience onto you&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Trisha Gee (@trisha_gee) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/trisha_gee/status/979014330631979010?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 28, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a Very Long Post.  It&amp;rsquo;s also a bit of a brain dump and is not well organised, sorry.  I
take comfort in the fact that if you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the role you won&amp;rsquo;t read it, and if you do
care you&amp;rsquo;re probably interested in all this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I get is &amp;ldquo;How does one become a Developer Advocate?&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve already
written about &lt;a href=&#34;/post/becoming_an_evangelist&#34;&gt;My Path to Evangelism&lt;/a&gt;, which covers how I got into
this job.  My route is not the only route, but at the bottom of that post there are some things you
can do to a) see if you like doing this kind of thing b) improve your skills in this area and c) get the
 experience and visibility you need to make it easier for someone to hire you to do this
 professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/trishagee/&#34;&gt;Developer Advocate for JetBrains&lt;/a&gt;. Developer
Advocates/Evangelists come in various different shapes and sizes depending upon the individual
and the organisation.  At JetBrains advocates do advocacy first and foremost (see the next
section which explains a bit about what I mean).  For me, this means I:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physically go to &lt;em&gt;conferences&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;give presentations&lt;/em&gt;.  I prefer live coding demos, because I
think a) it makes me look clever and b) it showcases the tools nicely. This is not a requirement
of the role, it&amp;rsquo;s something I personally chose because I thought it was good for my personal
&amp;ldquo;brand&amp;rdquo; (this is linked a bit to the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m a female developer, more on that later).
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hhariri&#34;&gt;Hadi&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; talks are more varied than mine, he has plenty that aren&amp;rsquo;t
specifically code-related.&lt;br /&gt;
From JetBrains point of view, if you&amp;rsquo;re out at conferences giving popular talks, that makes
the company look good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I am physically in a country/city I may also seek out &lt;em&gt;user groups&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;customers&lt;/em&gt; to go
and see. This is not a requirement of the job, but it&amp;rsquo;s something I want to do more of and get
better at.  It&amp;rsquo;s very effective and fairly limited extra overhead to also give the same talk you&amp;rsquo;re
giving at some conference to the local user group and some customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customer meetings&lt;/em&gt;. When I originally took this role,
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be doing a bit of consulting as part of the job, e.g. going to a customer and
trouble-shooting their TeamCity installation or running tailored training courses on IntelliJ
IDEA.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been here three years and I haven&amp;rsquo;t done that.  I have, however, done pre-sales
trips to demo a particular product (usually &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/upsource/&#34;&gt;Upsource&lt;/a&gt; and answer questions about it: what does
it do, how does it scale, where will it fit into this company&amp;rsquo;s process, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ve only
physically had to travel for these a couple of times, usually a company is more than happy to
have me present this via a private webinar.  These webinars can sometimes be to a huge number of
developers (hundreds), more usually to 10-20 techies, occasionally just to one or two people.
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a webinar or a physical meeting, I always, always have backup to help me with
things I don&amp;rsquo;t know.  I&amp;rsquo;m a technical advocate, I understand how to use the tool really well. I
don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily know everything on the roadmap (that&amp;rsquo;s usually the PMM), nor do I know all
the technical limitations (a lead techy will know this). It scares me a bit going into these
meetings knowing that I don&amp;rsquo;t know everything, but sometimes I have someone with me (either
physically at the meeting or online with me during the webinar) and I always have someone
available via Slack to answer any questions I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe my
credibility has suffered when I&amp;rsquo;ve said &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to that, let me quickly find
out&amp;rdquo;, especially when there&amp;rsquo;s almost always a fast response. If there&amp;rsquo;s no adequate response
there and then, I make a note of the question and promise to get back to them. I usually end
the meeting by repeating the next steps and listing the information I believe I have to find
out for them, and always follow up with an email. If the answers were quick to find, all the
answers will be in the follow up email. If the answers are still pending, I will tell them
that in the quick response and get back to them later with the answers (e.g. I don&amp;rsquo;t leave
them hanging with no response, it looks bad.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Webinars&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of giving webinars, it&amp;rsquo;s like doing a conference presentation, only
with
waaaaay more real-time viewers and almost zero real-time feedback. It&amp;rsquo;s like talking into the
void.  Some people like giving webinars precisely because they CAN&amp;rsquo;T see the audience.  I used
to hate them because the lack of feedback is very unnerving, but with practice (like anything)
I&amp;rsquo;ve become more comfortable with them.  I probably give maybe 3 public webinars a year (like my
upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2018/03/live-webinar-java-10-and-intellij-idea/&#34;&gt;webinar on Java 10&lt;/a&gt;, and maybe 6 or so private ones a year.  These numbers may be
totally incorrect, but that&amp;rsquo;s what it feels like.  The public webinars are frequently one of my
conference talks just presented online, the private ones are less formal/practiced and may be
something like a short-ish live demo (10-20 mins) followed by questions and further
customer-driven demos (i.e. &amp;ldquo;can you show me how you&amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screencasts&lt;/em&gt;. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done any screencasts before I came to JetBrains and they&amp;rsquo;re a totally
different skillset.  Not only do you have to learn how to use a brand new tool (I use Camtasia)
that requires a set of skills you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have already (i.e. video editing), but putting
together a 5 minute video of features is a VERY different thing to taking 40-60 minutes exploring
a concept in real-time with an audience. You have to work out up-front what it is you&amp;rsquo;re trying
to demo, figure out a sensible real-world use case for it, and then record the video and
narration that effectively shows this to users. I record those two things separately and edit
them together, others like to record the whole lot together. Because this area in particular is
one where probably most of the team was new to the skills needed, we&amp;rsquo;ve shared our knowledge a
few times here to try and improve ourselves and to try to get some consistency in approach. I
quite like doing screencasts because they&amp;rsquo;re a good way to poke at particular features in a tool,
and I like finding the use case that makes the feature make sense. But they can be quite a lot
of work. A screencast like my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/szlAxgchyXU&#34;&gt;VCS features in IntelliJ IDEA 2018.1&lt;/a&gt; can take less than a day
to
put together (most of which is editing), because this is an area of the tool I know well, and I
have a lot of example projects that showcase different use cases of Git workflows.  A
screencast on Spring features is more likely to take 2 or more days, most of which is locating
the right sort of code example that shows the features. It&amp;rsquo;s an area of the tool I haven&amp;rsquo;t used
much in a real development environment, a framework I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with but again don&amp;rsquo;t use
much, and also a framework that moves very rapidly, so I spend a lot of time getting up to
speed on the new parts of the framework and finding examples.  Screencasts generally fall into
two categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New in {Product} {Version} (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLPZy-hmwOdEXtJTNC65GCuw8f7sR13UK9&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA 2017.2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLPZy-hmwOdEXdOtXdFzyx_XCnrF_oD2Ft&#34;&gt;general tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blogging&lt;/em&gt;. I love writing. It&amp;rsquo;s what got me into this. It&amp;rsquo;s why this blog post is SO much
longer than it really ought to be. I probably average 1-2 blog posts a month.  Probably not that
much actually, it depends a lot on my travel and other workloads. For JetBrains I blog about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New releases/features for IntelliJ IDEA and Upsource (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2017/12/intellij-idea-2017-3-debugger-improvements/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA 2017.3: Debugger
Improvements&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics related to the tool but aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily features of the tool (e.g.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/tag/code-smells/&#34;&gt;Code Smells&lt;/a&gt; for
IntelliJ IDEA, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/upsource/tag/code-review-workflows/&#34;&gt;Code Review Processes&lt;/a&gt; for Upsource)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A specific topic that&amp;rsquo;s relevant to readers of the blog that either is relevant at a
particular time (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2017/09/java-9-and-intellij-idea/&#34;&gt;Java 9 and IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;), or is something I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered myself
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2017/10/creating-multi-release-jar-files-in-intellij-idea/&#34;&gt;Creating Multi-Release JAR Files in IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;) or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/tag/java-annotated/&#34;&gt;Annotated monthly&lt;/a&gt;: takes me a day every
month to put together the newsletter, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it as it forces me to stay up to date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or sometimes something that I think is interesting or cool and is vaguely
development-/Java-related.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;. I have access to Tweet on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intellijidea&#34;&gt;intellijidea&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/upsource_jb&#34;&gt;upsource_jb&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one behind
those handles though. I post links to the videos, blog posts and other content I produce, and I
also create content for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DriveToDevelop?src=hash&#34;&gt;Twitter Tips&lt;/a&gt;
for both of those products. I use Camtasia to record
short videos and convert them to GIFs.  The most painful part of this process is thinking of
something interesting to Tweet about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also &lt;em&gt;Tweet from my own personal account&lt;/em&gt;. As I have gained more followers I have been more
and more careful/restrained about what I Tweet from there. I recently realised these days I
retweet a lot and occasionally tweet things I think are interesting to developers. I spend less
and less time ranting on there or making personal observations, although I would quite like to
bring back a more personal element to my Tweets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Theoretically I also &lt;em&gt;answer questions via
Twitter/&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/users/653519/trisha&#34;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;/other social media&lt;/em&gt; about
our
tools.  I don&amp;rsquo;t get around to doing this very often, I should work it into my schedule/routine,
but sometimes I find it takes a disproportionally long time to replicate a problem and work out a
fix, by which time someone else has already answered or the original user has worked it out. If
someone addresses me directly I always try to respond, even if it&amp;rsquo;s just to ask someone to file
a ticket in YouTrack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Admin&lt;/em&gt;.  I actually have to do quite a lot of mundane admin stuff.  Part of it might be because
of my particular perfectionism, part of it might be because my situation really does require it.
For example, I have to book my own travel for a lot of the conferences, usually this means
flights and accommodation. I tried a travel agent for this, but I found a lot of the
complications were not around the actual booking process, but coordinating with everyone (my
family included) which times/days work best, am I bringing the family, am I going to do customer
visits, which customers might want to see me, when works for them etc. Also since I&amp;rsquo;m
travelling from Seville, we do have an airport but I&amp;rsquo;m very limited for flight choices, which
always bites me even though it&amp;rsquo;s five years since I was spoiled by living in London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are the advocates organised at JetBrains?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was at MongoDB, the Advocates were engineers who spent most of
their time working on language drivers for the database and some of their time blogging and
speaking at conferences.  At JetBrains, the Advocate position is a full time job doing the
advocacy stuff. We don&amp;rsquo;t report to engineering, we don&amp;rsquo;t report to marketing, our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/hadi-hariri-b0368a83/&#34;&gt;Boss Person&lt;/a&gt; reports directly to the CEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advocates all belong to the same team, but each advocate has their own product(s) and
specialties.  In terms of co-ordinating what we&amp;rsquo;re actually going to work on, we talk to the PMMs
 (Product Marketing Managers) for our product and they&amp;rsquo;ll let us know what they need from us.
 Each PMM and each product is different, so they have different interests/focuses/plans.  With
 IntelliJ IDEA I spend quite a lot of time working with the PMM on each of the 3 releases a year,
 and most of the rest of the content is driven by me: it&amp;rsquo;s either connected to something else I&amp;rsquo;m
  working on (like one of my conference talks) or a Java release or something. Working in this
  way is quite familiar if you&amp;rsquo;ve been a consultant: in this model, the PMM is basically my
  customer and not my manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physically, our team is almost entirely remote. The JetBrains development teams are based in
Munich and St Petersburg, and there&amp;rsquo;s an office in Prague, so those of us on a
European timezone have an easier time of it. Our American team members tend to be dragged out of
 bed earlier than they would probably like in order to dial in to meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do I still code?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes and no. I don&amp;rsquo;t write enterprise code any more, and I don&amp;rsquo;t write code that goes into the
IntelliJ IDEA codebase.  I do, however, spend a good chunk of the year creating projects that
demonstrate particular things, and live-coding within these projects.  I also occasionally still
contribute to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/morphia&#34;&gt;Morphia&lt;/a&gt;, although mostly I use that as an
example code base to demo various things
- I love the Morphia code because it&amp;rsquo;s real lived-in code that is very similar to the sort of
code that real developers will be working with, it&amp;rsquo;s not just a nice clean toy project that bears
 zero resemblance to real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a weekly basis I don&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time coding, but every now and then I will devote a day
or two (or sometimes a week or two) to playing with something to scratch that itch.  This is
often used in blog posts or demos but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s enough just to learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other members of my team spend more time coding, either on open source projects, on bots for
Slack, on creating tutorial code, on plugins for IntelliJ platform IDEs, etc. I probably code
less than any of the others and I would like to change that this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I need to learn on the job?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been doing advocacy before I got to JetBrains, but there were still plenty of things I
needed to learn or level-up when I got here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screencasts: I had zero experience here, and I struggled to begin with. But then the whole
team had a number of discussions about how we did them. At first I was scared to talk about
didn&amp;rsquo;t know or what I was struggling with, but I found that when I opened up (both on Slack and
during one of our annual actual-face-to-face get togethers) about my pain points, I found a)
lots of the others struggle too and b) some people had answers that worked for me.  Also c)
turned out I knew things other people didn&amp;rsquo;t know, and that gave me a big confidence boost. A
lot of this is now documented on Confluence, so new people won&amp;rsquo;t have to struggle as much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webinars: I&amp;rsquo;d done two at MongoDB and I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like them.  For the first year at
JetBrains I still didn&amp;rsquo;t really like them, but we gather feedback from attendees and on the
whole people liked my webinars, and those that didn&amp;rsquo;t usually gave constructive feedback, so I
gained confidence and I think I&amp;rsquo;ve improved in this area too.  Also, it became clear I
absolutely had to pay a lot more for my home internet connection, since the major complaint was
always that my sound would frequently cut out or get out of sync. Now I have faster internet and
it&amp;rsquo;s made my (work) life all round much better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self management: I&amp;rsquo;ve worked a lot at &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; enterprises, where there&amp;rsquo;s a clear chain of
command.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked for consultancies, where customers have clear expectations of you.
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked at startups, at one of which my manager liked to micromanage everyone, down to the
lines of code they wrote. JetBrains is not like any of those.  It is genuinely a flat
organisation (as I mentioned above, there&amp;rsquo;s very little management between me and the head boss
person), and people are given the freedom to work on what they want to, more or less however
they want to, you&amp;rsquo;re trusted to get on with your job.  This can be quite a change if you&amp;rsquo;re used
to formal management. It&amp;rsquo;s both a good thing and a challenge if you&amp;rsquo;re remote - there&amp;rsquo;s no
central person to contact regarding&amp;hellip; pretty much anything, which can be strange, but on the
plus side you get to locate and talk to lots of individuals about what they work on and what
they care about.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much travel is involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 5 years of doing advocacy I have been to quite a lot of conferences.  Every year I
say I&amp;rsquo;ll do less, and every year I end up doing much more than I expected. Last year I &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo;
did 7 events, and I was unable fly/on maternity leave for nearly 3 months.  That&amp;rsquo;s slightly more
than the one-every-other-month I wanted to do, but quite a bit less than previous years.  This year
I&amp;rsquo;m currently signed up for only two conferences, I expect that to at least double by the end of
the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everyone travels as much as me though, Hadi and I probably travel more than any of the
others.  Advocacy doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be spending your whole life racking up air miles, and at
JetBrains how much travel you do is entirely up to you. I choose which conferences to submit to,
I choose which ones to go to when I&amp;rsquo;ve been invited. I can ask for guidance on which ones may be
valuable to JetBrains, but ultimately the decision to travel is mine (now all the conference
organisers who I&amp;rsquo;ve said &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to probably feel aggrieved I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go to theirs - I&amp;rsquo;m so
sorry, but I won&amp;rsquo;t spend my whole life on a plane. Or, more likely, sat in the lounge in
Madrid/Barcelona/London/Amsterdam/Paris waiting for a connecting flight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect our technical writers won&amp;rsquo;t have to travel at all, except perhaps occasionally to the
office to connect with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s it like working remotely?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit everyone.  And there&amp;rsquo;s a skill to it too.  I tend to like to work
 10ish-6ish because if I don&amp;rsquo;t work normal office hours I&amp;rsquo;m worried I won&amp;rsquo;t be doing enough. I
 also track how much time I spend on things, mostly to see where all my time is spent on those
 weeks where I feel like I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JetBrains uses Slack a lot, so us remote people do have a direct line to what&amp;rsquo;s going on, even
into the teams that are all sat together in an office.  The Developer Advocates have our own
Slack channel, of course, and that tends to be full of &amp;ldquo;witty banter&amp;rdquo; / water cooler conversation.
It&amp;rsquo;s also the first place I go to ask questions about anything, and I&amp;rsquo;m no longer scared of
looking stupid if I ask a &amp;ldquo;dumb&amp;rdquo; question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;/post/adjusting_to_working_remotely&#34;&gt;worked remotely in the past&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s better here than
other places because JetBrains
understands there are remote workers and that we have rights and needs. It&amp;rsquo;s also good for me
because I&amp;rsquo;m in Europe, so although I&amp;rsquo;m physically separate at least I don&amp;rsquo;t have the
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/tales_from_the_other_side_confessions_of_an_offshore_resource/&#34;&gt;timezone problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working remotely is great for flexibility, of course.  And although I do try to work 10-6ish, in
my office upstairs where the children can&amp;rsquo;t get to me, I am around if one of them needs me
immediately. I also don&amp;rsquo;t have a commute, so my hours are a lot shorter than if I worked (for
example) in London. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe I could have gone back to work after just 4 months of
maternity leave if I had to work in an office - I&amp;rsquo;m still breastfeeding and this would have been
impossible if I didn&amp;rsquo;t work from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this has its pros and cons, working at home also comes with distractions (although it&amp;rsquo;s
 nice to be able to get the laundry done throughout the week rather than have to do it all at the
  weekend). Pros: a good excuse for a nice computer and exactly the desk / chair / office setup
  you want; close to the family and much more available than in an office. Cons: can be quite
  isolated, can be easily distracted, can be quite noisy (currently both the 5-month-old and the
  two-year-old are crying: is OK to be writing a blog now, would be a terrible time to record a
  screencast).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote working is a &lt;a href=&#34;/post/adjusting_to_working_remotely&#34;&gt;big topic of its own&lt;/a&gt;.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve done it before, you know the deal.  And
JetBrains is better than most places because they recognise us as real workers. But also probably
 because the whole team is remote, so it&amp;rsquo;s not just one or two people cut off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re in the process of working on an employee handbook which will help us remote people a lot
too, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of knowledge stored in people&amp;rsquo;s brains that isn&amp;rsquo;t documented anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the team like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a dozen or so advocates on the team, all with different technology backgrounds and
covering different tools.  Hadi and Svetlana cover Kotlin, which also tends to overlap with
IntelliJ IDEA. I do IntelliJ IDEA (I guess I&amp;rsquo;m the main IDEA advocate, I do all the release
material etc) and I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who really does Upsource, and have so far been nearly 100%
Java-the-language. Anton does TeamCity and because he&amp;rsquo;s Java &amp;amp; Kotlin there&amp;rsquo;s some overlap there
with IntelliJ IDEA.  Other team members cover C++, Python, Go, .NET, Web technologies (this last
is an area we&amp;rsquo;re looking for specific expertise) and related tools (Resharper, Rider, GoLand,
CLion, PyCharm, WebStorm) and I have probably forgotten a load of them too. I see us as
individuals doing a similar job but with surprisingly little overlap. This is one reason being
remote actually works for us, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to co-ordinate much. But we are trying to get better
at reusing stuff between tools, and/or taking other people&amp;rsquo;s ideas and content and reworking it
for our communities (for example, I stole a load of Paul&amp;rsquo;s PyCharm
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DriveToDevelop&#34;&gt;tip tweets&lt;/a&gt; and did them for
IntelliJ IDEA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average age of the team is somewhere up in the late thirties.  I myself am just about to
cross into the 40s - eeeek!  We&amp;rsquo;re all experienced developers with an interest in our
technologies and communities.  We&amp;rsquo;re laid back and passionate, which sounds like a weird
combination but works
well for us. There&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as a stupid question in our team, and even though we don&amp;rsquo;t
work super closely on everything, we all support each other and do our best to make the team
happy and productive.  We definitely have room for improvement for working together (Gary and I
had fun recording our &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/o-2fvj7GsOQ&#34;&gt;series of Git videos&lt;/a&gt; but we haven&amp;rsquo;t managed
 to do anything similar since)
but it&amp;rsquo;s not because we don&amp;rsquo;t want to work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the good parts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being remote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picking my own code projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning new technologies and tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where I live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the bad parts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being remote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not having enough time to code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning new technologies and tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep.  The plus sides are also the downsides.  I probably don&amp;rsquo;t have to explain why, but if anyone
 is interested in the specifics drop a note in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are we looking for in a developer advocate / technical writer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was all sparked by our need to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/company/jobs/&#34;&gt;hire a couple of people&lt;/a&gt;, and wanting to be really transparent
 about what the role was like, ideally to attract people who might not have considered this role
 for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JetBrains is currently
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/company/jobs/&#34;&gt;hiring a bunch of people&lt;/a&gt;, but the two roles that
sparked this whole
conversation are a Web Technologies Developer Advocate and an Engineering Technical Writer. I&amp;rsquo;m
not the one making the hiring decisions, and on top of that there&amp;rsquo;s no real hard and fast rules
about what makes a good hire into these roles, but I think these things are interesting to
us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally you will have at least 10 years of experience as a developer. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to have
been an architect/tech lead or other &amp;ldquo;senior&amp;rdquo; role, but you do need to have a very good
understanding of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be a developer, what the pain points are for people in this
role, how developers use technology and how they learn it.  In our
writing / presentations / screencasts we try to present information in a way that makes
developers awesome at their jobs (see Kathy Sierra&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2EdyIOH&#34;&gt;Badass: Making Users Awesome&lt;/a&gt;), which means our content is usually
pretty technical and targeted at developers.  Having a good chunk of experience as a developer in
the real working world makes this substantially easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You use our tools. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s possible for anyone to learn on the job.  As developers this is
pretty much all we do.  But it&amp;rsquo;s going to be much easier for you to talk about how our tools make
developer&amp;rsquo;s lives easier / improve people&amp;rsquo;s productivity if you&amp;rsquo;ve actually used the tools in
real life,
have really felt their benefits, and have a good enough understanding of how to use
them to look like a power user (at least in the context you&amp;rsquo;ll be showing them). You don&amp;rsquo;t have
to have used all of our tools all of the time, but to be a developer advocate of a particular
IDE, you really should have used that IDE to code in the day job and have used it as more than
just a text editor&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally you&amp;rsquo;ll have some public profile that demonstrates you are not only interested in some
technology community (ideally the one we&amp;rsquo;re hiring for, e.g. web technologies) but are active in
that community.  We&amp;rsquo;re not looking for Rock Star Ninja Fully-Established Famous Developers.  But
this role is very much about being visible to developers, so it would be nice to see that you are
capable of interacting with other techies in a community.  What do I mean by this? I mean you
don&amp;rsquo;t have to have tens of thousands of followers on Twitter &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; thousands of points on
StackOverflow &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; have been speaking at conferences for years &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; be the leader of a user
group &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; have an established blog &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; have written a book.
What we would like to see though is maybe one (or more) of the following (there may be other
types of public (or public-ish) activity which is just as good.  The key point is that you are
involved in your community in some way&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have presented at a conference or user group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active involvement in User Group(s) - e.g. organiser, regular presenter, active on mailing
list etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a technical blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a profile on StackOverflow which demonstrates the ability to provide valuable answers to
questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a GitHub (or similar) profile which showcases involvement in open source code and/or has
demo projects / code that other developers have found useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a Twitter profile that shows an interest in relevant technologies, and that you post
content that&amp;rsquo;s valuable to other developers (e.g. re-tweeting/linking to interesting content)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Related to point three, you have to be able to demonstrate truly excellent communication
skills.  I have been involved in hiring developers at all sorts of organisations, and
communication skills is always seen as an important part of the role.  But for a role like this,
the job is almost entirely about communicating to people: to developers / architects / even
management about why and how to use our tools, and between you and the product marketing managers
for
the tool you&amp;rsquo;re the advocate for (more on that above).  Add to that the fact that we are
largely remote, it&amp;rsquo;s that much more difficult both to express what we mean to our colleagues and
to get a feel for what our colleagues are trying to tell us. You need to be able to communicate
potentially very technical ideas to other techies, you may need to be able to understand process
and talk about how a tool fits into a process (or what process works for a tool set), you need to
be able to work out with potentially multiple stakeholders what your priorities are and talk
honestly to set expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ability to be self-managed.  We&amp;rsquo;re experienced people who are grown up enough to make our own
decisions.  We manage our own priorities, with input from stakeholders. We can ping the Boss Person
to ask for help, opinions, input, and he&amp;rsquo;s always, always there to help unblock us, give us
advice, point us to the right place/person.  He will NOT be going through our backlog and
prioritising work for us, setting deadlines, or demanding anything from us. Our job is to keep
users, customers, and the product owners happy, and we&amp;rsquo;re trusted to get on with that with the
full support of the team and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to women.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, so, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to do this because I hate trying to suggest that different
genders have different needs by singling out a particular gender. I also have found that my
advice &amp;ldquo;for women&amp;rdquo; works really well for almost everyone anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do very specifically want to talk to &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; if you are a woman developer (or other minority,
 but I can only speak from my experience of being a woman) and are even vaguely interested in
 developer advocacy as a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you maybe could do this, but you&amp;rsquo;re not ready yet, you probably are ready. For
every time you&amp;rsquo;ve thought you couldn&amp;rsquo;t present at a conference, think of those talks you&amp;rsquo;ve seen
where you&amp;rsquo;ve though &amp;ldquo;I could do that. I could do better than that&amp;rdquo;. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be
perfect straight away and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be better than everyone immediately. You simply
have to be good enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You already have the skills you need for managing the social media side of this job.  I had an
excellent question last week on Twitter about how I handle the fact that my Twitter feed is
effectively a public representation of JetBrains as a company. And I realised I don&amp;rsquo;t freak out
about this - partly because JetBrains is really cool about &amp;ldquo;the voice&amp;rdquo; of the company and is
happy to have us just being ourselves, but mostly because as a woman, particularly a woman
developer, I am already super-conscious of what I post, how I word things, how I appear on
social media. Doing this as a job required almost zero adjustment for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My experience in the Java/JVM community has shown me being a woman is a massive advantage for
things like getting in to speak at conferences.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the programme committee for a
couple of conferences, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the CFPs generally dominated by submissions from men. We&amp;rsquo;ve
actively looked for those from women and generally said &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to them unless there was a
compelling reason not to.  You will often get emails from conference organisers saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d
really love for you to submit to this conference because we don&amp;rsquo;t have enough women speakers&amp;rdquo;,
and while that particular approach makes me roll my eyes (what, you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the
content, you just care about having a woman&amp;rsquo;s face somewhere on your website?) it is something you
can use to your advantage. And to be fair, they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t invite you if you were crap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re worried about being taken seriously as a developer when you&amp;rsquo;re a woman, I can tell
you from my own personal experience that being semi-famous in this space has reduced the number
of &amp;ldquo;are you a real developer?&amp;rdquo; questions at conferences and events to zero. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got
&amp;ldquo;speaker&amp;rdquo; on your lanyard, if you&amp;rsquo;ve just given a live demo showing you can code, you no longer
have to prove yourself to anyone, it&amp;rsquo;s out there for everyone to see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to draw attention to this side of things because I don&amp;rsquo;t want you to worry about
it if you hadn&amp;rsquo;t already thought about it, but it&amp;rsquo;s something that I was scared of right at the
beginning: I was worried I might get shit over Twitter or on the blog for being a woman.  So far
(fingers crossed) I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the sort of thing I was afraid of. I do get mansplained at
sometimes, and I do have to respond to idiots on Twitter.  But a) I see my (white, male)
colleagues suffering the same thing all the time and b) my team, JetBrains and even my Twitter
followers etc have my back.  I have a support network.  The fear is still real though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are more of us doing this job, there will be fewer people looking at the single woman
developer thinking she represents all women developers.  If half a dozen women&amp;rsquo;s voices are out
there, it becomes clearer we don&amp;rsquo;t all want the same things or work the same way, And That&amp;rsquo;s OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a woman developer and are considering applying for this role, I urge you to please
apply.  And if you have any questions, queries, doubts etc, please do contact me directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d really love to see more applications from women developers. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say we discourage
or dislike applications from men or that we&amp;rsquo;ll reject you if you&amp;rsquo;re not female, but if you are a
woman developer and are even marginally interested in this role, please, please go for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s not generous at all, it&amp;rsquo;s totally self-serving for JetBrains since we&amp;rsquo;re trying
 to hire
developer advocates and technical writers&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; I was a power user of IntelliJ IDEA, and I had done live coding demos with it in the
past when I joined, and that was probably a large part of why I was hired.  However, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used
Upsource or TeamCity before I came to JetBrains and I have done advocacy for both
tools, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert in all JB tools. But the fact that I
had used other code review tools before and felt a LOT of pain while using them made Upsource a
joy to advocate, since it fixes so many of the pain points I&amp;rsquo;ve felt with other tools.  And the
fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in Continuous Delivery environments, and had experience with Jenkins, also
made it easier for me to see where TeamCity fits, what it does well, why you might use it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Now I have children I seriously appreciate that physically getting out to user group
events or
conferences is very challenging for developers who are parents.  That&amp;rsquo;s why this list also includes
things which are a little easier to do on what can laughably be called the &amp;ldquo;spare time&amp;rdquo; when the
children aren&amp;rsquo;t demanding 100% of your attention, e.g. blogs/Twitter/StackOverflow/mailing lists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
