<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/upcoming_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/upcoming_events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the list in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/public_appearances/&#34;&gt;talks section&lt;/a&gt; of my blog covers past presentations,
this page should list my confirmed upcoming events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio and Abstracts</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/abstracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/abstracts/</guid>
      <description>Bio Trisha has developed Java applications for a range of industries, including finance, manufacturing, software and non-profit, for companies of all sizes. She has expertise in Java high performance systems, is passionate about enabling developer productivity, and dabbles with Open Source development. Trisha is a leader of the Sevilla Java User Group and a Java Champion, she believes healthy communities and sharing ideas help us to learn from mistakes and build on successes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Credentials</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/speaking_credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/speaking_credentials/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken at JavaOne (2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, 2016) and have received the JavaOne Rock Star award several times. I&amp;rsquo;ve presented many times at QCon London, and other notable conferences include QCon New York, Devoxx BE and UK, JavaZone, CraftConf OSCON and various GOTO conferences. I also regularly present to user groups around the world, and am a leader of the Sevilla Java User Group.
See my full list of past presentations here (includes links to videos).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events 2014</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I updated you on my travel plans, so now I&amp;rsquo;ve had some more conferences confirmed,
I thought I would pass the information on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla MUG March Madness</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_mug_march_madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_mug_march_madness/</guid>
      <description>Last night the Sevilla MUG had our March Madness event. This was our largest event yet, with 36 people signed up. Although the aim of March Madness is to have a MongoDB Engineer at all the user groups this month, that&amp;rsquo;s not such a big deal for us as I live here, so this was also the first event where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the main attraction - Javier gave a really great talk about the lessons learnt at SocialBro after using MongoDB in production for the last couple of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First presentation at the Virtual JUG!</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the privilege of presenting the very first session for vJUG, a new virtual Java User Group that allows us to span geographies when sharing talks and stories. I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in the vJUG idea, especially now I&amp;rsquo;m not in London - if we can find good ways to share knowledge without having to travel, that will help us reach people who don&amp;rsquo;t normally go to conferences or don&amp;rsquo;t have a local user group to go to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trisha&#39;s World Tour 2013</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/trishas_world_tour_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/trishas_world_tour_2013/</guid>
      <description>Quick update on my scheduled events this year. &amp;nbsp;Please feel free to suggest your MUG or JUG or other tech group as somewhere for me to visit on this Grand World Tour if I&amp;rsquo;m in your city.

17-21st June - In New York - woohoo! &amp;nbsp;Getting to know Justin Lee, the newest member of the Java team, doing some pair&amp;nbsp;programming&amp;nbsp;(hopefully) and meeting people at the MongoDB Masters&amp;rsquo; Summit on Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 is looking a lot busier than I planned...</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/2013_is_looking_a_lot_busier_than_i_planned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/2013_is_looking_a_lot_busier_than_i_planned/</guid>
      <description>So, despite promising myself that I would only do one event a month for the rest of this year, looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a bit busier than that.

In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what I&amp;rsquo;m up to (or, even better, hoping to see me talk or meet me), here are my confirmed engagements:
15-17 May - GeeCon, Poland
18-20 June - GOTO Amsterdam - whole day tutorial on the new (unfinished) MongoDB Java driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike and I debut our new Disruptor presentation</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/mike_and_i_debut_our_new_disruptor_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/mike_and_i_debut_our_new_disruptor_presentation/</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday&amp;nbsp;Mike and I unveiled our brand shiny new presentation: Understanding the Disruptor, a Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Hardcore Concurrency. &amp;nbsp;This was a preview of the talk we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing at JAX London on the 2nd November.
A video of the session is available, as are the slides. &amp;nbsp;I promise not to say &amp;ldquo;so&amp;rdquo; anywhere near as many times when I repeat my performance at JAX (is there anything more painful than watching yourself on video?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first public appearance</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_first_public_appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_first_public_appearance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finally moving up from working behind the scenes to actually doing a (short) presentation for the LJC. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be giving a lightning talk on Wednesday at the AWS Elastic Beanstalk event,&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;the JCP - what it is and what our election to the executive committee means. &amp;nbsp;Ben and Martin&amp;rsquo;s post&amp;nbsp;gives a little more background on the subject.
Another LMAX LJC member&amp;nbsp;Mike will also be giving a lightning talk, on Project Coin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>