<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Mentoring on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/mentoring/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be an Ambassador!</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/be_an_ambassador</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/be_an_ambassador</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how I keep banging on about attracting different types of people into programming? &amp;nbsp;You know how we say we need to get them young?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1yinSe4_orw/UZzXQoQZr8I/AAAAAAAALkY/HgxArcLwj1Q/s1600/mathematician.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1yinSe4_orw/UZzXQoQZr8I/AAAAAAAALkY/HgxArcLwj1Q/s320/mathematician.jpg&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Typical Mathematician?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;A little while back I decided to put my money where my mouth was, so I signed up to be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stemnet.org.uk/content/ambassadors&#34;&gt;STEM Ambassador&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;STEMNET is an organisation that aims to inspire children to go into Science, Technology, Engineering and Maths careers, and it does this by creating a network of mentors (people like you and me) and schools. &amp;nbsp;So schools can publicise the sorts of events they&amp;rsquo;re running, and find mentors in an appropriate field for this event.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was a STEM Ambassador years ago, when I worked at Ford STEMNET came there looking for people like the graduates to come and talk to kids - STEMNET likes to have a large proportion of their ambassadors close(ish) to the age of the kids, so they grab graduates working in large organisations and apprentices. &amp;nbsp;Those just starting out in their careers often think they don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot to offer as mentors, but they&amp;rsquo;re wrong - making that&amp;nbsp;transition&amp;nbsp;from education to work is a worrying thing for kids, so speaking to people who have recently done this is dead useful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--jyL0hdI850/UZzXQIWZAKI/AAAAAAAALkU/OaFVMinjJck/s1600/engineer.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--jyL0hdI850/UZzXQIWZAKI/AAAAAAAALkU/OaFVMinjJck/s320/engineer.jpg&#34; width=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Typical Engineer?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I cheated when I was an ambassador the first time - I volunteered at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shsb.org.uk/&#34;&gt;my old school&lt;/a&gt;, where my parents were also teachers, and helped teach &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tutor2u.net/business/ict/intro_what_is_ict.htm&#34;&gt;ICT&lt;/a&gt; to the boys in year 9. &amp;nbsp;It was eye-opening for me - ICT is not programming. &amp;nbsp;Tech-savvy kids were bored and the other kids didn&amp;rsquo;t really know why they needed to learn Powerpoint/Word/Excel. &amp;nbsp;Personally I thought the Powerpoint lessons were useful - I was working in a large organisation where we were expected to give internal presentations, and had never been taught how to use a presentation tool, despite having various NVQs in IT that taught me all I would ever need to know about Word and Excel (these were very useful qualifications and that knowledge was relevant for many years - and no, this is not sarcasm). &amp;nbsp;But teaching kids Powerpoint when they&amp;rsquo;re 13 is not useful. &amp;nbsp;By the time they get to use it their knowledge is rusty and out of date.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We were taught BASIC programming in my primary school. &amp;nbsp;And it was basic - &lt;code&gt;20 GOTO 10&lt;/code&gt; stuff. &amp;nbsp;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that hard. &amp;nbsp;I mean, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone, but it was fairly easy to get going, and you got the point of it - you told the computer what to do, and it did it. &amp;nbsp;I think that&amp;rsquo;s what has always appealed to me about programming (insert joke here about programmers preferring computers to people because they do what they&amp;rsquo;re told - if you&amp;rsquo;re not a programmer, then you really don&amp;rsquo;t know how much the computer can rebel against you ever damn step of the way, like a child. &amp;nbsp;A very stupid child). &amp;nbsp;I was really struck by Jason Gorman&amp;rsquo;s idea that learning programming was quite a lot like learning music, and he proposed a &lt;a href=&#34;http://codemanship.co.uk/parlezuml/blog/?postid=980&#34;&gt;grading system for programmers&lt;/a&gt; similar to that of music. &amp;nbsp;I can see the similarities between music and programming, certainly in my background - in primary school we were given introductory lessons in both music and programming as a whole class, and those who showed an interest or aptitude for either subject took up lessons at lunchtimes or evenings. &amp;nbsp;With music, that&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward, many schools have access to at least one music teacher for the usual instruments. &amp;nbsp;For programming, this is much more difficult. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s usually a keen teacher who&amp;rsquo;s self taught leading this class. &amp;nbsp;Which is great, but many schools do not have this keen teacher. &amp;nbsp;And this keen teacher, should he or she exist, is looking for someone to learn off as well, just like the rest of us. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-PiUd3wctHFo/UZzXRf_c6lI/AAAAAAAALkk/csUH7zuafck/s1600/scientist.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-PiUd3wctHFo/UZzXRf_c6lI/AAAAAAAALkk/csUH7zuafck/s320/scientist.jpg&#34; width=&#34;267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Typical Scientist?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;i&gt;We&lt;/i&gt; are the people the schools are looking for. &amp;nbsp;We have the experience - years of it. &amp;nbsp;We have the context for that awkward question &amp;ldquo;but when am I ever going to use this stuff?&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;We can show them why it&amp;rsquo;s fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But what&amp;rsquo;s in it for us? &amp;nbsp;Well, it looks great on your CV, of course, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get to network and meet with other professionals, including those in different but overlapping fields. &amp;nbsp;Kids also have really interesting approaches to problems. &amp;nbsp;It has been known for groups of children to provide novel answers to problems that have stumped professionals. &amp;nbsp;And doing something like this is really great for your confidence - if you can speak about what you do in front of a group of children, all staring at you, then speaking in meetings or conferences becomes infinitely easier. &amp;nbsp;I honestly believe that all the times I spent in a classroom helping out one or other of my parents is the reason I&amp;rsquo;m more relaxed speaking at conferences than I ever thought I would be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-klM3xjs-A6w/UZzXR8VKcwI/AAAAAAAALko/cIuVUmMTUkk/s1600/geek.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-klM3xjs-A6w/UZzXR8VKcwI/AAAAAAAALko/cIuVUmMTUkk/s320/geek.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Typical Technologist?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Sadly, I let my Ambassador status lapse when I got a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; job in London, it became so much more difficult to create the time to go into a school, since clearly it needs to be during work hours. &amp;nbsp;But nearly ten years later, after talk of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/4KIDS/Home&#34;&gt;Devoxx4Kids&lt;/a&gt; and a bunch of other initiatives to get kids coding, I decided I needed at least to get my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/disclosure-barring-service-check/overview&#34;&gt;CRB (now DBS) checks&lt;/a&gt; done so I could work with children if the opportunity came up. &amp;nbsp;If you sign up as an&amp;nbsp;ambassador, STEMNET will sort this out for you for free, which is one of the main reasons I chose to sign up with them again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another great thing is the induction - they&amp;rsquo;re not going to let you loose with the kids without&amp;nbsp;providing&amp;nbsp;a bit of help and guidance. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s only a couple of hours out of your day, and, if nothing else, gives you an opportunity to meet interesting people in other STEM jobs. &amp;nbsp;On my induction there were surprisingly few IT people (maybe 3-4). &amp;nbsp;There were various apprentices, structural engineers, dentists, ex-teachers, PhD students and&amp;hellip; oh I&amp;rsquo;ve totally forgotten what everyone did, but it was interesting and sciencey. &amp;nbsp;And about half of the inductees were women, which enormously surprised me. &amp;nbsp;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if programming is lagging well behind the other STEM jobs in terms of women doing the role, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think you can draw a conclusion based on a group of people who either chose to be mentors or were pushed gently (or not so gently) in that direction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RaFaSj1Hmp8/UZzTIAf5HOI/AAAAAAAALkE/U2662Y01VFE/s1600/2013-05-21+13.56.09.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RaFaSj1Hmp8/UZzTIAf5HOI/AAAAAAAALkE/U2662Y01VFE/s640/2013-05-21+13.56.09.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The induction covers stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about here - like why you should do this and what teachers, students and ambassadors get out of it - and some basic dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts for working with kids. &amp;nbsp;Nothing too scary, and even though I&amp;rsquo;ve done this before I found it useful and made me more keen to be involved. &amp;nbsp;The minimal commitment is one event a year, and this can even be something you&amp;rsquo;ve arranged yourself (like going into your own kids&amp;rsquo; school). &amp;nbsp;And although I&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for the London area, it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily geographically constrained - one of the ideas I liked the most is taking kids for a Skype tour around your office, showing where you work, how you work, etc. &amp;nbsp;I think that will help blow away some of the preconceptions around programmers anti-socially sitting in their own rooms hacking out lines of code, for example.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll notice the rather lovely drawings littering this post. &amp;nbsp;The first exercise we did in the induction was to draw a stereotypical scientist, technologist, engineer, and&amp;nbsp;mathematician. &amp;nbsp;The point of being an ambassador is to help combat these stereotypes, giving kids real role models to look to, people who can help them see what&amp;rsquo;s out there for them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These kids don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to be Bill Gates, Steve Jobs or Mark Zuckerberg.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some of them want to be just like you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Do and How Did You Get There?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/what_do_you_do_and_how_did_you_get_there</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/what_do_you_do_and_how_did_you_get_there</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&#34;http://careers.grad-dc.co.uk/2012/05/18/107/&#34;&gt;yet another interview&lt;/a&gt; with me is available, but this one is in written form. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s for the Graduate Developer Community, the aim is to show undergraduates and graduates what real techies jobs are like, and how people doing them they got there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s long, but if you know anyone just starting out their career who wants to get a feel for where they might want to go, please point them at it. &amp;nbsp;The site has a number of interviews with people in different roles so it&amp;rsquo;s quite a good way to showcase the diversity of what&amp;rsquo;s available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
