<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Hardware on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/hardware/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to the Surface Pro</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/surface_pro_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/surface_pro_3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, leaving MpngoDb also meant leaving my macbook air (i should hace thought this job moce through ,ore carefully).
so i had a tough decision to make - get a new macbpok, or try something else (or reclaim my personal macbook off mu boufriend,
but thst option conveniently slipped my mind, as who wants to upgrade to a 4 year old piece of hardware?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very very happy qirh the macbook air - in fact, i bought my persional one after thoughtworks foisted one onto me for my short twnure
there, and i became addicte tot tje way it felt for typing, to the easy of using the touchpad (and never feeling like i needed
an exrernal mouse), and, most of all, inloved that it was only marginally heavier tha na &amp;lsquo;arge bottle of water. I coild never go
back to anotjer portable computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until someone at the lonodn javabcommunity unconference showed me their Microsoft Surface. At first, I sneered - its windows, amd although
i actually rarher liked the Nokia Lumia i was given for being anRemarkable Woman, I wasnt reqlly sold  on New World
Windows. But then, i saw how tjin and light it was, and how nice the screem was.  And the keyboard was detachable,
and its a tablet. and a laptop. And it has a proper Wdinwos desktpp mode, for installing Real aplicatoons, its not just a Very Expensive
iPad competitor.  And then? The guy who owned the surface whipped out his stylus, and started drawing pn tje screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; im interestewd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This device has the capabolity to solve a problem ive been having, and have been trying to address a number o fways: i carry too much stuff around when
i travel. and i travel a lot.
  - I bring my laptop, so i csn code while im away, and for presenting from - i can present from the ipad
if it&amp;rsquo;s just slideware, but ive been giving this live demomwhich needs a rewl IDE.
 - I bring my ipad - orignally i thought inwould usenthis if i was at a conference and not presenting - i can take norew, wrire blog pots, stay up
 to date. Turnsnout i usually need rhe laptop too, if only becausen i was supposednto be writing code for tje day job so
 i needed rhe ide even if i was going to otjer sessions or waiting my turn tonpresent. I tried not bringing the ipad,
 but the batteryblife on tje laptop was arounf 3-4 hours, which barely cuts it on a european flight, if you include
 airportnwaiting time, and certainly doesnt lastna trqnsatlantic journey. so i use the ipad for watching stuff on planes
 and anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t need an ide, as the batteryblife is (or was, before tje ladt upgrade) much better. and saves precious pjone battery
  - if i have space, and tjink i might have time for a blog or notes, i&amp;rsquo;ll bring my bamboo tab&amp;rsquo;et.  i know i haven&amp;rsquo;t
  illustrsted my blognposts for quire a while, and very fww of my presentations have featured my pictures either, but
  I still optimisitically bring my bamboo tablet with me on many of my journies.  It&amp;rsquo;s not very heavy, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a
  big deal to bring it, but it;s just another piece of baggage (and another thing to plu in to the limited USB slots on
  the laptop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could have one device that:
 - Was slim and light
 - Lets me run IntelliJ IDEA
 - Can be presented from
 - Lets me easily sketch, preferably with Gimp or a similar tool
 - Has a decent battery life (needs to last for most of a transatlantic flight)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the optional benefits of
 - Being small enough that when the passenger in front of me smushes his seat back into my space it doesn&amp;rsquo;t snap the
 laptop screen
 - Being light enough/tablety enough that I can use it on take off and landing (do you know how much valuable working
 time is lost on each flight??)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then my life would be simpler, and Simpler Is Better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I discovered the Surface, I very nearly downgraded to the smaller Macbook Air to meet those last two criteria, but
I was really worried about losing the screen real estate. I hate coding through a letter box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the Surface intrigued me.  Apart from being Windows, it might meet all my criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Taking the Plunge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played with it a bit in the pub that nivht, and I tried it in fnac to see if i hared the feel of the kayboard.  At the end of
my time at MongoDB, I switched to working on my (Windows) gaming PC, to see if lsoing all the familiar keyboard shortcuts
was a problem, to remember how to use Home and End keys instead of Fn and arrows (for some reason, text navigation on
the Mac was one of my deciding factors for switching to it in the first place), and to see if I remembered how to run things on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the airport (woah, you&amp;rsquo;d never think to find me at one of &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt;), Dixons was doing a deal on the Surface, and also
offering a 60 day return-it-if-you-don&amp;rsquo;t-like-it guarantee.  I took the chance, and I bought the i5, 8Gb, 256 Gb option
(the memory was a bonus, but I always ran out of space on the iPad and the 128Gb Air if I put even half a dozen TV episodes
on there for watching on the plane).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use it as my primary coding machine for my new job, and to evaluate its performance. I&amp;rsquo;d send it back to
Dixons if I decided I wanted to stick with a Mac (by the way, I&amp;rsquo;d had the Surface just a few hours before my iPad went
missing, it seems &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; in the house who is not me decided that the iPad was decidedly his now, regardless of the outcome
of the experiment.  I dunno, some people&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Insert picture of a chart of your feelings towards the Surface)
The first week using the thing was pretty rough, and I was pretty certain during that time that I would be wrapping it up
and sending it back.  But because I thought I would be doing this (and at the point it looked like a refurbished Macbook Air
was definitely in my future, for free), I had nothing to lose by really trying to use the thing in anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a new job was a good excuse for all the setup too, I think making the switch while I was mid-flow in deliverables
would have been hard, but since I had new software to install and new credentials to set up anyway, the setup cost was
acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 1:
Bear in mind that during this time I&amp;rsquo;m using the Surface as a desktop replacement - I&amp;rsquo;ve got it in my home office and
I want to use it with a second monitor. I&amp;rsquo;m used to having the bluetooth keyboard and touchpad for the mac, and having the
laptop on a riser (insert photo of all the technology from that first day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1:
 - I&amp;rsquo;m surprised that the macbook keyboard and touchpad actually do work with the surface.  Great! I can use my old setup!  Only&amp;hellip;
 - &amp;hellip;yes the machine sees the trackpad, but none of the gestures work, not even scrolling.  However, I do find some drivers from
 somewhere that give me scrolling support, except&amp;hellip;
 - &amp;hellip;the trackpad scrolls the wrong way. Not just the wrong way for what I&amp;rsquo;m used to on the mac (and many of us remember that
 day we had to switch directions when Apple inflicted that update on us, only now we wonder how we ever managed the old way), but
 the wrong way for the touchpad on the surface.  So I scroll in one direction on the mac trackpad, and in the opposite direction on
 the surface trackpad.  This is going to mess with my mind
 - The mac touchpad now supports a light tap as a click, instead of having to press to click - if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used the mac touchpad, you
 might not know what I mean, as the tap-click is quite common on other laptops. But it was FAR too sensitive, and I kept clicking on
 everything.  Drove me NUTS
 - Apple keyboard works.  There&amp;rsquo;s a pleasant surprise!
 - The resolution on my external monitor looks a bit crappy actually - the screen manages to look jagged and blurry at
 the same time.  The experience on the second monitor (insert specs here) was definitely better on the Macbook
 - On the first day, I wrote a note that says &amp;ldquo;function keys don&amp;rsquo;t work, or don&amp;rsquo;t do what they say on the tin&amp;rdquo;. Reading it
  now I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what that means, as I haven&amp;rsquo;t really stumbled over it since then.  But I just tried pressing the ones that
  look like screen brightness, and they opened new tabs in Chrome. Which wasn&amp;rsquo;t even open.  That was unexpected. I also miss having
  volume on the function keys, they were pretty much the only ones I used on the mac. I think I set the defaults of the Surface
  to use the fucntion keys as F-keys (not search or brightness or whatever) so my shortcuts in IntelliJ worked correctly,
  but I can&amp;rsquo;t swear to that. I seem to remember doing that on the macbook too.
 - Obviously adjusting to the Ctrl/Cmd differences, particularly in my IntelliJ shortcuts, was (and still is) tripping me up. But I&amp;rsquo;m
 OK with this, as even 2 years after switching from Linux to mac for full-time development, I still kept getting the mac shortcuts wrong
 anyway
 - I have a note that says &amp;ldquo;function key doesn&amp;rsquo;t do home/end&amp;rdquo; - this is definitely not true right now, so either I
 changed a setting, or this applies to using the mac keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2:
 - I think I disabled a click setting for the laptop touchpad, there&amp;rsquo;s no need for a tap-to-click when you also have
 a click on the touchpad.
 - This right-click thing on the touchpad drives me MENTAL. For whatever reason, I tend to use the lower right part of the
 touchpad to click, and since the whole right side of the touchpad seems to be mapped to right-click, it means I&amp;rsquo;m almsot
 always right clicking on things instead of clicking. I looked for a way to turn this off, but it appears there is none.
 On the mac, I never really used this two-fingers-is-a-right-click feature, because I have a freakishly long middle finger and
 it was uncomfortable, so I tended to hold down alt to get a right-click. I have wished &lt;strong&gt;every day&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve used the surface for
 an Alt=right-click feature.
 - Skype didn&amp;rsquo;t work properly. Honestly I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the problems, but I know it was for calls not chat. It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous
 that the windows version is worse than the OSX version, given who owns it, but hey. I have used Skype several times, sometimes
 to call via Skype, sometimes to call a UK phone line. The UK phone call was horrible, but then it always was on the mac too,
 the other end can never hear me, and on both the surface and the phone it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to correctly transmit keypad presses,
 i.e. when the voicejail system on the other end says &amp;ldquo;press 3 to attempt to speak to a real human&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3:
 - The pen is really nice.  And I&amp;rsquo;ve played with the handwriting recognition in Evernote, which is surprisingly good.  Actually, I might start
 using that rather than the screen keyboard - I started writing this post with the screen keyboard, and this is what I got:
&amp;gt;  I bring my ipad - orignally i thought inwould usenthis if i was at a conference and not presenting - i can take norew, wrire blog pots, stay up
   to date. Turnsnout i usually need rhe laptop too, if only becausen i was supposednto be writing code for tje day job so
   i needed rhe ide even if i was going to otjer sessions or waiting my turn tonpresent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the handwriting recognition is better than my finger positioning.
 - The screen keyboard is actually pretty nice, and the noises it makes are really cute. Took me a while to work out that
 you don&amp;rsquo;t get any autocorrect or automatic sentence capitlisation in Desktop mode, but you do if you&amp;rsquo;re running as a tablet.
 What this basically means is I&amp;rsquo;ve had to install two versions of evernote - the Windows desltop version, because it&amp;rsquo;s good and
 does everything I want, and &amp;ldquo;Evernote touch&amp;rdquo;, the tablet/phone version, which I had originally installed by accident and immediately
 uninstalled and replaced with the desktop app, as the tablet app seems to be missing pretty much everything, plus it looks
 completely difference, and I can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.  I re-installed it though, as if I&amp;rsquo;m going to write notes on-the-move
with the screen keyboard, I need to use the touch version so my horrible typing errors get fixed.
 - I expect to be able to scroll touching the screen in Evernote for desktop, but you can&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s bascially a mouse click. You
 can scroll in Evernote Touch though, presumably that&amp;rsquo;s been deisgned for it.
 - I struggle with the onscreen keyboard on this day, but I figure stuff out, including that there&amp;rsquo;s a different button that
 you have to press if you want the keyboard to not overlay the things you want to look at or do stuff with
  - Scrolling doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly in Tweetdeck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 4:
 - Honestly, did we really used to go to random websites to download software to install? It seems really fraught with danger.
 I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise how much I&amp;rsquo;d got used to the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has sounded more like a Technology Anonymous rant than a serious review of the surface. Ah well, if anyone can help me with any of
 my problems, I consider it a win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that drive me crazy:
 - The laptop touchpad:
   &amp;ndash; The scrolling doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work, and isn&amp;rsquo;t always smooth. I Often end up using the arrow keys
   &amp;ndash; The right click on the right side is &lt;em&gt;insanely&lt;/em&gt; annoying
   &amp;ndash; To be fair, I don&amp;rsquo;t think the surface has a particularly bad touchpad, I remember that pretty much all laptops before
   I used the macbook had horrible touchpads.  It&amp;rsquo;s probably pretty good compared to other laptops, it&amp;rsquo;s just really nowhere
   near as good as the apple touchpads - both the one built into the laptop and the magic external one are excellent.
 - The mac touchpad.  The backwards scrolling and &lt;em&gt;extreme&lt;/em&gt; click sensitivity was too much, and I stopped using it
 - Scrolling doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly in Tweetdeck - if I hover over a column and scroll with the touchpad, it scrolls the column
 to the left.  Very, very annoying.  I end up using the arrow keys a LOT for scrolling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromises/sacrifices I can take (AKA stuff Microsoft could address to make the Surface and/or Win):
 - The resolution on the second monitor.  Hated it at first, have got used to it.
 - Keyboard is not backlit.  This is irritating, but not currently a showstopped. But I have yet to try and use it on
 an overnight flight yet - I always loved the backlit keyboard on the mac at those times
 - Remapping the keys.  As per Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s super useful blogpost, I&amp;rsquo;ve remapped the right Alt key to Ins just so
 my IntelliJ shortcuts don&amp;rsquo;t all have to be remapped
 - Having a touchscreen monitor, whether it&amp;rsquo;s because your screen is also a tablet, or because you have an actual touchscreen,
 means your screen &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; has fingerprints all over it.  Not cool for my OCD. But irritates me a lot less than expected.
 - I keep pressing Windows Key + E instead of Ctrl+E (on the mac it was Cmd+e, and the cmd key is obviously in the same place as the windows
 key).  Thi is very irritating, but at some point my muscle memory will learn.
 - I have the Desktop and Tablet versions of some apps: Evernote (so I can use the proper version most of the time,
 but get the benefits of the cleverer screen keyboard in Evernote Touch) and Kindle (so I can use the Desktop
 version for opening books from Dropbox, and for searching, and all the other useful features from the desktop Kindle app
 that I used all the time on the mac, and the Tablet version so the font is actually visible when reading as a table, so
 the books are big enough icons to tap on with your finger).
 -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I miss about the mac:
 - Volume on function keys
 - Battery life indicator - time left in hours.  27% remaining is not too useful, I need to know how many hours that is.
 - The input box at the top of every help menu - I&amp;rsquo;m super lazy and used this all the time to type in the function I wanted to
 use, and OSX would highlight where in the menus this feature lived. IntelliJ has its Ctrl+Shift+A shortcut, which does
 something similar (only better), but for all other apps I end up hunting through menus for the thing I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that worked:
 - The macbook bluetooth keyboard. Sure, the keys are in a different place (espectially as my bluetooth keyboard is
 Spanish and I purposefully bought a UK keyboard for the Surface), but it does work. I just don&amp;rsquo;t use it as without
 a separate mouse or touchpad, I might as well use the surface keyboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I like
 - Once i got used to the very light touch that is the Surface keyboard, I think I prefer it.  It&amp;rsquo;s a nice feeling -
 kinda clicky, kinda squishy like laptop keyboards are, but such a short distance to push the keys down it actually feels
 very low effort, like your brain is able to talk to the computer with minimal resistance.
 - Windows Key + S opens up the search, which works like the apple spotlight (Cmd+Space). I thought I would really miss
 this feature, so I&amp;rsquo;m glad there&amp;rsquo;s an equivalent. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t taken long to retrain my muscle memory.
 - Honestly, getting a full Delete key back on the keyboard is surprisingly pleasing. Fn+Backspace has &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; annoyed
 me, especially in shortcuts in an IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that still need more testing
 - Battery life: Today I
   &amp;ndash; used the surface as a tablet and watched 40 minutes of video in the gym
   &amp;ndash; spent 20 minutes or so sketching (with the pen) an architecture diagram for my boyfriend while we waited in the aiport
   (yep, that&amp;rsquo;s the sort of relationship we have.  Poor boy.)
   &amp;ndash; have been using it for 90 minutes on the plane
   &amp;ndash; &amp;hellip;and I&amp;rsquo;m down to 17%.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty disapointed with this.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the specs are supposed to
   be, and I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain I could do more to save battery (for example it wasn&amp;rsquo;t in flight mode until I got it onto the plane,
   and the screen was at normal brightness until about 30 minutes ago when I realised I was under 30% battery).
   &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;d like to test how long it lasts on a flight from full charge, with some reasonable power-saving settings. But I&amp;rsquo;m worried
   it won&amp;rsquo;t take me all the way across the Atlantic, and with only a single toy, instead of the laptop/iPad combo, I have
   no backups for Things To Do when the power is out.
(2 hours into the flight and 7%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusions:
 - I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s a solid desktop replacement: the poor resolution on the second monitor, and the fact the second monitor
 totally throws off the pen use on the tablet make this more of a nice laptop than a great desktop replacement
 - Battery life is disappointing, but needs investigation
 - For travelling, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; this is going to be a great choice
 - And for encouraging creativity and different modes of working, it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic. I&amp;rsquo;ve sketched more in the last month than
 the last year, and switching from keyboard to touch screen to pen is really easy and allows you to work in different ways
  to traditional laptops or desktops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep the Surface (I think). The laptop/tablet combo, with the fantastic stylus support, is worth the sacrifices.
Although I prefer OSX overall as an OS, Apple has nothing to compete with this hardware right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
