<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Javaone12 on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone12/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: The Summary</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_summary</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_summary</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0-i_HcBbYEc/UG9JMFLgCxI/AAAAAAAALNk/Y-4DCaY6UHw/s1600/2012-10-01+07.37.51.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0-i_HcBbYEc/UG9JMFLgCxI/AAAAAAAALNk/Y-4DCaY6UHw/s640/2012-10-01+07.37.51.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;So, JavaOne.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4LX8X74MR1M/UG9HT1hdisI/AAAAAAAALMs/TWP67rS4B8Q/s1600/TaylorStCafe.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4LX8X74MR1M/UG9HT1hdisI/AAAAAAAALMs/TWP67rS4B8Q/s400/TaylorStCafe.png&#34; width=&#34;267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Taylor Street Cafe&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I&#39;m going to be controversial. &amp;nbsp;I think this was my favourite conference of this year. &amp;nbsp;I know that&#39;s not trendy, and that Oracle-bashing is still a popular pastime. &amp;nbsp;And I know I&#39;ve also made a big deal about how much fun it is to meet people who program in different languages. &amp;nbsp;But there is something very special about being surrounded by thousands of people from all around the world who use the same technology as you, some facing the same problems, some solving very different issues.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Maybe it&#39;s because since I first spoke at JavaOne last year I&#39;ve met a lot of people in this ecosystem - Oracle Java people, other conference organisers, Java User Group leaders, speakers and attendees from all sorts of places - and seeing many of them in one place is fun and makes you feel like you&#39;re &#34;home&#34;. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d be sat in the Taylor St Cafe area and people would sit down and hang out with me. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d be hiding somewhere trying to write a presentation and people would say Hi. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d be separated from the other LJC guys while I grabbed a glass of water and someone would stop to chat. &amp;nbsp;It was awesome. &amp;nbsp;I even managed to get a tiny bit of work done between socialising.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Personally, I have learnt very valuable lessons:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Doing two conferences back to back is exhausting. &amp;nbsp;If I do it ever again, I really need to optimise my travel between them (i.e. not fly from St Louis to London and then to San Francisco 48 hours later).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Especially if I have two conferences back to back, but almost definitely as a rule, it&#39;s best to have the materials for presentations complete before the conference. &amp;nbsp;I probably would have enjoyed myself even more, and definitely had a chance to see a lot more sessions, if I hadn&#39;t had one presentation to finish.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Presenting four sessions in one conference is extremely challenging. &amp;nbsp;Technically I only had two full-length presentations (the Disruptor presentation I&#39;ve done at OSCON/GOTO/QCon etc and my &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/javaone-problem-with-women-technical.html&#34;&gt;Technical Approach to Women&lt;/a&gt;, which was more like a very structured BOF), a short 20-minute talk and a panel. &amp;nbsp;But I think one full-length presentation and a couple of other bits is probably a much more sane amount. &amp;nbsp;Especially given 1) and 2) above.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;So I didn&#39;t get a chance to really see many sessions. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m sure the blogosphere will be full of good summaries of them, and they will be available for free via the schedule builder (audio and slides only).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There will be a bunch of other blog posts mentioning the inconvenience of having it in three hotels, the poor suitability of some of the rooms, the difficulty of sharing San Francisco with Oracle Open World, the mediocre food. &amp;nbsp;But you don&#39;t spend the money to fly halfway across the world to San Francisco for the crappy box lunches. &amp;nbsp;You fly here to meet - face-to-face - some of the people who created Java, those who are steering it now, and the community that continues to make it relevant and fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Highlights for me:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-x24hP1hzAyU/UG9Ho-cDcsI/AAAAAAAALNE/7QqjOp7FTqQ/s1600/gosling.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-x24hP1hzAyU/UG9Ho-cDcsI/AAAAAAAALNE/7QqjOp7FTqQ/s320/gosling.png&#34; width=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;font-size: 13px; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;James Gosling talks about Robots!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://medianetwork.oracle.com/video/player/1871712019001&#34;&gt;Technical keynote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/javaone/entry/dr_bob_ballard_special_guest&#34;&gt;Dr Robert Ballard&#39;s keynote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Community keynote&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Gosling&#34;&gt;James Gosling&lt;/a&gt; on stage!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having well-known Java people say Hi to me out of the blue&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/javaone-problem-with-women-technical.html&#34;&gt;Women in Technology session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I already mentioned the technical keynote in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/javaone-user-group-sunday.html&#34;&gt;summary of Sunday&lt;/a&gt;, but I forgot to talk about Dr Robert Ballard&#39;s section, which is crazy because it was so inspiring. &amp;nbsp;What I got out of that was how much fun technology can be, and how kids are really ready to be amazed and engaged with science and technology, provided you get them young enough. &amp;nbsp;I also really loved that the photos of all the scientists showed great diversity, something he seems to take very seriously. &amp;nbsp;His comment was &#34;A child needs to see their face 20 years out to know they can play in the game. Don&#39;t sell science, sell scientists and engineers&#34;. &amp;nbsp;The point I took from that was that by focussing on &#34;science&#34; and &#34;technology&#34;, we could be losing people - by showcasing the people, the talent, the passions, we are much more likely to engage children. &amp;nbsp;And I think that stands for adults as well.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XzDZJM8QFHA/UG9H6aw8GGI/AAAAAAAALNY/A8iBGCFDGWQ/s1600/robots-and-people.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XzDZJM8QFHA/UG9H6aw8GGI/AAAAAAAALNY/A8iBGCFDGWQ/s320/robots-and-people.png&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;font-size: 13px; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;A robot!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;And this nicely fits the message I was trying to get across in my session on Wednesday (which I know I&#39;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/javaone-problem-with-women-technical.html&#34;&gt;already blogged about&lt;/a&gt;) - it&#39;s dead important to address the failure points when it comes to diversity, but I think we forget to push the positives - the reason we don&#39;t understand why some groups of people are under-represented in technology is because we all love being here, it&#39;s a great industry to work in. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d love to see our passions more widely showcased than simply at conferences where we&#39;re a self-selecting audience.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Bfal0DsvHx4/UG9HIvDYvLI/AAAAAAAALMY/ehlSr0SOVko/s1600/LJC.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Bfal0DsvHx4/UG9HIvDYvLI/AAAAAAAALMY/ehlSr0SOVko/s400/LJC.png&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The LJC panel about our involvement in the Java Community Process&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;Not only was this a great JavaOne for me personally, it was a real triumph for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Last year there were only two of us here, and Martijn was working hard to introduce me to the other JUG leaders and the people on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jcp.org/en/home/index&#34;&gt;JCP&lt;/a&gt; committee that we were going to be working with over the next 12 months. &amp;nbsp;This year, there were five of us here, spreading the word about our work as a member of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jcp.org/en/participation/committee&#34;&gt;Executive Committee&lt;/a&gt; of the Java Community Process (the Java standards body), primarily our &lt;a href=&#34;http://adoptajsr.org/&#34;&gt;Adopt a JSR&lt;/a&gt; program. &amp;nbsp;We also wanted to talk to a load of people about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://java.net/projects/adoptopenjdk/pages/AdoptOpenJDK&#34;&gt;Adopt OpenJDK&lt;/a&gt; program as well, we&#39;ve found lots of developers are really keen to develop the language itself, Java at the fundamental level, and we really want to help bridge the gap between the guys who work on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/&#34;&gt;OpenJDK&lt;/a&gt; project and the developers in the community. &amp;nbsp;But all our hard work over the last year, kicking off these programs and working with other user groups and Oracle to really harness the power of the community, has been recognised. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;ve won not one, but two awards - woohoo! &amp;nbsp;Fame, glory, girls/boys, money etc await us! &amp;nbsp;Well, not quite... but it&#39;s certainly nice to be the &#34;Award Winning London Java Community&#34;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Ob5Soi91ze0/UG9G_0Nnm4I/AAAAAAAALMQ/sCzbt6FMGiY/s1600/community-keynote.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Ob5Soi91ze0/UG9G_0Nnm4I/AAAAAAAALMQ/sCzbt6FMGiY/s320/community-keynote.png&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The LJC in the Community Keynote&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;Our two shiny accolades are:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/us/corporate/press/1854931&#34;&gt;Duke&#39;s Choice Award&lt;/a&gt; for Innovation and Contributions to the Community&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/jcp/entry/10th_annual_jcp_award_winners&#34;&gt;JCP Member of the Year&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://soujava.org.br/&#34;&gt;SouJava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;So, a really great JavaOne. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m not sure, if I&#39;m honest, who reads my summaries of conferences - I know lots of people do read them, but I don&#39;t know if that&#39;s those who went to the conference or those who would have liked to have gone, or those who don&#39;t know what it&#39;s like at conferences.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But in case this is useful to anyone who is reading this, next year come to JavaOne if:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You want to know what&#39;s coming up for Java the platform or Java the language&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You want to meet, or at least see presenting, the people who are actually making these changes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You want to meet other Java developers from around the world - whether you want to find someone with the same problems as you, or want to see different issues that face people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You want to see the Power Of User Groups!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You want to understand how decisions are made with regards to the future of Java&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You want to meet like-minded people&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UGdIjKFq2Bc/UG9HfCm94UI/AAAAAAAALM4/rXbL-X-VPeI/s1600/Vegas.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UGdIjKFq2Bc/UG9HfCm94UI/AAAAAAAALM4/rXbL-X-VPeI/s400/Vegas.png&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The Exhibitors Hall was like Vegas! But there was a buzz which was infectious&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;Oh there&#39;s millions more, and even if you only tick one of those reasons, I personally think it&#39;s a great way to get a better understanding of the language we use every day as developers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And finally, some of my sessions will be available, audio and slides only, via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/connect/search.ww?event=javaone&#34;&gt;content catalog&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Look for the following:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;UGF10467 - Benefits of Open Source&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CON3732 - Concurrent Programming with the Disruptor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CON5130 - London Java Community: How to Change the World&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CON11338 - The Problem with Women: A Technical Approach&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: The Problem With Women - A Technical Approach</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday dawned, with a sense of foreboding (actually it dawned with me coughing my lungs out, but we&amp;rsquo;ve heard enough about the sub-optimal state of my respiratory system this week). &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On this day, I was giving the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2012/06/subject-of-women-programmers-is-boring.html&#34;&gt;talk I was dreading&lt;/a&gt; when I got asked to do it.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s the talk I actually put more work into than any of the other sessions I was presenting at this JavaOne.&amp;nbsp; It was the Women In IT talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s timely, given that conference season has one again led to cries of &lt;a href=&#34;http://cerianjenkins.me/2012/10/02/insight-of-an-intern-sexism-in-tech/&#34;&gt;sexism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jessitron.com/2012/09/this-is-not-ok.html&#34;&gt;discrimination&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;So although I really hate banging on about the subject (you&amp;rsquo;d never believe it from my blog) it&amp;rsquo;s still necessary to cover.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel, and have felt for a long time, that &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2011/01/on-how-not-to-target-girl-geeks.html&#34;&gt;the way we&amp;rsquo;re approaching the &amp;ldquo;problem&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; of the lack of women techies is just wrong. &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Obviously&lt;/i&gt; painting stuff pink is just not going to cut it (I hope that&amp;rsquo;s obvious). &amp;nbsp;I think the fundamental problem is that we keep thinking about women. &amp;nbsp;While that should be great for someone like me, it actually triggers a whole bunch of gender stereotyping in our poor human brains which prevents us seeing the big picture - the fact that we&amp;rsquo;re not attractive as an industry for women suggests we&amp;rsquo;re losing a whole heap of talent because of some sort of image problem. &amp;nbsp;We just don&amp;rsquo;t see the other missing minorities, or we&amp;rsquo;re not comfortable talking about them. &amp;nbsp;I mean, can you image running a session about attracting more black people into programming? &amp;nbsp;I suspect there would be uproar in singling out a minority based on something as arbitrary as skin colour.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To be fair, even before the session there was a tiny bit of controversy:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JgSVCSZexEg/UG3fuhHgeuI/AAAAAAAALLg/FYubozFuf-E/s1600/pmonks.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JgSVCSZexEg/UG3fuhHgeuI/AAAAAAAALLg/FYubozFuf-E/s1600/pmonks.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is nice though to see guys (because indeed this was someone of the male persuasion) getting upset at the thought of someone taking a shot at the girls again. &amp;nbsp;I think it probably would have been a &lt;i&gt;little&lt;/i&gt; more helpful to the session if they&amp;rsquo;d put my name on it&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Maybe the publicity helped, because there was a really decent turnout for the talk. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m terrible at estimating numbers, and of course I completely forgot to take a photo of my lovely audience. &amp;nbsp;But I&amp;rsquo;d say there were&amp;hellip; 60? 80? people there? &amp;nbsp;Between 50 and 100 anyway, and seemed like a roughly even split of men and women, and there were people of different backgrounds. &amp;nbsp;Which is great, it&amp;rsquo;s more women than you normally see at a conference, and more men than you usually see at an event talking about &amp;ldquo;women&amp;rsquo;s issues&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;I really love running sessions about this subject with guys there, I&amp;rsquo;m of the opinion that talking about this with just women is almost completely useless, and isolates us from the rest of our community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I took the novel approach of actually trying to treat the problem the same way coders treat any problem: break it down logically.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;So I had the problem, the requirements, a retrospective, and the aim was to come up with a list of tasks going forward.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gsaab&#34;&gt;Georges Saab&lt;/a&gt; from Oracle was great as our &amp;ldquo;Business Analyst&amp;rdquo; - not only did he outline the business value in increasing diversity in the workplace:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Greater pool of talent to hire from&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Happier and more productive employees&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Greater retention rates&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;He also gave examples of how this is a bigger problem than just &amp;ldquo;Women in IT&amp;rdquo; - he spoke about being the outsider as an American who had relocated to Sweden, and how he benefitted from being in a country that recognises a father&amp;rsquo;s rights when his daughter was born there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-K9RVDN6uDE8/UG3mH1ykffI/AAAAAAAALL4/xwpuhtMpvTY/s1600/TrishaRetrospective.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-K9RVDN6uDE8/UG3mH1ykffI/AAAAAAAALL4/xwpuhtMpvTY/s400/TrishaRetrospective.jpg&#34; width=&#34;298&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;At LMAX we&amp;rsquo;re super-Agile (something we&amp;rsquo;ll actually be talking about at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV12/Home&#34;&gt;Devoxx&lt;/a&gt; this year), so the logical thing to do is to have a retrospective. &amp;nbsp;The question was somewhat fluffy - tell me about working as a techie, specific points about being female not essential. &amp;nbsp;So as with all our retrospectives, we covered good points, bad points, questions and ideas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;Incidentally, loads of people there knew about Agile methods and many were using them at work. Does this mean that agile is now more-or-less the norm? &amp;nbsp;Does it mean that companies that encourage people to go to conferences are agile or agile-friendly companies? &amp;nbsp;Or does it mean that people who care about people (i.e. those that go to a session like this) are more drawn to Agile methods? &amp;lt;/aside&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m wearing trainers to present, for the very first time! Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CeciliaBorg/&#34;&gt;Cecilia Borg&lt;/a&gt; for taking the photo)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;((Also, special super-thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveonjava&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt; who saved my presentation by sneaking in with a flipchart, stand and pens literally seconds before I needed it))&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everyone in the audience came up with really great points about working as a techie. &amp;nbsp;The thing I found most interesting was that very little of it was gender-specific.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Negatives&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pink it and Shrink it&amp;rdquo; marketing campaigns, allegedly for women.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How do you get into the job? &amp;nbsp;Entry and career paths unclear&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Micromanagement&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The hours&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lack of mentoring/role models&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Booth Babes (they are bad for women, but they are bad for men too - very demeaning to assume that guys as bright and&amp;nbsp;successful&amp;nbsp;as techies are drawn only to boobs)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Salary discrepancies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=brogrammer&#34;&gt;Brogrammers&lt;/a&gt; stereotype&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Education pipeline – women doing &amp;ldquo;computery&amp;rdquo; subjects decreasing from about 13 years old and onwards (&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/11/why-we-shouldnt-target-women.html#comment-form&#34;&gt;UK numbers&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pressure to be visible when you&amp;rsquo;re a woman/minority&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re seen as a woman first and a techie second&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Time drain to keep current, 90% of what you do is learning new stuff not using skills you already had&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Positives&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being different makes you stand out&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The hours&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The salary&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Woman&amp;rsquo;s perspective is a positive for the team (&lt;i&gt;Later agreed that diverse teams generally were more interesting to work in&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen an increase in the number of senior women&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Balanced teams are more productive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There are lots of jobs in IT, always hiring&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Flexibility and meritocracy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Women Are Exceptional (rare to get in as a girl so you&amp;rsquo;re either really interested, or really good, or both)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t understand this, my CIO is a woman?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is there a correlation between gamers and professional programmers?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Does the wider availability of technology (e.g. Facebook) lead to a wider appeal (of working in the industry) to people?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;As parents should we be doing more to encourage our kids into technology?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is the image of techies changing?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;We can replace the word &amp;ldquo;Woman&amp;rdquo; with person pretty much everywhere, and it becomes clear that we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be trying to work out the problems that face women, but instead be working harder to attract more awesome people into the job we love (I asked who in the room really hated the job, and one person half put his hand up. &amp;nbsp;So as techies, we generally like what we do), and to look after everyone who&amp;rsquo;s here already as well. &amp;nbsp;So that lead on to the actions we could do to help this.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Actions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Look elsewhere for technical talent (e.g. people with craft skills are creative and practical)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We should be more actively networking (join your local &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.java.net/jugs/java-user-groups&#34;&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get them young - go to schools and show kids what we do&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Challenge stereotypes - we&amp;rsquo;re not geeks who live at home and code in our bedrooms, we&amp;rsquo;re collaborative and creative individuals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We need more role models of all flavours&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Flexible education - it should be cheaper to make &amp;ldquo;mistakes&amp;rdquo; - e.g. to switch degrees or to cross-train from other qualifications, we can&amp;rsquo;t be limited by choices we made so young&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work experience to give kids/young people a taste of different jobs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Encourage / expect children to ask questions, more than just learning the school curriculum&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Buy kids technology e.g. raspberry pi, arduino&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Show our faces, we are all role models&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be vocal about our passions. &amp;nbsp;We love this job, let&amp;rsquo;s tell people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I felt extremely positive at the end of the session, I think guys saw some of the attitudes that affect women, and women saw that guys were not only sympathetic to our &amp;ldquo;plight&amp;rdquo;, but that they suffer discrimination too. &amp;nbsp;Basically we&amp;rsquo;re all in this together, and talking gender specifically is sometimes dividing us.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;One observation that I loved was&amp;nbsp;that one guy&amp;rsquo;s wife wanted their daughter to do what he does because he loves his job, and she sees hers as a chore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0cm;&#34;&gt;I also had a number of spin-off conversations later, as always happens when people are dead interested, and a really good point someone raised is that as techies we&amp;rsquo;re frequently the odd one out, the outsider, in a group of &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; people. &amp;nbsp;We&amp;rsquo;re actually quite used to it and pretty much embrace it. So if anything we&amp;rsquo;re an industry which will be more tolerant of your outsider-ness (as a woman, as someone who looks different) than more traditional jobs. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s a thought, and an attitude we should perhaps publish more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The three things I think we should do as individuals are:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Take The Plunge&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Women in particularly, but all of you who don&amp;rsquo;t think you can be That Person - start talking at conferences, start writing blogs, start a new user group if you haven&amp;rsquo;t got one, go into schools. &amp;nbsp;Be that role model.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Don&amp;rsquo;t Point Out Her Gender&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know the guys mean well, and women are guilty of this too, but don&amp;rsquo;t highlight to a women at a conference/interview/meetup when you meet her for the first time that she&amp;rsquo;s female. &amp;nbsp;She knows this. It&amp;rsquo;s almost always said in a positive way (&amp;ldquo;Wow, it&amp;rsquo;s great that you&amp;rsquo;re here, we don&amp;rsquo;t see many women in these parts&amp;rdquo;), and I know you mean it to be encouraging. &amp;nbsp;But it just highlights how different she is, not how awesome it is she&amp;rsquo;s doing the same thing you&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. What We Do Is Awesome&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re here because we like what we do, we get paid for doing our hobbies. &amp;nbsp;Not many people can boast of that. &amp;nbsp;We need to get out there and tell people how much fun it is to be a techie. &amp;nbsp;Don&amp;rsquo;t let the Hollywood geek stereotype be the only image people have of us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I had a really good time, and I came out feeling very positive about my job, my industry, and the people who do this. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;d love to run this session again if I get the opportunity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;EDIT: The &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/connect/search.ww?event=javaone#loadSearch-event=javaone&amp;amp;searchPhrase=CON11338&amp;amp;searchType=session&amp;amp;tc=0&amp;amp;sortBy=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;i(11424)=&amp;amp;i(10050)=&amp;amp;i(10090)=&amp;amp;i(10092)=&amp;amp;i(11842)=&amp;amp;i(10086)=&#34;&gt;slides and audio&lt;/a&gt; are available. &amp;nbsp;The content catalog is a little counter-intuitive to use, hopefully that link will take you to a page with this session title on - click on it and there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;media&amp;rdquo; on the pop up window. &amp;nbsp;This session doesn&amp;rsquo;t lend itself well to audio because of the audience participation aspect but I do repeat most of the points and you get a feel for the session.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: User Group Sunday</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4uvOXlKEyfE/UGnku_oqLLI/AAAAAAAALK0/rdugE0GC4nY/s1600/DSC_0295.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4uvOXlKEyfE/UGnku_oqLLI/AAAAAAAALK0/rdugE0GC4nY/s640/DSC_0295.JPG&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well this is exciting! &amp;nbsp;JavaOne 2011 is the first conference I spoke at, so this the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve covered the same conference two years running. &amp;nbsp;I think.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very nice to be back at JavaOne. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2011/10/javaone-2011-roundup.html&#34;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;it was my first opportunity to meet so many people - the guys at Oracle who work really hard to make sure Java has its own identity; the JUG Leaders and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jduchess.org/&#34;&gt;Duchess&lt;/a&gt; folk; the JCP EC committee members; and loads of people who live and work in the area who I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally get a chance to speak to in person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;m here with several other&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;people, and it&amp;rsquo;s great to be a member of the Alumni, to have the privilege of showing other guys around and introducing people to each other. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s nice to run into people I met here for the first time last year, some of whom I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to see at other events this year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, Sunday, is an interesting day. &amp;nbsp;The focus is on community, so I get to hear what other JUGs are doing, some of their pain points, and learn some of the things they&amp;rsquo;re doing that maybe we should think about. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lm0BeJifdNs/UGnYYDgNbVI/AAAAAAAALKI/rWANg1dfTks/s1600/DSC_0279.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;212&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lm0BeJifdNs/UGnYYDgNbVI/AAAAAAAALKI/rWANg1dfTks/s320/DSC_0279.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The day started well, with Jim and Richard de-mystifying the business and technology&amp;nbsp;terminology&amp;nbsp;we&amp;rsquo;re bound to come across at this conference. &amp;nbsp;8:15am is a really harsh time to have to do your first presentation, but it had a good turnout and was a great way to kick off the conference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;I followed this with a talk about why you would open source&amp;nbsp;your secrets, a short presentation detailing the benefits to your business of opening up parts of your codebase. &amp;nbsp;It went better than expected, given my voice has all but disappeared due to a stupid cold and plane travel and jet lag (and noisy bars). &amp;nbsp;I had contingency plans on how to present via typing or drawing on my iPad, but in the end I managed even despite the microphone not being turned on. &amp;nbsp;Doh.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-y3i2xpoKxdM/UGnapgQNiiI/AAAAAAAALKQ/SRkBw51f9Kk/s1600/DSC_0289.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-y3i2xpoKxdM/UGnapgQNiiI/AAAAAAAALKQ/SRkBw51f9Kk/s400/DSC_0289.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There were a series of presentations on how to make your JUG successful and how to run Adopt a JSR/OpenJDK programmes in your user group, before &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kittylyst&#34;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt; and I had to dash off to the public EC meeting. &amp;nbsp;This was not as well-attended as last year, but it meant that I had a chance to talk to all the EC members, and to drink more free champagne than one really ought to in the afternoon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-j-qDgQoK7EQ/UGncAE5vqYI/AAAAAAAALKY/F6R2jOURWjc/s1600/DSC_0291.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-j-qDgQoK7EQ/UGncAE5vqYI/AAAAAAAALKY/F6R2jOURWjc/s320/DSC_0291.JPG&#34; width=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Next on the packed schedule was a trip to yet another location (seriously, that&amp;rsquo;s 4 different locations just on Sunday) for the keynotes. &amp;nbsp;Note: next time I say &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not far, let&amp;rsquo;s walk&amp;rdquo; in San Francisco, hit me with sticks. &amp;nbsp;That&amp;rsquo;s the second time in as many days I&amp;rsquo;ve been hit with a vertical distance that was further than the horizontal. &amp;nbsp;At least this time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t wheeling my luggage up the hill like I was on Friday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The keynotes were definitely better than last year. &amp;nbsp;I really enjoyed how the technical keynote put the shiny new stuff into an everyday context - seeing JavaFX running on all the platforms, including embedded, and seeing lambdas used in anger, was really engaging. &amp;nbsp;In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s much more likely to get &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; developers using these things. &amp;nbsp;I particularly enjoyed the interplay between Mark Reinhold and Brian Goetz, it&amp;rsquo;s great to see people like that so passionate about what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, it really humanizes them and their projects.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ODxw1aQyY-E/UGnlEk2QI4I/AAAAAAAALK8/DLZYaOE33kI/s1600/DSC_0311.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ODxw1aQyY-E/UGnlEk2QI4I/AAAAAAAALK8/DLZYaOE33kI/s320/DSC_0311.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The last trip of the day was back down the hill to one of the many parties scheduled this week. &amp;nbsp;Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not in every party that you get given an award, so this was particularly sweet - the London Java Community has been honoured with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.java.net/dukeschoice&#34;&gt;Duke&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;This is the first year a community has won a &amp;ldquo;Dukey&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to be part of a group of people who are actively contributing to the language I work with daily, and to be recognised for this. &amp;nbsp;So yes, I was on stage getting an award again. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s addictive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, a really great kick off to this year&amp;rsquo;s JavaOne, and I&amp;rsquo;m back at the apartment well before my coach (well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://uber.com/invite/w2rk7&#34;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt;) turns into a pumpkin and resting my voice in time for my Disruptor presentation tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nkfHDUEb_qU/UGnlcHCHk-I/AAAAAAAALLE/gCqr9CtoGk4/s1600/DSC_0316.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nkfHDUEb_qU/UGnlcHCHk-I/AAAAAAAALLE/gCqr9CtoGk4/s640/DSC_0316.JPG&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So yeah&amp;hellip; in keeping with this year&amp;rsquo;s theme of basically only blogging about the exciting conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve been to,
I&amp;rsquo;m going to blog about the exciting conferences I am attending in the future. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been great at doing that,
the disconnect between the time I submit a presentation and the actual announcement means that I often forget I haven&amp;rsquo;t told anyone about what I&amp;rsquo;m up to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Firstly, I&amp;rsquo;m back in the States this month to present my very first workshop - &lt;a href=&#34;https://thestrangeloop.com/sessions/concurrent-programming-using-the-disruptor&#34;&gt;An Introduction to the Disruptor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;at Strangeloop. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve been given a mere 6 months to prepare it (note: sarcasm) and it&amp;rsquo;s still a work in progress. &amp;nbsp;So, if you&amp;rsquo;re coming, feel free to suggest things you want to see covered. &amp;nbsp;If you are coming, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Secondly, I&amp;rsquo;m back in the States again a minute and a half later for several presentations at JavaOne. &amp;nbsp;I really enjoyed JavaOne last year, it was my first international conference, my first speaking gig, and a great place to meet loads of dead interesting people. &amp;nbsp;This year I&amp;rsquo;m being greedy and I&amp;rsquo;m doing more than one talk:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sun 30th Sept:&amp;nbsp;UGF10467 - Benefits of Open Source&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mon&amp;nbsp;1st Oct:&amp;nbsp;CON3732 - Concurrent Programming with the Disruptor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wed 3rd Oct:&amp;nbsp;CON5130 - London Java Community: How to Change the World&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wed 3rd Oct:&amp;nbsp;CON11338 - The Problem with Women: A Technical Approach&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m afraid the content catalog totally confounds me, so I can&amp;rsquo;t link to each talk specifically, but you should be able to search on the identifiers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;        Then I&amp;rsquo;m back on home turf, at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/2012/sessions/?tid=2604#session-22064&#34;&gt;JAX London&lt;/a&gt;, doing the Disruptor talk yet again. &amp;nbsp;I always enjoy JAX, it has a lot of participation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; members, it attracts an international set of speakers and it&amp;rsquo;s right on my doorstep.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, I&amp;rsquo;d really, really like to go to Devoxx again this year, but that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been confirmed yet. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll do everything in my power to be there, but no promises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Right. &amp;nbsp;I suppose I had better get back to writing this workshop&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
