<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaOne12 on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaOne12 on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: The Summary</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, JavaOne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4LX8X74MR1M/UG9HT1hdisI/AAAAAAAALMs/TWP67rS4B8Q/s1600/TaylorStCafe.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taylor Street Cafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to be controversial. I think this was my favourite conference of this year. I know that&amp;rsquo;s not trendy, and that Oracle-bashing is still a popular pastime. And I know I&amp;rsquo;ve also made a big deal about how much fun it is to meet people who program in different languages. But there is something very special about being surrounded by thousands of people from all around the world who use the same technology as you, some facing the same problems, some solving very different issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: The Problem With Women - A Technical Approach</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday dawned, with a sense of foreboding (actually it dawned with me coughing my lungs out, but we&amp;rsquo;ve heard enough about the sub-optimal state of my respiratory system this week).   On this day, I was giving the &lt;a href=&#34;https://trishagee.com/2012/06/24/the_subject_of_women_programmers_is_boring/&#34;&gt;talk I was dreading&lt;/a&gt; when I got asked to do it.  It&amp;rsquo;s the talk I actually put more work into than any of the other sessions I was presenting at this JavaOne.  It was the Women In IT talk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: User Group Sunday</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday/</guid>
      <description>Well this is exciting! JavaOne 2011 is the first conference I spoke at, so this the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve covered the same conference two years running. I think.
It&amp;rsquo;s very nice to be back at JavaOne. Last year it was my first opportunity to meet so many people - the guys at Oracle who work really hard to make sure Java has its own identity; the JUG Leaders and Duchess folk; the JCP EC committee members; and loads of people who live and work in the area who I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally get a chance to speak to in person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events/</guid>
      <description>So yeah&amp;hellip; in keeping with this year&amp;rsquo;s theme of basically only blogging about the exciting conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve been to, I&amp;rsquo;m going to blog about the exciting conferences I am attending in the future. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been great at doing that, the disconnect between the time I submit a presentation and the actual announcement means that I often forget I haven&amp;rsquo;t told anyone about what I&amp;rsquo;m up to.
Firstly, I&amp;rsquo;m back in the States this month to present my very first workshop - An Introduction to the Disruptor at Strangeloop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
