<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaOne12 on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaOne12 on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: The Summary</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_summary/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: The Problem With Women - A Technical Approach</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday dawned, with a sense of foreboding (actually it dawned with me coughing my lungs out, but we&#39;ve heard enough about the sub-optimal state of my respiratory system this week). On this day, I was giving the talk I was dreadingwhen I got asked to do it. It&#39;s the talk I actually put more work into than any of the other sessions I was presenting at this JavaOne. It was the Women In IT talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: User Group Sunday</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday/</guid>
      <description>Well this is exciting! JavaOne 2011 is the first conference I spoke at, so this the first time I&#39;ve covered the same conference two years running. I think.It&#39;s very nice to be back at JavaOne. Last yearit was my first opportunity to meet so many people - the guys at Oracle who work really hard to make sure Java has its own identity; the JUG Leaders and Duchessfolk; the JCP EC committee members; and loads of people who live and work in the area who I wouldn&#39;t normally get a chance to speak to in person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events/</guid>
      <description>So yeah&amp;hellip; in keeping with this year&#39;s theme of basically only blogging about the exciting conferences I&#39;ve been to, I&#39;m going to blog about the exciting conferences I am attending in the future. I haven&#39;t been great at doing that, the disconnect between the time I submit a presentation and the actual announcement means that I often forget I haven&#39;t told anyone about what I&#39;m up to.Firstly, I&#39;m back in the States this month to present my very first workshop - An Introduction to the Disruptorat Strangeloop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>