<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>London on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/london/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The birth of a new community</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topping off my mini-tour at the end of May, I was invited to Rotterdam to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://010dev.nl/post/social-tech-event-the-disruptor-and-the-perfect-programmer&#34;&gt;present to a brand new community&lt;/a&gt; of developers. &amp;nbsp;I was really interested in attending because my experience with user groups is pretty much limited to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;, and I knew this would be different due to being a) across a wider range of technologies and b) shiny and new.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was hosted (rather awesomely) in a brewery, and until then I&amp;rsquo;d never given a presentation in a pub. &amp;nbsp;Frankly it&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m keen to do more of. &amp;nbsp;Due to a total technology fail on the part of all of us, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the projector working with any of the various laptops. &amp;nbsp;However, with 30-odd techies, free wireless and slides &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/concurrent-programming-using-the-disruptor-copenhagen&#34;&gt;available on Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;, we managed a novel and collaborative presentation approach, with people clustered around the laptops with the largest screens, and someone at each one&amp;nbsp;valiantly&amp;nbsp;keeping up with my quick pace through over 100 slides of stick-men drawings (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.objectify.be/wordpress/?p=488&#34;&gt;a review of the evening is available&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I really enjoyed it, it was quite a change of pace from the conferences - my first attempt at presenting after imbibing probably a little toooo much wine, and a much more intimate venue which encouraged a lot of questions and discussion. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s actually a format that worked, and maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a way to get it to work even more smoothly, if the slides on all the laptops were synchronised, and there was some way for me to gesture wildly at the appropriate parts of the slides like I do when I&amp;rsquo;m on stage. &amp;nbsp;Hmmm, maybe that&amp;rsquo;s actually a webcast now I think about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I had an excellent time, thanks to the hospitality of the rather awesome Rotterdam-ians. &amp;nbsp;What I found fascinating &amp;nbsp;- as well as the venue and the novel presenting style - is the formation of a group of people with broadly similar interests. &amp;nbsp;One of the great strengths of a place like London is its size - you will find a number of people here with&amp;nbsp;interests&amp;nbsp;like yours, and sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; make it ridiculously easy to find them. &amp;nbsp;One of the weaknesses of London, however, is its size - there are so many people you could attract that you end up narrowing your search field. &amp;nbsp;You pick a very specific technology, a tiny geographical area, a single interest, to build a community around.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking for a while it would be nice to have a community of people who aren&amp;rsquo;t all the same, who share overlapping but different passions. &amp;nbsp;But how do you create something like that? &amp;nbsp;You need a single thing to draw those people together, otherwise they&amp;rsquo;ll never find each other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In smaller cities the geography limits the numbers, so you can have a broader range of interests represented. &amp;nbsp;In London, I can see something as (relatively) specific as a Java User Group becoming even more specific. &amp;nbsp;With nearly 2500 members, you could easily spin off Java-for-banking, Java-for-gaming, Java-in-west-London-zone-2 etc etc. &amp;nbsp;In fact, we&amp;rsquo;ve already spawned off a number of groups like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/grad-dc/&#34;&gt;Graduate Developer Community&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/&#34;&gt;London Scala Users&amp;rsquo; Group&lt;/a&gt; and so forth. &amp;nbsp;With nearly 2500 members, you cannot possibly meet them all, you can&amp;rsquo;t even get a feel for what everyone&amp;rsquo;s into. &amp;nbsp;How do you get the intimacy from a smaller user group without narrowing the scope so much that all of you might as well be clones? &amp;nbsp;The awesome thing about user groups is coming across new ideas, seeing solutions to problems you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know existed, hearing about things people are working on that never occurred to you. &amp;nbsp;For that, you need diversity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And one of the nice things about a city as large as London is you get plenty of diversity. &amp;nbsp;But how do you pull together that diversity? &amp;nbsp;How do you create a group that is diverse, when by necessity you need something central for those people to gravitate towards? &amp;nbsp;And if the diversity creates a large group, how do you create intimacy and feel personally involved, the stuff that comes for free if you belong to a smaller group where you know everyone?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In Rotterdam, at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/04/in-which-i-defend-male-species-at-all.html&#34;&gt;Girl Geek meetup&lt;/a&gt;, I saw the advantage of using something other than a specific technology to gather together a group of interesting people - you get a wider range of experiences and passions. &amp;nbsp;How you can achieve this without using&amp;nbsp;geography&amp;nbsp;or genetics to select your&amp;nbsp;participants?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is it even possible to build a community when your goal is diversity?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2012</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2012</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2012</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m late with my write-up of &lt;a href=&#34;http://qconlondon.com/london-2012/&#34;&gt;QCon&lt;/a&gt;, and what&amp;rsquo;s worse, it will be partial - &amp;ldquo;sadly&amp;rdquo; I was in Lanzarote on a training week with the running club from the Thursday (8th) so I missed most of it.&amp;nbsp; A sacrifice I had to make for 7 days in the sunshine….&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firstly, me me me&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I presented the talk I &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/new-disruptor-presentation-unveiled-to.html&#34;&gt;previewed at Skillsmatter&lt;/a&gt; the previous week, something I was calling the User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Disruptor, but actually turned out to be how-can-Trish-fill-95-slides-with-pictures-and-finish-in-under-40-minutes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The audience was different to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://skillsmatter.com/&#34;&gt;Skillsmatter&lt;/a&gt; event, not surprisingly.&amp;nbsp; What was surprising is that I expected people at the conference to be less aware of &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/&#34;&gt;the Disruptor&lt;/a&gt;, and those who came to the Disruptor-only LJC event to have had more exposure to it.&amp;nbsp; It was a (pleasant) surprise to see how many of the standing-room-only audience had not only heard of the Disruptor but had &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/disruptor&#34;&gt;read stuff about it&lt;/a&gt; (I always love it when people have read my blog), played with it and were even using it in anger.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Because of that, I think if anything the talk did not go into enough detail, or enough new stuff, to please everyone.&amp;nbsp; Tough crowd!&amp;nbsp; But it was gratifying to hear the audience correct me in some of my answers, and answer other people&amp;rsquo;s questions - it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to know people are listening.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Of course, I will post a link to the presentation when it&amp;rsquo;s available. &amp;nbsp;For now only the &lt;a href=&#34;http://qconlondon.com/dl/qcon-london-2012/slides/TrishaGee_ConcurrentProgrammingUsingTheDisruptor.pdf&#34;&gt;slides are online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;I enjoyed QCon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;QCon was noticeably different to the other conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve been to in the last six months.&amp;nbsp; For one, it&amp;rsquo;s not a Java conference - sure, I was hosted on the Java track, but QCon is wider-ranging than just one technology platform.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s because of this, or because it was based in the notoriously impatient London, but I felt like there was a message of &amp;ldquo;Look, let&amp;rsquo;s just get stuff done, OK?&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; Ultimately we get paid to deliver stuff for the business, and since my favourite question is always &amp;ldquo;but what are we trying to achieve?&amp;rdquo; I like to hear ideas around how to actually deliver.&amp;nbsp; Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;ve loved the technology conferences - I like to hear about new stuff I had no idea about, and I really like the community vibe from them.&amp;nbsp; But it&amp;rsquo;s a nice change to be shaken up into thinking exactly &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; we do all this.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Data Panorama&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Firstly, Rebecca Parsons and &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; from my old employer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtworks.com/&#34;&gt;ThoughtWorks&lt;/a&gt; put Big Data into perspective.&amp;nbsp; Previously I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really cared about it - we process lots of data at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lmax.com/&#34;&gt;LMAX&lt;/a&gt; but we don&amp;rsquo;t really have to dig into it, so Big Data is not top of my &amp;ldquo;oooh I really worry about that&amp;rdquo; problems.&amp;nbsp; There were quite a few interesting points I took out of this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-A6XxOlBvbMg/T3F3oFTMPFI/AAAAAAAAJlk/1uaS3_A3ozs/s1600/2012-03-07+09.58.29.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-A6XxOlBvbMg/T3F3oFTMPFI/AAAAAAAAJlk/1uaS3_A3ozs/s320/2012-03-07+09.58.29.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&amp;nbsp;- In the past, it was easy (and possibly even correct) to model the whole application based on the data you were collecting or manipulating (and probably storing in a relational database).&amp;nbsp; These days it&amp;rsquo;s not just the data from your app you need to worry about (and that can get big enough), but also all the news, blogs, twitter, and Facebook stuff generated by you and about you.&amp;nbsp; In addition, your data might not even be located with your app - the cloud has made the physical question of location redundant.&amp;nbsp; All of this pushes you towards an architecture which has to separate data from the application, and forces you to ponder your design.&amp;nbsp; I heard good arguments for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00794TAUG/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00794TAUG&#34;&gt;Domain Driven Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00794TAUG&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt; here, which is nice because we like that at LMAX.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Reporting and analytics on Big Data must be more fluid.&amp;nbsp; There&amp;rsquo;s so much data about you, your users, your application, out there that you don&amp;rsquo;t even know the questions to ask.&amp;nbsp; Instead you want to be able to spot patterns in data you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know you had,&amp;nbsp; I thought this was dead interesting - I studied Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence at university, and we were told data mining using AI was going to be fundamental to companies who wanted to be on the bleeding edge.&amp;nbsp; Only now is it looking like people realise it&amp;rsquo;s becoming that important.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Martin referred to Data Scientists and said he was suspicious of scientists.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;d been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00139XTG4/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00139XTG4&#34;&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00139XTG4&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt; on the train in that morning and couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if he&amp;rsquo;s read the same thing - that was talking about how you should treat someone with suspicion if they suggest you can apply science and logic to anything that is… well, actually to anything other than actual science (by which he meant physics I believe).&amp;nbsp; By saying it&amp;rsquo;s a science you suggest it&amp;rsquo;s predictable and follows rules.&amp;nbsp; And if it was predictable, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be hard.&amp;nbsp; Big Data is anything other than predictable - the data could be corrupt (it&amp;rsquo;s safest to assume some of it is); it&amp;rsquo;s generated by people (and we all know how fickle they are); and if you&amp;rsquo;re collecting lots of it practically randomly, then cause/effect/correlation are not guaranteed.&amp;nbsp; So Martin suggests the term Data Journalist.&amp;nbsp; There was a storm on Twitter which suggested a certain amount of disagreement with this term, but I like it.&amp;nbsp; But then, I like to pretend I&amp;rsquo;m a writer and not a programmer.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- They gave some examples of using data to drive economic growth (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://opendata.go.ke/&#34;&gt;Kenya&lt;/a&gt;) - what I thought was interesting about this is that it was a win-win situation - expose the data to grow technology skills, but get a lot of interesting/useful/socially responsible applications in return.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Something I liked was about the idea of embracing &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; data, stuff that&amp;rsquo;s not trustworthy for whatever reason.&amp;nbsp; You can assume that the good data overwhelms the bad but you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure.&amp;nbsp; By looking for more fluffy patterns, vague correlations, in your data, you might expose something interesting even if the data&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; As humans, we can&amp;rsquo;t expect that we won&amp;rsquo;t make a mistake - it&amp;rsquo;s better assume we will and work out how to deal with it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- There was a call to not passively accept requirements, but to play an active role.&amp;nbsp; I like to think this ties in to my post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/why-customer-isnt-always-right.html&#34;&gt;working with your customer&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; But then I would.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- I got a lot from this keynote, even if it was just a feeling of &amp;ldquo;I knew it!&amp;nbsp; I was right!&amp;ldquo;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Highly available systems in Erlang&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Joe Armstrong was a very interesting person to listen to, clearly someone who&amp;rsquo;s been there and done that. Even without the presentation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://qconlondon.com/dl/qcon-london-2012/slides/JoeArmstrong_BuildingHighlyAvailableSystemsInErlang.pdf&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt; are interesting in their own right as they contain a lot of information and guidelines.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The points I took away are:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- If part of the system fails, it&amp;rsquo;s not up to that part to fix itself.&amp;nbsp; You need special help to deal with failures.&amp;nbsp; If you fell over with a heart attack, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t try and heal yourself, you&amp;rsquo;d get a medic&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Isolation between threads/programs will mean that those different things cannot interfere with each other (i.e. no shared state).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- My favourite quote was &amp;ldquo;If you make things synchronous you&amp;rsquo;ll bugger things up&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; In theory, it&amp;rsquo;s so much easier for us humans (programmers) to think synchronously.&amp;nbsp; But whenever you design your system to by asynchronous, you find that your system actually becomes simpler and not more complicated.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;JVM performance optimizations at Twitter&amp;rsquo;s scale&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- I had a terrible view in the fully packed room, so I was just picking up phrases. I heard&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/asz&#34;&gt;Attila&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;mention the Uncanny Valley, a phenomenon I was introduced to by my sister when she was studying her Cybernetics PhD (Google it, I found it fascinating). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- There was a lot of really useful information about how the Java GC works.&amp;nbsp; It seemed to back up the (rough) premise we work on - stuff that&amp;rsquo;s very short-lived is fine, and stuff that lasts &amp;ldquo;forever&amp;rdquo; is fine - it&amp;rsquo;s the stuff in between which&amp;nbsp; cripples your system when it keeps getting shoved around.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Decisions Decisions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dannorth.net/&#34;&gt;Dan North&lt;/a&gt; was, as always, an excellent speaker.&amp;nbsp; He entertained us but got us all thinking.&amp;nbsp; Five years ago at QCon London (my very first conference ever, and the thing that motivated me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2007/03/qcon-london.html&#34;&gt;start a professional blog&lt;/a&gt;), I saw Dan speaking and I was inspired to think about my working practices.&amp;nbsp; He was talking about BDD at the time, which was a relatively new concept to me.&amp;nbsp; I came away from that QCon with clearer ideas of what awesome development practices should look like.&amp;nbsp; Never did I imagine that five years later, not only would I be working in an environment which follows a lot of those practices (and pioneers many more) but that I would actually be speaking at the same conference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dSflRhQmCtU/T3F3eta5bUI/AAAAAAAAJlU/TSJDG-V23Ck/s1600/2012-03-07+16.47.15.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dSflRhQmCtU/T3F3eta5bUI/AAAAAAAAJlU/TSJDG-V23Ck/s320/2012-03-07+16.47.15.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since then, and of course, Dan isn&amp;rsquo;t talking about the same things either. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a lot of conferences this year, and I heard nothing really preaching to the &amp;ldquo;meta-agile&amp;rdquo; LMAX (still have a post pending about our agile practices&amp;hellip;).&amp;nbsp; When it comes to agile, there seem to be very few people who we can learn off - don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, there are lots of things we want to improve on, which is why we&amp;rsquo;re looking for people to learn off.&amp;nbsp; But most people are still preaching TDD and we want to know &amp;ldquo;what next?&amp;rdquo;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Well, Dan took everything we thought we knew, and ripped it to pieces.&amp;nbsp; Taught us to challenge everything we think we know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;It was irritating actually because he had no answers.&amp;nbsp; But he did tell us that the answers we think we already have might not be the right ones….&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Well worth watching his talk when it comes online, I really can&amp;rsquo;t summarise it here.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Developers Have a Mental Disorder&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I nearly missed this ending keynote.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t,&amp;nbsp;Greg Young&amp;nbsp;is awesome at ranting.&amp;nbsp; He said developers have a disease - we overcomplicate things, when we try to simplify things.&amp;nbsp; We want to abstract stuff, we love to look for patterns and reuse when actually sometimes we just need to solve the problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In my notes I have &amp;ldquo;People come to conferences for answers, when they should be remembering to use their brains&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; I assume that&amp;rsquo;s a quote from him, and not a comment I thought of at the time, but I wholeheartedly agree with it - if a shiny new technology solved your problems, you&amp;rsquo;d be out of a job.&amp;nbsp; Your job is to take the problem and figure out how to solve it.&amp;nbsp; Not to drag and drop an answer into place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another talk that I can&amp;rsquo;t do justice to, watch the video when it comes online.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;…and finally….&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;At the end of the day, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atlassian.com/&#34;&gt;Atlassian&lt;/a&gt;-sponsored community night was awesome.&amp;nbsp; I got to chat to (be prepared for gratuitous name dropping here) &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt;; my old friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simonbrown.je/&#34;&gt;Simon Brown&lt;/a&gt;; my ubiquitous &lt;a href=&#34;http://londonjavacommunity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; colleagues &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/karianna&#34;&gt;Martijn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jr0cket.co.uk/2012/03/qcon-london-2012-aftermath-return-of.html&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://zeroturnaround.com/&#34;&gt;Zero Turnaround&lt;/a&gt; guys; a couple of ex-colleagues from Evolution / Detica; a heap of LMAX and ex-LMAX guys; and, of course, bundles and bundles of new interesting people.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary (i.e the short version for those who can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to read this whole post)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s wishful thinking, but the messages I took from QCon were:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pASVscBgNZY/T3F3V-wBbuI/AAAAAAAAJlM/K8VlKf0FjLM/s1600/2012-03-07+17.49.55.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pASVscBgNZY/T3F3V-wBbuI/AAAAAAAAJlM/K8VlKf0FjLM/s320/2012-03-07+17.49.55.jpg&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you want to solve the problem your business has, you might want to model your system around their world.&amp;nbsp; Funny, that sounds suspiciously like Domain Driven Design.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Synchronous is bad, mmmkay?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hardcore understanding of what the computer is really doing seems to be coming back into fashion.&amp;nbsp; Hmmm, I wonder who started that…? (tongue firmly in cheek, we can&amp;rsquo;t have been the only ones)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t tune something you don&amp;rsquo;t understand&amp;rdquo; - testing and monitoring is kinda important.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Our business is all about trade offs.&amp;nbsp; There is no perfect solution, they pay us because it&amp;rsquo;s very very hard to work out something that&amp;rsquo;s Good Enough.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ultimately it feels like back to basics: understand the problem; model the domain, and have sympathy for the hardware that&amp;rsquo;s running your solution.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Corporate Bit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;QCon overall turned out to be a bit of an LMAX fest in the end, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bad-concurrency.blogspot.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Andy Stewart (our Chief Lord Business Analyst), all giving presentations there as well as me.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be on home turf, and it&amp;rsquo;s very cool to see that we have such a range of things to talk about that so many of us are invited to speak.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;PS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I just found out there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://qconnewyork.com/&#34;&gt;QCon in New York&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; My invitation seems to have got lost in the post.&amp;nbsp; Don&amp;rsquo;t suppose anyone wants me to speak there…?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Did On My Holidays</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/what_i_did_on_my_holidays</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/what_i_did_on_my_holidays</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And now, a post for my long-neglected, less technical readers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I took a week off in July to try and avoid that Oh My God I Missed Summer Again feeling.  Granted, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get that in the UK even if you&amp;rsquo;re not stuck in an office the entire time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Really this is just an excuse to post some photos on the blog.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mOMqqFVCFi8/TkY2yVOPIiI/AAAAAAAAIJs/5vZHMmyqubk/s1600/Embankment.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mOMqqFVCFi8/TkY2yVOPIiI/AAAAAAAAIJs/5vZHMmyqubk/s400/Embankment.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Monday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hopped on the bike and explored from Kensington to Westminster.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Felt distinctly smug when I grabbed my lunch from Victoria amongst all the less fortunate people who had to go back to their offices.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-WxvvRy0iE9w/TkY3P8gtp_I/AAAAAAAAIJw/qXE_1DbSUV4/s1600/Gull.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-WxvvRy0iE9w/TkY3P8gtp_I/AAAAAAAAIJw/qXE_1DbSUV4/s400/Gull.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tuesday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Decided to dose up on Culture, and went to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationalgallery.org.uk/&#34;&gt;National Gallery&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Last time I was there I was eight years old, and I distinctly remember admiring the frames more than the art.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The rather&amp;nbsp;marvellous&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artfinder.com/&#34;&gt;Artfinder&lt;/a&gt; makes up for the fact that you can&amp;rsquo;t take photos inside the gallery - I can share most of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artfinder.com/user/4229/collection/tuesday/public/&#34;&gt;pieces that struck me&lt;/a&gt; when I was there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-THH2_9dBQL8/TkY6P5ka5zI/AAAAAAAAIJ0/IHCur57_naA/s1600/Secret.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-THH2_9dBQL8/TkY6P5ka5zI/AAAAAAAAIJ0/IHCur57_naA/s400/Secret.jpg&#34; width=&#34;267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wednesday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally got around to embarking on one of the walks in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Secret-London-Exploring-Original-Unusual/dp/1566566363?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Secret London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1566566363&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I chose to do the City, from St Paul&amp;rsquo;s, covering Bank, Monument and Liverpool St.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was&amp;nbsp;fascinating. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in a lot of places round there, socialise there regularly, and have explored a number of the nooks and crannies. &amp;nbsp;But I was astounded at how many places I had never seen, alleys I had no idea existed, and gardens hidden away between modern office blocks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Highly recommended.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-WyWhmBr0Ay8/TkY7VjTQQRI/AAAAAAAAIJ4/5TJmXfQ_644/s1600/LondonBridge.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-WyWhmBr0Ay8/TkY7VjTQQRI/AAAAAAAAIJ4/5TJmXfQ_644/s400/LondonBridge.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thursday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My parents dropped by and I racked my brain for a different way to explore this massive, old city. &amp;nbsp;And it came to me: using the artery of the city - the river. &amp;nbsp;So we took a boat to Greenwich.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Where they were &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wharf.co.uk/2011/07/batman-filming-in-greenwich.html&#34;&gt;filming Batman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And I didn&amp;rsquo;t know until after we&amp;rsquo;d left.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gutted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WTSxxolJIlg/TkY7vahoneI/AAAAAAAAIJ8/VIteMVNt6Uo/s1600/Sky.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WTSxxolJIlg/TkY7vahoneI/AAAAAAAAIJ8/VIteMVNt6Uo/s400/Sky.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Friday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sun finally makes an appearance. I was going to write a blog post, but I refuse to be indoors on a sunny day if I can get outside for some Vitamin D production (and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t bought my &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.apple.com/uk/browse/home/shop_mac/family/macbook_air&#34;&gt;new shiny&lt;/a&gt; then).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sat in the park, sunbathed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brilliant day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brilliant week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
