<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>london on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/london/</link>
    <description>Recent content in london on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The birth of a new community</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community/</guid>
      <description>Topping off my mini-tour at the end of May, I was invited to Rotterdam to present to a brand new community of developers. I was really interested in attending because my experience with user groups is pretty much limited to the London Java Community, and I knew this would be different due to being a) across a wider range of technologies and b) shiny and new.
It was hosted (rather awesomely) in a brewery, and until then I&amp;rsquo;d never given a presentation in a pub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2012</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2012/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m late with my write-up of QCon, and what&amp;rsquo;s worse, it will be partial - &amp;ldquo;sadly&amp;rdquo; I was in Lanzarote on a training week with the running club from the Thursday (8th) so I missed most of it. A sacrifice I had to make for 7 days in the sunshine….
Firstly, me me meI presented the talk I previewed at Skillsmatter the previous week, something I was calling the User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Disruptor, but actually turned out to be how-can-Trish-fill-95-slides-with-pictures-and-finish-in-under-40-minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Did On My Holidays</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/what_i_did_on_my_holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/what_i_did_on_my_holidays/</guid>
      <description>And now, a post for my long-neglected, less technical readers.
I took a week off in July to try and avoid that Oh My God I Missed Summer Again feeling. Granted, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get that in the UK even if you&amp;rsquo;re not stuck in an office the entire time.
Really this is just an excuse to post some photos on the blog.
Monday
Hopped on the bike and explored from Kensington to Westminster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>