<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jobs on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jobs on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Advice for Programmers (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers/</guid>
      <description>Since I have a tendancy to bang on every now and again about how we, as developers, could do better in managing our careers (for example, by creating CVs that don&amp;rsquo;t suck, and by staying ahead of the curve), Dave Thomas asked me to speak for a mere 50 minutes on the subject at GOTO Aarhus, a talk I wasn&amp;rsquo;t enormously happy with as there was no way to cover a lifetime of hard-fought experience in such a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Etiquette</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/linkedin_etiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/linkedin_etiquette/</guid>
      <description>For no reason other than LinkedIn communications are starting to irritate me, here&amp;rsquo;s my personal LinkedIn Etiquette guide. Feel free to disagree with it all.
 I&amp;rsquo;m not going to accept invitations from recruiters. Not just because I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for a job (who knows what the future holds?), but because I believe it shows a lack of respect to my network to bring recruiters one step closer to being able to contact them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying Ahead of the Curve</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/staying_ahead_of_the_curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/staying_ahead_of_the_curve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had an interesting discussion last night at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; developer sessions, and
it&amp;rsquo;s a topic that comes up again and again:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make your CV Not Suck</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/how_to_make_your_cv_not_suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/how_to_make_your_cv_not_suck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re applying for a job at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lmax.com/&#34;&gt;LMAX&lt;/a&gt;, your CV (or résumé, for our American readers) usually comes through me and I decide whether
to call you for a technical phone screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to let you into a secret.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you an awesome developer?</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/are_you_an_awesome_developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/are_you_an_awesome_developer/</guid>
      <description>We are hiring!
If you think we&amp;rsquo;re doing something interesting, or if you think you can help us do our thing even better, come join us. &amp;nbsp;Your boss will be the dude who wrote Continuous Delivery, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a chance to experience what Danny calls meta-Agile (or Agile Agile), and you&amp;rsquo;ll really start to care about Domain-Driven Design.
Ideally we&amp;rsquo;re after Java people, but at the heart of it we want people who are dead passionate about development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Hunting</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/job_hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/job_hunting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt a lot professionally and personally during my time here in New York, but the time has come to go back &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo;.I&amp;rsquo;ll be relocating to London in September. I guess it won&amp;rsquo;t hurt to mention on here that I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking for an exciting new job when I get back there. Check out my LinkedIn profile if you are in the market for a Java tech team lead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>