<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Intellij on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/intellij/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IntelliJ Tricks I Learnt Today</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/stuff_i_learnt_about_intellij/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/stuff_i_learnt_about_intellij/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Day three of my &lt;a href=&#34;/new_year_new_adventures&#34;&gt;brand new job&lt;/a&gt; - woohoo!  One of my first tasks is checking the documentation
of IntelliJ, since I&amp;rsquo;m
already a &amp;ldquo;Power User&amp;rdquo;, to see if there&amp;rsquo;s stuff missing that someone like me might want to see. Firstly, a confession -
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;ve actually read the IntelliJ documentation before.  I mean, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; read it.  Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ve dipped
into it when I needed to know something, I&amp;rsquo;ve searched for help with specific items, but like many developers, I tend to
use something first rather than read the documentation first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what, today I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt a whole bunch of useful things IntelliJ can do that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t previously known,
and they&amp;rsquo;re the sorts of things you would only stumble over if a) you read the docs (pah!) or b) you watched someone
else using the tool and saw them doing something you didn&amp;rsquo;t know was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s today&amp;rsquo;s list, and feel free to laugh at me and be smug in my direction if you already knew these things (note: I
have upgraded to IntelliJ 14, and at the time of writing I don&amp;rsquo;t know which of these features are new and which are
simply previously undiscovered):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Navigate directly to an action or option&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press Shift+Ctrl+A (Windows) or Shift+Cmd+A (Mac) and start typing the name of the thing you want to do, or the setting
you want to change. I&amp;rsquo;ve found this especially useful now I&amp;rsquo;m back on Windows and I don&amp;rsquo;t have that nice helpful typing
box on the help menu that will take me straight to the menu item I want.  But what&amp;rsquo;s most useful about this for me today,
as I&amp;rsquo;m setting up a new profile on a new laptop (more on the new laptop later, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t defeat me utterly) is that
from here, you can turn various settings on and off without having to navigate through the settings screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/stuff_i_learnt_about_intellij/action.png&#34; alt=&#34;Navigate to Action&#34; title=&#34;Navigate to Action&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Statement completion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never knew there was a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/IntelliJIDEA/Code+Completion#CodeCompletion-4.Statementcompletion&#34;&gt;shortcut for finishing off a statement&lt;/a&gt;,
all that Java boilerplate you need to keep the compiler happy - semi colons and curly brackets and everything.  But
there is, and I can see it being super useful, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re using other bits of IntelliJ code completion to
create the core of your line of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Issue tracker integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure loads of people are already using integration with their favourite issue tracker, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really thought
about this as something that I really cared about.  But I was watching the intro videos for YouTrack (not surprisingly
I&amp;rsquo;ll be using this instead of Jira during my time at JetBrains) and when I saw
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/youtrack/documentation/&#34;&gt;how the IDE integration worked&lt;/a&gt;, I
suddenly realised how this small thing can add up to save thousands of keystrokes over time, not to mention saving
precious navigational seconds and window-switching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, just the ability to generate at least the start of the commit message is a saving in time, and adds to project
consistency if all your developers are doing the same thing.  On my last project we only just realised we all quoted the
Jira issues in subtly different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Settings shortcut keys&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I initially started using IntelliJ in anger back in 2008, I was very much a point-and-click type user. Over time,
pair programming with keyboard-super-users and giving live demos with very limited time available, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked harder
to become a keyboard-shortcuts person.  With the latest version of IntelliJ, I can&amp;rsquo;t find the tiny icons I use to get to
the settings window, something that I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a lot as I set up the new IDE instance on the new laptop.  So I bit
the bullet and learnt the keyboard shortcuts, and it&amp;rsquo;s already saving me a bunch of time (on the rare occasions when the
aforementioned &amp;ldquo;Navigate to Action&amp;rdquo; fails me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ctrl+Alt+S for the settings dialog (appears to be Cmd + , on the Mac)
Shift+Ctrl+Alt+S for the project structure dialog (appears to be Cmd + ; on the Mac)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/stuff_i_learnt_about_intellij/settings.png&#34; alt=&#34;Settings Shortcuts&#34; title=&#34;Settings Shortcuts&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah.  I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I wasn&amp;rsquo;t already using those either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Selecting the negative&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use completion/suggestions all the time from IntelliJ, I&amp;rsquo;m far too lazy to type everything.  What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise, is
that you don&amp;rsquo;t just have to accept the default they give you.  If, for example, IntelliJ suggests a boolean value, you
can get it to negate that value by selecting it with &amp;ldquo;!&amp;rdquo; instead of enter or tab.  Yes, I know I&amp;rsquo;ve done a horrible job
of explaining that, but take a look at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/IntelliJIDEA/Code+Completion#CodeCompletion-5.Negatingcompletion&#34;&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt;
and try it, it&amp;rsquo;s quite cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Exclude from Autocomplete&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of code completion, sometimes IntelliJ is sometimes just a bit too keen to suggest something, and you really
will never want that value.  In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve always used &lt;code&gt;Settings -&amp;gt; Editor -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; Auto Import&lt;/code&gt; to manage the
suggestions (the most common one for me is I will never want &lt;code&gt;java.awt.List&lt;/code&gt;, I will almost always want
&lt;code&gt;java.util.List&lt;/code&gt;).  Well, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to go into settings to do this, you can
&lt;a href=&#34;https://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/IntelliJIDEA/Code+Completion#CodeCompletion-9.Excludefromcompletion&#34;&gt;do it from the suggestions themselves&lt;/a&gt; -
navigate to the item you don&amp;rsquo;t want (in my case, &lt;code&gt;java.awt.List&lt;/code&gt;) and press Alt + Enter, this will give you the option
of excluding this from the suggestions in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I found from just one day of browsing the documentation and setting up my IDE from scratch yet again.
Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll promptly forget all these, or maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll be new weapons in my armoury of IDE-fu. Either way, maybe one or
two people will find this useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Adventures</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/new_year_new_adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/new_year_new_adventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just over two years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;/post/and_for_my_next_trick/&#34;&gt;I embarked upon a journey&lt;/a&gt; as a developer / evangelist for a company who was then
called 10gen (who got fed up of saying &amp;ldquo;the MongoDB people&amp;rdquo;, and transformed into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Inc&lt;/a&gt;). My goals for
this role were: to learn what it was
like working for a company that produced a technology product; to discover what impact working in an open source fashion has; and to
level up my advocacy skills.  I have met all these goals, and more - I met some fantastic people; learnt different approaches to
software development; discovered my new favourite database for creating applications; moved to Spain; started both a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/&#34;&gt;MUG&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt;;
worked to understand the value of community and evangelism, and to help create a strategy for these areas;
and my evangelism efforts and open source work earned me the &lt;a href=&#34;https://java.net/website/java-champions/bios.html#Gee&#34;&gt;Java Champion&lt;/a&gt; title.
I&amp;rsquo;m extremely proud of what I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved over this period, and very grateful to MongoDB for giving me these opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, a new adventure is about to begin.  If you&amp;rsquo;ve seen my &lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/&#34;&gt;live coding demo&lt;/a&gt;
this year, you&amp;rsquo;ll know of my love affair with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;,
a tool I use daily (even for blogging). Well, now I&amp;rsquo;m joining the team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt;,
where I&amp;rsquo;m going Full Advocate. I &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; this means I get to carry on doing more of what I love - presenting, writing,
and working on demos to help developers become more productive. I hope this will give me opportunities to stay ahead of the curve in the
Java/JVM world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, in answer to the Most Frequently Asked Question, I am staying in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen in love with Sevilla and I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to
leave yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/Sevilla.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sevilla Cathedral&#34; title=&#34;Sevilla Cathedral&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall leave you with my somewhat disasterous &amp;ldquo;Top Ten IntelliJ Tips&amp;rdquo; from GOTO Aarhus, which is worth watching just to see Dan North
save me from the curse of the live demo.  Things can only get better from here, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/QsHasoJUgKo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
