<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers want to be heard</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/developers_want_to_be_heard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/developers_want_to_be_heard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaadvent.com/2014/12/developers-want-to-be-heard.html&#34;&gt;piece for the Java Advent Blog&lt;/a&gt;,
about how developers aren&amp;rsquo;t just communing with the computer, they also need to feel listened to by real human beings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaadvent.com/2014/12/developers-want-to-be-heard.html&#34;&gt;Read it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Adventures</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/new_year_new_adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/new_year_new_adventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just over two years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;/post/and_for_my_next_trick/&#34;&gt;I embarked upon a journey&lt;/a&gt; as a developer / evangelist for a company who was then
called 10gen (who got fed up of saying &amp;ldquo;the MongoDB people&amp;rdquo;, and transformed into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Inc&lt;/a&gt;). My goals for
this role were: to learn what it was
like working for a company that produced a technology product; to discover what impact working in an open source fashion has; and to
level up my advocacy skills.  I have met all these goals, and more - I met some fantastic people; learnt different approaches to
software development; discovered my new favourite database for creating applications; moved to Spain; started both a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/&#34;&gt;MUG&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt;;
worked to understand the value of community and evangelism, and to help create a strategy for these areas;
and my evangelism efforts and open source work earned me the &lt;a href=&#34;https://java.net/website/java-champions/bios.html#Gee&#34;&gt;Java Champion&lt;/a&gt; title.
I&amp;rsquo;m extremely proud of what I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved over this period, and very grateful to MongoDB for giving me these opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, a new adventure is about to begin.  If you&amp;rsquo;ve seen my &lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/&#34;&gt;live coding demo&lt;/a&gt;
this year, you&amp;rsquo;ll know of my love affair with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;,
a tool I use daily (even for blogging). Well, now I&amp;rsquo;m joining the team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt;,
where I&amp;rsquo;m going Full Advocate. I &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; this means I get to carry on doing more of what I love - presenting, writing,
and working on demos to help developers become more productive. I hope this will give me opportunities to stay ahead of the curve in the
Java/JVM world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, in answer to the Most Frequently Asked Question, I am staying in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen in love with Sevilla and I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to
leave yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/Sevilla.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sevilla Cathedral&#34; title=&#34;Sevilla Cathedral&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall leave you with my somewhat disasterous &amp;ldquo;Top Ten IntelliJ Tips&amp;rdquo; from GOTO Aarhus, which is worth watching just to see Dan North
save me from the curse of the live demo.  Things can only get better from here, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/QsHasoJUgKo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Speaker Diversity</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/more_female_speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/more_female_speakers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last month at Devoxx I was in a session discussing what we can do to encourage more diversity in our speakers (specifically,
although not limited to, increasing the number of women speakers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to outline the things I remember being discussed, although as usual we did not find the answer to the problem,
only identify some issues and explore some options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very chaotic blog post, because if I don&amp;rsquo;t post it now I&amp;rsquo;ll never post it, and it&amp;rsquo;s better if my thoughts are scrawled down and
posted than if this all goes to die in my drafts folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Firstly, what stops people from stepping up to speak?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the very first thing any developer says when you ask them why they haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about presenting at conferences or user
groups. Turns out, you always have something to say.  For example, our most popular sessions at the Sevilla JUG and MUG are &amp;ldquo;Introduction
 to&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;. You hear from plenty of experts who have travelled the whole road to some pinnacle of excellence,
 but what many developers need is simply someone a couple of steps ahead of them to lead them forwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You always know more than &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt;, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to know everything, and you don&amp;rsquo;t need to know more than everyone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I be role model?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So many women feel this, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely sympathetic to this view point: I&amp;rsquo;m a woman developer, getting along, happy in my job,
happy being a programmer, why the hell should I have to stand up and present and blog and be a role model for other women? Men don&amp;rsquo;t have
to do that. Men can &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; be developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, there&amp;rsquo;s the fear that if you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; stand up, become a role model, that somehow people will think you&amp;rsquo;re representing all
women developers. You&amp;rsquo;ll be worried because you can only represent who you are, what you do, you can&amp;rsquo;t represent a whole gender in a
single presentation or a single interview.  And the pressure! What if I mess up? What if I say something my gender does not agree with?
What if I say something that causes my whole gender to be judged?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally understandable fears. Totally true that many people will ask you to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; woman developer, to answer for all women.  Well,
that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m asking more women to stand up, to be role models - if we all step up, it will no longer just be me, and you,
and that other one over there. There&amp;rsquo;ll be more of us, more differing voices, we&amp;rsquo;ll stand out less. But we have to stand up first.  And
in the meantime it&amp;rsquo;s us and our points of view they&amp;rsquo;re listening to. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you rather voice your opinion than have someone else speak
on your behalf? Especially when very few people really can represent you, who you are and what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I can&amp;rsquo;t answer the questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised at what you do know, so people who present run into this less than you&amp;rsquo;d think, even if you&amp;rsquo;re just beginning,
but just in case here are some tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat the question, paraphrasing. Firstly, this ensures you&amp;rsquo;ve actually heard the question correctly. Secondly,
it allows the whole audience to hear it, and thirdly, but most importantly, it buys you time to think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be honest - say you don&amp;rsquo;t know, and move on. If you know somewhere that might have the answer,
point the person to that resource.  But a technical audience actually values the answer &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; more than you think. Especially
the person who asked the question, it makes them feel really smart!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, but you think the audience might know, throw it back to them. Either to the person who asked the question,
if that feels appropriate (especially if this is one of those &amp;ldquo;look how smart I am&amp;rdquo; questions),
or to the audience as a whole. In conferences in particular, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance someone there knows the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re genuinely terrified of all questions, say at the start of the presentation that you won&amp;rsquo;t take questions in the talk. Offer
an alternative, like via Twitter or e-mail, if you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;What can conference organisers do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specifically invite the people you want presenting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Don&amp;rsquo;t just wait for them to submit. If you want more women, more diversity, invite them. And invite them early&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure your women presenters early.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Recognise that there are relatively few women presenters on &amp;ldquo;the circuit&amp;rdquo;, and understand that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; wants them to speak at their
conference. This rare breed, the female technical presenter, gets booked up &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt; in advance.  They&amp;rsquo;re probably as in-demand as your
keynote speakers, and can probably devote less time to appearing at conferences than those who have made it to keynote-standard (I&amp;rsquo;m
making a sweeping generalisation that your techy women have day-jobs as developers and your keynote speakers are either professional
presenters or at least can argue presenting as a critical part of their job).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you have a limited resource (experienced women presenters) that&amp;rsquo;s in high demand. You need to reach out directly to them,
invite them, and secure them well in advance of your conference.  Many big conferences, for example JavaOne and QCon,
will invite speakers six months in advance. If you give women speakers a month&amp;rsquo;s notice before your conference or event,
they simply are not going to have the space in their schedule at that late notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Showcase your diversity on your website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already heard of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microaggression_theory&#34;&gt;microaggressions&lt;/a&gt;,
go and read what that means before you get any further.  There&amp;rsquo;s a very simple thing you
need to do with your website, whether you&amp;rsquo;ve opened for CFP or you&amp;rsquo;re trying to get attendees to register - make sure the photos on your
website show the type of diversity you want to encourage.  Only yesterday I was looking at the website of a big conference,
who I know for a fact are working &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard to ensure diversity, not just with gender but race, age,
and where possible in less physically obvious dimensions. The conference is many months off, so the only photo they have on the website
is a background photo of the exhibition hall from some previous year, crammed full of attendees - white, male attendees,
as far as it&amp;rsquo;s possible to tell.  It&amp;rsquo;s extremely subtle. You might not even notice, as the photo is behind the headers and text of the
site. But I noticed. And you can be sure the subconscious of every person who went to the website to either submit a proposal for a
talk, or is considering asking their employer to pay for the registration, also noticed.  The conscious mind might be able to shrug it
off.  But the subconscious of a non-white and/or non-male person notices and plants the subtle seed
of &amp;ldquo;this conference is not for me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, conference and event organisers - if you want more women applying to speak at your conference,
show more women on your website.  If you want a more diverse audience, show more diverse faces.  If you&amp;rsquo;ve invited your women presenters
early and secured them early, show their photos on the site - this sends a strong message to other women that their talk proposals will be
taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run warm up nights to try out new speakers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I know conference organisers get &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of submissions, and I know it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell which are going to be good speakers,
especially if they&amp;rsquo;re new speakers or don&amp;rsquo;t have a video.  If you&amp;rsquo;re genuine about improving the diversity of your speakers,
run free nights to a) promote your conference and b) try out new speakers.  Probably a good idea to have a new speaker and a known
speaker to attract the crowd and give newbies a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be so damn picky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New speakers need to be encouraged. Find a way to see their content without just discarding an unknown name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing speakers might not have the luxury of creating new content. Many conferences want genuine practitioners,
not just evangelists, but those people have day jobs and can&amp;rsquo;t be creating a new talk just for your conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leave space for new speakers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;hellip;and don&amp;rsquo;t just have 7 slots for a pro speaker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look at your swag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not just guys t-shirts.  One conference gave out cupcakes for example. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just have to be handbags and high-heeled shoes,
just take a quick look and see if your swag is generally useful for techies, or if it leans towards men only. Men only swag (men&amp;rsquo;s
t-shirts, bottle openers, subtle things like that) subliminally says &amp;ldquo;you don&amp;rsquo;t belong here&amp;rdquo; to the women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give feedback&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can&amp;rsquo;t tell every individual why they were rejected, but you could look at all the rejected submissions and give broad indications of
the type of CFPs that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it. Maybe write a blog post explaining which sorts of talks didn&amp;rsquo;t make it and why.  This will help
speakers create content that better fits your conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be specific about what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you have tracks you&amp;rsquo;re finding content for, put them on the website/CFP, so people know what the topics are. If you have an
idea that you want 30% beginner material and 30% very advanced, make that clear too. Especially if you want &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; beginner or &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt;
advanced. People will submit more appropriate talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a beginner&amp;rsquo;s track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;hellip;not just for the speakers, for the content too. Beginner speakers may be more comfortable presenting &amp;ldquo;Introduction to&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; talks.&lt;br /&gt;
Having a beginners track, whether it&amp;rsquo;s for content or speakers, will make newbies feel more included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;What other things can we try?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User groups can grow talent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice writing CFPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightning talks, book club, different meetup styles (like fishbowl)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run an open conference to encourage new speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women&amp;rsquo;s user groups are instrumental&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So here&amp;rsquo;s something interesting. I&amp;rsquo;m sceptical of all-women user groups as I feel it separates us from the communities we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be
contributing to. But women&amp;rsquo;s user groups can help us to integrate better.  For example, Duchess France helped and encouraged its members
to submit talks to Devoxx, gave feedback on CFPs before they were submitted, and provided a safe place for the women to practice
presenting beforehand.  I think this is exactly the sort of thing women&amp;rsquo;s user groups could be fantastic for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Advice for budding speakers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just Do It&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more you do it, the more comfortable you&amp;rsquo;ll be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a speaker, it can make you feel less of an impostor at a conference - you&amp;rsquo;re not just a woman developer, you&amp;rsquo;re a speaker!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s afraid, it&amp;rsquo;s not just you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every developer wants to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The audience is on your side&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start Small (user groups)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be technical. But you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be super smart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bootstrapping is hard - you haven&amp;rsquo;t presented so you can&amp;rsquo;t get into conferences. Again, user groups can help with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair. Ask a more experienced presenter if you can co-present with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for mentors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; is perfectly acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate there is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much more I could have covered, and many topics deserve more depth. But this is the brain dump from the Devoxx
session, and maybe one day things will be expanded into their own topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not waste, it&#39;s learning</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/its_not_waste_its_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/its_not_waste_its_learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one my my rare weekends at home, I found myself on a pottery course (this is the sort of thing that happens when you&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; person).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/its_not_waste_its_learning/pottery-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;OK, not pottery, horses. The course was on a farm.&#34; title=&#34;OK, not pottery, horses. The course was on a farm.&#34; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;OK, not pottery, horses. The course was on a farm.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a fantastic time on the course, there was something enormously satisfactory and therapeutic about working with my hands,
on something creative that was for me, and only me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/its_not_waste_its_learning/pottery-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My first bowl&#34; title=&#34;My first bowl&#34; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;Honestly, I think the one I did in primary school when I was seven was better.&lt;br /&gt;
And I don&amp;rsquo;t care, because I loved creating it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that really struck me that day was embracing failure and destruction as part of the creative process.  Let me give you a
couple of examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teacher showed us several techniques for creating pottery, one of which was using plaster moulds and very liquid clay to produce more
complex items (for example, mugs and animal figures).  He told us that when using a new mould,
the first few items would be useless.  But these &amp;ldquo;failures&amp;rdquo; are an important process for the mould itself.  The
class was in Spanish, so my understanding was imperfect, but I think it was something to do with the fact that the plaster moulds are
supposed to absorb water, and therefore I assume at the beginning they absorb far too much and the clay ends up being too dry and brittle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/its_not_waste_its_learning/pottery-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pottery created with moulds&#34; title=&#34;Pottery created with moulds&#34; /&gt;

 &lt;figcaption&gt;Pottery created with moulds&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second example was when he showed us why it was so difficult to create a clay plate - bowls, mugs, cups were fine,
but a plate is difficult as it&amp;rsquo;s flat and the shape doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough structure for it to have any rigidity  if it&amp;rsquo;s even slightly damp
(and clay stays damp for a looong time, even in a climate like Seville&amp;rsquo;s). He demonstrated this by cutting straight through the plate
that he&amp;rsquo;d put into the mould earlier and folding it up, to the collective intake of breath of the whole class - a class of people of a range
of ages and backgrounds. We seem socially programmed to find destruction of any kind upsetting (which is probably, overall,
not a bad thing), when the teacher sliced the plate in half to demonstrate how floppy the plate was, we were all disturbed by this waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/its_not_waste_its_learning/pottery-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My pieces&#34; title=&#34;My pieces&#34; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;Even when I broke my bowl when preparing it for the kiln, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to abandon it - I turned it into a
candle holder&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing - it&amp;rsquo;s clay.  Clay is mud.  It&amp;rsquo;s from the ground.  Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s almost completely reusable.  All of the leftover
clay from our earlier exercises, all of the excess liquid clay from the moulds, all of the pieces that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it,
it was put aside and saved for later.  It&amp;rsquo;s not a waste.  It&amp;rsquo;s learning.  It&amp;rsquo;s experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got me thinking.  If we can be like that about something concrete, something that exists in the real world,
why aren&amp;rsquo;t we like that about something as ephemeral as code?  Why are we so afraid to throw away code? And don&amp;rsquo;t tell me we&amp;rsquo;re not
afraid - how many &amp;ldquo;spikes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;prototypes&amp;rdquo; have you seen running in production?  Have you read people talking about
creating code and throwing it away, and thought &amp;ldquo;that sounds nice, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to just producing useful code&amp;rdquo;? (Note: I&amp;rsquo;m not
talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000069.html&#34;&gt;throwing away perfectly good production code&lt;/a&gt;,
nor am I talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://codesqueeze.com/refactorbation/&#34;&gt;refactorbation&lt;/a&gt;, a term I just discovered and love.
I&amp;rsquo;m talking about creating for research, spikes, learning etc, and then throwing it away).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/its_not_waste_its_learning/pottery-6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Java&#34; title=&#34;Java&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;What?? I needed to carve something into the medallion&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1477800670/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1477800670&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=5KXFITDLKQQCXD3K&#34;&gt;Build Your Routine, Find Your Focus, and Sharpen Your Creative Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1477800670&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;,
and there&amp;rsquo;s a section in there that talks about getting into the habit of
creating just for the sake of creating.  Not for your side projects, not for a client, not even for your portfolio.  Simply to get into
the habit of creating.  &lt;em&gt;Maybe&lt;/em&gt; some of those ideas, or processes, will come in handy later down the line.  Or maybe,
like the clay moulds, simply creating something for throwing away actually helps the overall process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiences have left me with a feeling that I should start getting used to the idea of throwing code away,
and start creating things for no reason other than the feeling of creating.  It could be like running - in theory I run so I have to
worry less about my weight and my fitness, but actually I run &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more frequently when I run just for the joy of running. The fitness
and health are side benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we&amp;rsquo;re so reluctant to throw code away precisely because it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; ephemeral.  Maybe with the clay,
we can see that concrete thing, that mud, being turned into something useful eventually.  With running,
you can feel the difference in your attitude, in your fitness, maybe see it on the scales. With code, when you delete those characters,
revert that change, you feel like you lost something, and have nothing to show for that precious time.  When actually you created new
pathways in your brain, added new memories and learnt new lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;m ready yet to create just for the sake of creating, I think I&amp;rsquo;m just too results-driven. But I&amp;rsquo;m going to
write about it here to remind myself that it is something I want to do. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s the exercise, not the end result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/its_not_waste_its_learning/pottery-7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The full haul&#34; title=&#34;The full haul&#34; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;The final pieces, still needing the kiln to finish the glaze.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB London</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mongodb_london/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mongodb_london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt;, 6th November, 50% off with discount code &lt;strong&gt;50Trisha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt; is nearly upon us again,
and I&amp;rsquo;m dead disappointed I can&amp;rsquo;t make it this year (I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2014/presentation/Party%20Keynote:%20Staying%20Ahead%20of%20the%20Curve&#34;&gt;keynoting at GOTO Berlin&lt;/a&gt; instead,
which I&amp;rsquo;m terrified, I mean, excited, about). The last MongoDB London was really interesting for me - I was fairly new to the company,
I&amp;rsquo;d been here less than six months, and it was a really great way to go both broad and deep on the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was trying to find a blog post where I talked about my experiences, but it looks like I only wrote that In My Mind. In fact,
I only only wrote two whole lines of notes on the conference.  But 18 months later I clearly remember presentations from my colleagues
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Ross&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://derickrethans.nl/&#34;&gt;Derick&lt;/a&gt; demonstrating the geo capabilities in MongoDB,
presentations which heavily influenced the &lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/&#34;&gt;live coding demo&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving
recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also remember Eliot&amp;rsquo;s presentation - Eliot is one of those people who totally gets away with breaking the &amp;ldquo;speak in a measured,
clear fashion&amp;rdquo; presenters rule, he fires fascinating information at you at high speed and it&amp;rsquo;s actually one of the compelling things
about his talks. If you ever get a chance to see him talk about the product, it&amp;rsquo;s totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, the most awesome thing about the conference was the chance to meet, and talk to,
a bunch of different MongoDB people - there are the engineers who work on the product (like me and my colleagues);
the people leading the way with the technology, like Eliot; and finally, but for me most importantly,
you get to meet really interesting people who are using MongoDB in ways that you might not even imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway the point of this sales pitch is, whether you&amp;rsquo;re using MongoDB already or you&amp;rsquo;re keen to find out about it,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt; is only going to take a day from your life,
and you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a bunch of interesting things. And, with a Special Discount Code from me,
it&amp;rsquo;s only £45! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mongodb-london-2014-registration-13140209721&#34;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt; with code &lt;strong&gt;50Trisha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Groovy to import XML into MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been demonstrating how easy it is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRrSAkEAnZQ&#34;&gt;create modern web apps using AngularJS,
Java and MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.  I also use Groovy during this demo to do the sorts of things Groovy is
really good at - writing descriptive tests, and creating scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the time pressures in the demo, I never really get a chance to go into the details of the script I use,
so the aim of this long-overdue blog post is to go over this Groovy script in a bit more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly I want to clarify that this is not my original work - I &lt;strike&gt;stole&lt;/strike&gt; borrowed most of the ideas for the demo from my
colleague Ross Lawley. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/posts/the-most-popular-pub-name/&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; he goes into detail of how he built
up an application that
finds the most popular pub names in the UK.  There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/posts/the-most-popular-pub-name/#toc_1&#34;&gt;section in there&lt;/a&gt;
where he talks about downloading the open street map data and using python to convert the XML into something more MongoDB-friendly - it&amp;rsquo;s
this process that I basically stole, re-worked for coffee shops, and re-wrote for the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m assuming if you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Java for any period of time, there has come a moment where you needed to use it to parse XML. Since my
demo is supposed to be all about how easy it is to work with Java, I did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; want to do this. When I wrote the demo I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really all
that familiar with Groovy, but what I did know was that it has built in support for parsing and manipulating XML,
which is exactly what I wanted to do. In addition, creating &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/Collections#Collections-Mapsmaps&#34;&gt;Maps&lt;/a&gt; (the
data structures, not the geographical ones) with Groovy is really easy, and this is effectively what we need to insert into
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Goal of the Script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parse an XML file containing open street map data of all coffee shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract latitude and longitude XML attributes and transform into
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-geojson&#34;&gt;MongoDB GeoJSON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform some basic validation on the coffee shop data from the XML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert into MongoDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure MongoDB knows this contains query-able geolocation data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/blob/java-one/src/main/scripts/PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34;&gt;PopulateDatabase.groovy&lt;/a&gt;,
that link will take you to the version I presented at JavaOne:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript.png&#34; alt=&#34;PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34; title=&#34;PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Firstly, we need data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the same service Ross used in his blog post to obtain the XML file containing &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rdquo; coffee shops around the world. Now,
the open street map data is somewhat&amp;hellip; raw and unstructured (which is why MongoDB is such a great tool for storing it),
so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I really have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the coffee shops, but I obtained enough data for an interesting demo using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.overpass-api.de/api/xapi?*[amenity=cafe][cuisine=coffee_shop]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/blob/master/src/main/scripts/resources/all-coffee-shops.xml&#34;&gt;resulting XML file&lt;/a&gt; is in the
github project, but if you try this yourself you might (in fact, probably will) get different results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each XML record looks something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;node id=&amp;quot;178821166&amp;quot; lat=&amp;quot;40.4167226&amp;quot; lon=&amp;quot;-3.7069112&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;amenity&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;cafe&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;cuisine&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;coffee_shop&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;name&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;Chocolatería San Ginés&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;wheelchair&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;limited&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;wikipedia&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;es:Chocolatería San Ginés&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/node&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each coffee shop has a unique identifier and a latitude and longitude as attributes of a &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt; element.  Within this node is a series
of &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; elements, all with &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; attributes. Each coffee shop has a varying number of these attributes,
and they are not consistent from shop to shop (other than &lt;code&gt;amenity&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;cuisine&lt;/code&gt; which we used to select this data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Initialisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Script Initialisation&#34; title=&#34;Script Initialisation&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything else we want to prepare the database.  The assumption of this script is that either the
collection we want to store the coffee shops in is empty, or full of stale data.  So we&amp;rsquo;re going to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/ecosystem/drivers/java/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt; to get the collection that we&amp;rsquo;re interested in, and then drop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s two interesting things to note here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Groovy script is simply using the basic Java driver.  Groovy can talk quite happily to vanilla Java,
it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to use a Groovy library.  There are Groovy-specific libraries for talking to MongoDB (e.g. the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://grails.org/plugin/mongodb&#34;&gt;MongoDB GORM Plugin&lt;/a&gt;), but the Java driver works perfectly well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-database&#34;&gt;databases&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-collection&#34;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt; (collections are
a bit like tables, but less structured) explicitly in MongoDB.  You simply use the database and collection you&amp;rsquo;re interested in,
and if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist, the server will create them for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we&amp;rsquo;re just using the default constructor for the &lt;code&gt;MongoClient&lt;/code&gt;, the class that represents the connection to the database
server(s).  This default is localhost:27017, which is where I happen to be running the database.  However you can specify your own
address and port - for more details on this see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94065240033/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-i&#34;&gt;Getting Started With MongoDB and Java&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Turn the XML into something MongoDB-shaped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Parse &amp;amp; Transform XML&#34; title=&#34;Parse &amp;amp; Transform XML&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next we&amp;rsquo;re going to use Groovy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/api/groovy/util/XmlSlurper.html&#34;&gt;XmlSlurper&lt;/a&gt; to read the open street map
XML data that we talked about earlier.  To iterate over every node we use: &lt;code&gt;xmlSlurper.node.each&lt;/code&gt;.  For those of you who are new to
Groovy or new to Java 8, you might notice this is using a closure to define the behaviour to apply for every &amp;ldquo;node&amp;rdquo; element in the XML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Create GeoJSON&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Create GeoJSON&#34; title=&#34;Create GeoJSON&#34; /&gt;

Since MongoDB documents are effectively just maps of key-value pairs, we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a Map &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt; that contains the
document structure that represents the coffee shop that we want to save into the database.  Firstly,
we initialise this map with the attributes of the &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt;. Remember these attributes are something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;node id=&amp;quot;18464077&amp;quot; lat=&amp;quot;-33.8911183&amp;quot; lon=&amp;quot;151.1958773&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to save the ID as a value for a new field called &lt;code&gt;openStreetMapId&lt;/code&gt;. We need to do something a bit more
complicated with the latitude and longitude, since we need to store them as GeoJSON, which looks something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ &#39;location&#39; : { &#39;coordinates&#39;: [&amp;lt;longitude&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;latitude&amp;gt;],
                 &#39;type&#39;       : &#39;Point&#39; } }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lines 12-14 you can see that we create a &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt; that looks like the GeoJSON, pulling the &lt;code&gt;lat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;lon&lt;/code&gt; attributes into the appropriate
places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Insert Remaining Fields&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Insert Remaining Fields&#34; title=&#34;Insert Remaining Fields&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Validate Field Name&#34; title=&#34;Validate Field Name&#34; /&gt;

Now for every &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; element in the XML, we get the &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; attribute and check if it&amp;rsquo;s a valid field name for MongoDB (it won&amp;rsquo;t let us
insert fields with a dot in, and we don&amp;rsquo;t want to override our carefully constructed &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; field). If so we simply add this key as the
field and its the matching &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; attribute as the value into the map. This effectively copies the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; key/value data into key/value pairs in the MongoDB document so we don&amp;rsquo;t lose any data,
but we also don&amp;rsquo;t do anything particularly interesting to transform it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Save Into MongoDB&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Save Into MongoDB&#34; title=&#34;Save Into MongoDB&#34; /&gt;

Finally, once we&amp;rsquo;ve created a simple &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt; Map representing the document we want to save into MongoDB,
we insert it into MongoDB if the map has a field called &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;.  We could have checked this when we were reading the XML and putting it
into the map, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually much easier just to use the pretty Groovy syntax to check for a key called &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we want to insert the Map we need to turn this into a &lt;code&gt;BasicDBObject&lt;/code&gt;, the Java Driver&amp;rsquo;s document type,
but this is easily done by calling the constructor that takes a Map.  Alternatively, there&amp;rsquo;s a Groovy syntax which would effectively do
the same thing, which you might prefer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;collection.insert(coffeeShop as BasicDBObject)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Tell MongoDB that we want to perform Geo queries on this data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add Geo Index&#34; title=&#34;Add Geo Index&#34; /&gt;

Because we&amp;rsquo;re going to do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/operator/query/nearSphere/&#34;&gt;nearSphere&lt;/a&gt; query on this data,
we need to add a &amp;ldquo;2dsphere&amp;rdquo; index on our location field. We created the &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; field as GeoJSON,
so all we need to do is call &lt;code&gt;createIndex&lt;/code&gt; for this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it!  Groovy is a nice tool for this sort of script-y thing - not only is it a scripting language,
but its built-in support for XML, really nice Map syntax and support for closures makes it the perfect tool for iterating over XML data
and transforming it into something that can be inserted into a MongoDB collection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2014, Day One</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m at JavaOne again, and after only one day I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt stuff.  And, of course,
had a great time catching up with interesting people.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=10289&#34;&gt;Superpowered CI with Git - Sarah Goff-Dupont&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Continuous Integration we did at LMAX is quite different to what we do at MongoDB, and I was hoping to get some tips on better CI with
Git, especially given feature branches.  There was a good overview of development process using branch-per-feature,
 and a comment that it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible to do &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; CI in this sort of environment.  But there was pragmatic advice on how to manage
 the process and run automated builds in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The take-home point for me is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to investigate &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks&#34;&gt;git hooks&lt;/a&gt; to try and
  streamline our process and run some fast checks more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Sarah showed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hipchat.com&#34;&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt; in anger - I&amp;rsquo;ve now heard this mentioned enough that I&amp;rsquo;m going to look into it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2276&#34;&gt;Advanced Unit Testing with Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve [spoken before about Spock](&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/tags/spock/), and how much I love it.  The first section of this talk was a recap
of some of the basics, but the second part went on to some features I either previously ignored or wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of.  For example, in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt;, we do use annotations to denote slower-running tests so we can select which environments to run in,
but we&amp;rsquo;re not using Spock annotations for this.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more we could do with both custom annotations like our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/blob/3.0.x/util/src/main/category/Slow.java&#34;&gt;@Slow&lt;/a&gt; annotation,
Spock&amp;rsquo;s built in annotations like &lt;code&gt;@Issue&lt;/code&gt;, and some others which may not yet be in maven central like &lt;code&gt;@Requires&lt;/code&gt; for running
language-version tests (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/JavaLanguageSpec
.groovy&#34;&gt;e.g. Java 8 tests&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;@IgnoreRest&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also liked the example of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/OldExampleSpec.groovy&#34;&gt;checking the new value against an old
value&lt;/a&gt;,
I can totally see this being useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other bits and pieces in this talk I&amp;rsquo;d like to dig into in more detail that I think will be very useful for the Java Driver.
But even more importantly, I learnt how to zoom into my screen so I can use that in my own presentation. Pro presentation top tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you have even minor testing pains, it&amp;rsquo;s worth finding Ken&amp;rsquo;s talks on Spock, they&amp;rsquo;re great! And a source of inspiration for
better testing, as well as a sneaky way to understand why Groovy is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCP Awards and Party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But it&amp;rsquo;s not all work at these events.  For me, the highlight was the music at at the JCP Awards party.  Firstly,
we had an award-winning beat-box guy from the UK (sadly I don&amp;rsquo;t remember his name so I can&amp;rsquo;t link to his stuff).  An unusual choice for
an event like this, but it was a lot of fun. Then there was the live super-band, The Null Pointers, made up of JUG leaders from around the
world (including &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matkar&#34;&gt;@matkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/frankgreco&#34;&gt;@frankgreco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fguime&#34;&gt;@fguime&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit,
 I was a little concerned about this idea, but the guys were fantastic, and it was a lot of fun singing along to Free&amp;rsquo;s Alright Now and
 Radiohead&amp;rsquo;s Creep. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/openworld/appreciation-event/index.html&#34;&gt;Aerosmith&lt;/a&gt; is going to have to work hard to compete with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;and a quick plug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=1703&#34;&gt;main presentation is on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a keyword-tastic live demo of AngularJS, Java &amp;amp; MongoDB.  Something &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; goes wrong in
this presentation, so I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://doodle.com/fvrasw9vrpxyb9dm&#34;&gt;taking bets right now on what that will be&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with MongoDB and Java</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_started_with_mongodb_and_java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_started_with_mongodb_and_java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been missing an introduction to using MongoDB from Java for a little while now - there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of information in &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/ecosystem/drivers/java/&#34;&gt;the
documentation&lt;/a&gt;, but we were lacking a step-by-step guide to getting started as a Java
developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sought to rectify this with a couple of blog posts for the MongoDB official blog: the first, an introduction to using MongoDB from
Java, including a non-comprehensive list of some of the libraries you can use; the second, an introductory guide to simple CRUD
operations using the Java driver:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94065240033/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-i&#34;&gt;Getting Started with MongoDB and Java, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94724924068/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-ii&#34;&gt;Getting Started with MongoDB and Java, Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very much aimed at Java/JVM developers who are new to MongoDB, and want to get a feel for how you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guides are for the current (2.x) driver. When we release 3.x, we&amp;rsquo;ll release updated guides as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla Java User Group Java 8 Launch Party</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_java8_launch_party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_java8_launch_party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night at the Sevilla JUG we officially celebrated the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/&#34;&gt;Java 8&lt;/a&gt; - yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Bt48HX7IQAAQBQq.jpg:large&#34; alt=&#34;Partay&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled by the picture, people had more fun than it looks.  Honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who missed the session, or who was there and wants access to the materials, here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/lambda-streams-java-8&#34;&gt;The Main Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/happy-mappy&#34;&gt;Trisha&amp;rsquo;s real-life lambda code&lt;/a&gt; (the class we were looking at was &lt;code&gt;TweetDecorator&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/SimonRitter/javase8-55thingsv2-sritter&#34;&gt;slide deck&lt;/a&gt; of another of Simon&amp;rsquo;s
presentations, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rtAredKhyac&#34;&gt;55 New Features in Java SE 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the last link is to a video from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/virtualJUG/&#34;&gt;vJUG&lt;/a&gt;, the Virtual Java User Group,
which is a great source of presentations from international speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readable, Succinct, or Just Plain Short?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/short_vs_readable.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/short_vs_readable.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which is more readable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;releaseVersion = version.substring(0, version.indexOf(&#39;-SNAPSHOT&#39;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;releaseVersion = version[0..-10]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a value of &lt;code&gt;0.109-SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt;, they both give the same result.  And I&amp;rsquo;m tempted by the second,
because it&amp;rsquo;s shorter.  But I&amp;rsquo;m going to go with the first one - not because it&amp;rsquo;s more Java-ish and I&amp;rsquo;m scared of Groovy syntax,
but because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to understand if/when something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: if &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t conform to the expected pattern, the two code fragments fail in two different ways.  If &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt;
doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain &lt;code&gt;-SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt;, the first will fail with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java.lang.StringIndexOutOfBoundsException: String index out of range: -1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;whereas the second will either arbitrarily slice the last 9 characters off the end of whatever the String does contain,
or if it&amp;rsquo;s too short you&amp;rsquo;ll get something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java.lang.ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException: Negative array index [-10] too large for array size 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you, the developer, see this error (or notice your mangled version number) and look at the failing line of code,
you&amp;rsquo;ll have two different experiences.  When looking at the second example, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t write it in the first place or if you have a
memory as shocking as mine, you won&amp;rsquo;t get any clues from that code as to what the &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt; is - you&amp;rsquo;ll see what it does (chop the last
9 characters off the &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; string), but not why.  You can &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; the problem by adding an arbitrary 9 characters onto your &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking at the first example, however, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the intent right there - it&amp;rsquo;s trying to chop the string &lt;code&gt;-SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt; (and any
characters that might happen to come after it) off the end of the &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; string.  With this line of code,
if you checked the value of &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; and saw it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the correct suffix, you&amp;rsquo;d have a good idea of what the problem is and how
to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a third way, that potentially keeps the descriptiveness (is that a word?) of the first solution and makes it a bit shorter and
Groovier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;releaseVersion = version[0..&amp;lt;version.indexOf(&#39;-SNAPSHOT&#39;)]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need the less-than sign plonked in there to make it work correctly, which I find a bit jarring,
but it does work.  It&amp;rsquo;s a little more succinct than the original Java syntax and retains the intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in conclusion: yes, shorter code is generally better (and often more readable).  But I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in sacrificing code that
expresses the intent in order to reduce the number of characters used.  We&amp;rsquo;re not living in a memory-poor world any more,
and code is meant to be read by humans as well as computers.  Let&amp;rsquo;s make our code easy to understand when it goes wrong,
not simply the shortest way to do something when the stars are all perfectly aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Handover</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_handover.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_handover.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I walked into the kitchen to see how lunch was going and my boyfriend handed me a knife,
a part-chopped hard boiled egg and said &amp;ldquo;finish this, I need to have a shower&amp;rdquo;. As you do. Apparently there were two things that needed
doing - &amp;ldquo;this&amp;rdquo; needed finishing, and I needed to keep an eye on the fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;paired&amp;rdquo; with him while we&amp;rsquo;ve made that salad before, and I can tell when a fish is burning.  How hard could it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished chopping the egg and putting it into the salad, I realised I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if that was the last thing that needed to go into
the salad - when he said &amp;ldquo;finish this&amp;rdquo;, did he mean the whole salad, or just the egg chopping?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This blog post will be vaguely about technology at some point.  Probably.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After searching for other eggs that might need to be added, and sifting through the salad to see what was already in there,
I was still unclear about whether it was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrum.org/Resources/Scrum-Glossary/Definition-of-Done&#34;&gt;done&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; or not, so I
went to bother my boyfriend in the bathroom (this is not a euphemism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I told you there were only two things left to do&amp;rdquo; he said - it was so clear to him what the steps were to finish,
that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand that there might be hidden assumptions in his handover.  All he wanted was for me to finish chopping the
(only) egg.  Oh and mix it all up. Of course. When I checked if I was supposed to add the olive oil and the salt, the answer was &amp;ldquo;No,
I don&amp;rsquo;t trust you to do that&amp;rdquo; (he&amp;rsquo;s right - I&amp;rsquo;m English, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know you could put salt in a salad
and certainly have no idea about quantities of olive oil. My Spanish boyfriend is genetically wired to know this stuff).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the unclear instructions (&amp;ldquo;keep an eye on the fish&amp;rdquo;, if taken literally, could result in me watching it burn - fortunately I knew it
was secret code for &amp;ldquo;remove it from the heat when it&amp;rsquo;s done&amp;rdquo;) we had a very nice lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/HandoverSalad.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Salmon &amp;amp; Salad&#34; title=&#34;Salmon and Salad&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are parallels between this, and what I was struggling with last week (hurrah, we get to the tenuous analogy!).  I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying
to do my first release for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/morphia&#34;&gt;Morphia&lt;/a&gt;, the project I&amp;rsquo;m taking over
for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.  I know my colleague was working hard on an automated release script (one click releasing FTW),
and I know he invested a reasonable amount of time in automating the release process (this is code for &amp;ldquo;I had a bad feeling about this&amp;rdquo;).
I was going to be the first to try this out without his machine/settings/user. Yay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday night Justin gave me some tips of what was involved, finishing with &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;and then &lt;code&gt;.gradlew relase&lt;/code&gt; should just work&amp;rdquo;.  Simples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day One: I struggled with the nexus plugin and permissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Two: I woke up with one of those ideas that hit you in the night and fixed that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I spent two days trying to work out why the Git plugin wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me log in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I realised that for the whole time I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been using the local version of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evanchooly/github-release-gradle-plugin&#34;&gt;gradle release plugin&lt;/a&gt; like I thought,
but an older version. When I fixed that&amp;hellip; I spent half a day proving I still had the same issue as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I commented out the code that wasn&amp;rsquo;t working, hard coded a bunch of values and used an old script to upload the Javadoc (don&amp;rsquo;t
get me started on how long it took me to find how &lt;a href=&#34;http://maven.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Maven&lt;/a&gt; was populating the release number,
nor do I want to express the pain I felt at having to install Maven after being in love with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gradle.org/&#34;&gt;Gradle&lt;/a&gt; for the
last two years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/morphia/releases/tag/r0.108&#34;&gt;release 0.108 of Morphia&lt;/a&gt; went live on Thursday night - huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, as a responsible human being, rather than high-fiving myself, cracking open a bottle of wine and knocking off for the
weekend, next I need to prepare the handover for the next person doing the release. Not least because it&amp;rsquo;s probably going to be me,
and my memory is shocking.  I have two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a wiki page with the steps needed, manual or automated, including all the local properties that need to be set up as we can&amp;rsquo;t
have some of these passwords floating around on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the automated release so it really is one click / command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, option 2 still needs documentation because of the local properties that are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really want to do is crack open that wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the moral of the story is: handovers are hard.  And essential.  And worse, often the person doing the handing over is doing so
because they&amp;rsquo;re short on time and, for whatever reason, not responsible for the next phase of the project. Combine this lack of time with
all the assumptions and implicit knowledge in that person&amp;rsquo;s head, and the information being transferred is likely to be&amp;hellip; less than
optimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the handover receiver is now responsible for something they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough knowledge of and they&amp;rsquo;re not even aware of assumptions or
unknown unknowns. If you&amp;rsquo;re handing over between departments or teams, they might not even have the right tools to find out how to
progress (Ops teams and testers don&amp;rsquo;t always have access to the code, for example, and if they did might not have the context to find it
useful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tools to help ease the pain of handovers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/PairProgrammingMisconceptions.html&#34;&gt;Pairing&lt;/a&gt;. Pairing might seem expensive (two people at one
keyboard?? How will they type fast enough?), but the savings in handover time (and increase in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia
.org/wiki/Bus_factor&#34;&gt;Bus Factor&lt;/a&gt;) make it completely worthwhile.  Pairing with The Boy in making salad meant at least I knew what the steps and
ingredients were, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what stage we were at. At LMAX, we reduced a lot of our testing backlog by embedding the testers
in the development team, and pairing with them at the start and at the end of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/UserStory.html&#34;&gt;user stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t do pairing, code reviews help. I was at least aware of our release plugin as I&amp;rsquo;d seen the original develop in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/&#34;&gt;Java
driver&lt;/a&gt;. If I&amp;rsquo;d been pairing or code reviewing on Morphia,
I would have been even more aware of what the steps were and what changes had been made for that project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, if good old fashioned talking isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing, documentation is a good start.  And everyone who uses the docs needs to be
able to update the documentation when they find something wrong, missing, confusing, or just want to annotate it with something useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of these good practices, really what you want is to remove all possible areas of miscommunication. Computers are logical things,
 so if you can write down an exact list of steps that need to be done in order to achieve something,
you might be able to, I dunno, write that in a script, or something. If you
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321601912/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0321601912&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;linkId=M5DNVR42T66J63VO&#34;&gt;Automate All The Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0321601912&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to have these messy,
complicated conversations with these messy, complicated people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you knew that already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m off to try and fix my script. I&amp;rsquo;ve even thought of a way to not need local properties, so maybe next time (or the time after),
when I have to do a release I&amp;rsquo;ll only have to type a single command. It&amp;rsquo;ll be worth a week or two to implement this if it saves me a week
like the last one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, that wine&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;No boyfriends or colleagues were harmed in the making of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nighthacking at Sevilla Java User Group</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_jug_sevilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_jug_sevilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday &lt;a href=&#34;http://steveonjava.com/&#34;&gt;Mr Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt; came to Sevilla on his crazy European tour to show us Lego and Robots.  This was our largest turnout yet
for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Java User Group&lt;/a&gt; event in Sevilla, which surprised me as it was on a weekend,
and the weekend before the spectacle that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Week_in_Seville&#34;&gt;Semana
Santa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/I5rnDZGNJW8&#34;&gt;in Sevilla&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also the first event that we&amp;rsquo;ve had videoed (apologies for the horrible focus at times on the video,
I&amp;rsquo;m just learning and used to relying heavily on auto-focus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/q3OKs08X3oo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks very much to Stephen for visiting, and thank you to those who came, you&amp;rsquo;re making me re-think the idea of running events at
weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/photos/all_photos/?photoAlbumId=21306622&#34;&gt;photos on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events 2014</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/upcoming_events_2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I updated you on my travel plans, so now I&amp;rsquo;ve had some more conferences confirmed,
I thought I would pass the information on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been really lucky to have been selected for some great conferences this year.  I was asked to do a few more,
and it was genuinely painful to say no to everything, but it seems the laws of space and time cannot be broken,
and so I&amp;rsquo;ve been forced to select a tiny subset of all the places I&amp;rsquo;d like to go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 May: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/presentation/HTML5,%20Angular.js,%20Groovy,%20Java,
%20MongoDB%20all%20together%20-%20what%20could%20possibly%20go%20wrong?&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;m giving the same live coding presentation from QCon London,
although knowing me I expect there will be some tweaks, changes, additions, and maybe improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22-23 May: In New York City, since I&amp;rsquo;m more or less in the area.  Gimme a shout if you want to meet for a drink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25-28 May: &lt;a href=&#34;http://speakerconf.com/&#34;&gt;SpeakerConf&lt;/a&gt; Barcelona.  And while I&amp;rsquo;m in the area&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29 May: Barcelona JUG - &amp;ldquo;HTML5, Angular.js, Groovy, Java, MongoDB all together - what could possibly go wrong?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-5 June: New York City, probably (wait, am I going to be at home at all??)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23 July: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2014/public/schedule/detail/35444&#34;&gt;OSCON&lt;/a&gt; - live coding again!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;28 Sep - 2 Oct: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/speakers/index.html#gee&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt; woohoo!  I love having this opportunity to visit San
Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple of other events I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to work out the details for, but I think this is 2014 all booked up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla MUG March Madness</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_mug_march_madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_mug_march_madness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-JVIgox7nGXo/UyjIQYxtiSI/AAAAAAAANc4/JV3lj4xwcgk/w919-h689-no/IMG_20140318_193758.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/events/166679892/&#34;&gt;Last night&lt;/a&gt; the Sevilla MUG had our
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lczajkowski.com/2014/02/19/march-madness-comes-to-a-city-near-you/&#34;&gt;March Madness&lt;/a&gt; event.  This was our largest event yet,
with 36 people signed up.  Although the aim of March Madness is to have a MongoDB Engineer at all the user groups this month,
that&amp;rsquo;s not such a big deal for us as I live here, so this was also the first event where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the main attraction - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JvrBaena&#34;&gt;Javier&lt;/a&gt; gave a really great talk about the lessons learnt at &lt;a href=&#34;http://es.socialbro.com/&#34;&gt;SocialBro&lt;/a&gt; after using
MongoDB in production for the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides for my introduction to Replica Sets and Sharding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
 &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/32480708&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 And the slides for the main attraction:

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
 &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/32464459&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px; font-size:small&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare
 .net/fjavierbaena/sevilla-mongo-developers-group-mongodb-cmo-aprendimos-que-la-culpa-era-nuestra&#34; title=&#34;Sevilla Mongo Developers Group
 - MongoDB: Cómo aprendimos que la culpa era nuestra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cómo aprendimos que la culpa era nuestra&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/strong&gt;from&lt;strong&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/fjavierbaena&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Francisco Javier Baena Ríos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event went really well, everyone seemed engaged, and our first talk in Spanish seemed to encourage more questions than normal.  We
were also in a new venue, and although I love the central location of our previous venue and the friendliness of the owners,
the menu of the new location seemed to be a massive win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ESw5r9B24Hs/UyjHcM2M-DI/AAAAAAAANco/hBVhN4IMFew/w919-h689-no/IMG_20140318_220941.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2014</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. My 4th QCon London.&amp;nbsp; That’s not bad.&amp;nbsp; And every time, it’s a different experience (if you must, see my blogs for&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2013/03/qcon-day-one.html&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2012/03/qcon-london-2012.html&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;, and even 2007 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2007/03/qcon-initial-thoughts.html&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2007/03/qcon-todo-list-inspired-by-conference.html&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; - how cute was I? &amp;ldquo;agile seems like a jolly good idea; automated testing appears to be important&amp;rdquo;)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I can’t even tell you what I did on the first day, I was mostly panicking about my presentation - I was inspired after my trip to New York last month to change my talk at the last (responsible?) minute and do a live coding session, something much more technical than my recent talks.&amp;nbsp; I’ll leave the details for a separate blog post though, when the video comes out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thing that stands out for me from Wednesday though was Damian Conway programming &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway&#39;s_Game_of_Life&#34;&gt;Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life&lt;/a&gt; in Klingon.&amp;nbsp; Yeah.&amp;nbsp; Just find the video and watch it, the man is a genius.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; msallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; oallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/12947751623/player/f7e8167be5&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The Thursday keynote was inspiring too from a totally different point of view - Tim Lister of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DY5A8X2/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00DY5A8X2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&#34;&gt;Peopleware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00DY5A8X2&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt; fame shared stories from his career, and I came away from that really happy I work as a technologist, but with an increased desire to learn off other amazing people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; msallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; oallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/12966704755/player/7193594b96&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;On Thursday I hosted the&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/sets/72157641948363514/with/12970259753/&#34;&gt;Not Only Java&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;nbsp;track - I’m on the programme committee for QCon, and this year we wanted to cover&amp;nbsp;leading edge technologies (as always) but we didn’t want to slice things into strict technology silos [interruption: argh! the person in front of me nearly destroyed my laptop by suddenly moving their chair back! Why do people bother in economy on a morning flight?]. &amp;nbsp;So I wanted the Java track to be more representative of what today’s Java programmers care about - for the programmers of course, but also because I know there are architects and team leads at QCon who might not realise how things have moved on with the language, and how much polyglot programming we do these days.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com.es/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt; kicked it off with a great history lesson on the progress (or occasionally,&amp;nbsp; lack of it) in Java.&amp;nbsp; He begged us to study and understand Set Theory, to use async design, to think of the users of our APIs, and, most of all, to design nice, clean code.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Next up, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EvaAndreasson&#34;&gt;Eva&lt;/a&gt; took us through the fundamentals of Garbage Collection - this might not seem like a cutting edge subject these days, but it’s one of the most misunderstood subjects for Java programmers.&amp;nbsp; Eva gave us a really great, understandable view of the different types of garbage collectors, how they work, and their pros and cons.&amp;nbsp; She left us with a call to arms to not simply let other people try and solve this problem, but to get stuck in and contribute ourselves, via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/&#34;&gt;OpenJDK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; msallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; oallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/qconpictures/12970531704/player/e2c2f63b43&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After lunch was my nerve-wracking live coding session, putting together a full stack end-to-end web app using AngularJS, HTML5, Java and MongoDB.&amp;nbsp; It only went wrong twice, and people seemed to like it.&amp;nbsp; I’ll post the video in another blog post as soon as it&amp;rsquo;s publicly available. &amp;nbsp;Code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito&#34;&gt;available on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;We’ve been playing with the open spaces idea at QCon.&amp;nbsp; The Java one only had a few people in it, but that gave everyone a chance to speak at least.&amp;nbsp; We covered Java 8 (the Good and the Bad); other JVM languages; and UIs for Java (Javascript or GWT?).&amp;nbsp; And I plugged the work the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; does in London, of course.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;After this &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodil.org/&#34;&gt;Bodil&lt;/a&gt; blew me away creating a My Little Pony game using &lt;a href=&#34;https://rx.codeplex.com/&#34;&gt;RX&lt;/a&gt; in the browser.&amp;nbsp; ‘Nuff said.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/speakjava&#34;&gt;Simon Ritter&lt;/a&gt; gave us a view of the Java 8&amp;nbsp; features most likely to impact the way Java developers think about software design - lambdas and streams.&amp;nbsp; I thought this was a really great introduction to the concepts if you haven’t seen them before, and with concrete examples that showed how we should be using them. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re not already looking at lambdas and streams, you should be - even if you&amp;rsquo;re not going to be using Java 8 yet, it&amp;rsquo;s worth getting a heads up on how it&amp;rsquo;s going to impact our programming style.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I’m very pleased with the way the Java track turned out on the day - every speaker was first class, a wide range of topics was covered, and I, for one, learnt something in every presentation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;To finish off the day, Emma Langman gave an awesome keynote about how people are the messy bit of your system, and how they’re never rational and you shouldn’t expect them to be.&amp;nbsp; I also highly recommend this talk, especially if you’re a techy and you’ve found yourself in some sort of management or team lead position.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Sadly I couldn’t stay for day three of the conference, I had to fly off to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2014/03/the-joy-of-coding.html&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding&lt;/a&gt; to re-give the live coding presentation there.&amp;nbsp; Because, if you’re going to do something terrifying and doomed to failure, you might as well do it twice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;QCon is an expensive conference, especially compared to the developer-friendly prices of something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.co.uk/&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;, but for getting a big picture of where the industry is, of things you might be missing, for learning hard core technical skills and understanding the important of the fluffy-people-stuff, and finally for meeting a wide range of people from developers to CTOs, I think you&amp;rsquo;d be hard pushed to find something better in London. &amp;nbsp;IMHO (and remember, I did disclose I&amp;rsquo;m on the programme committee). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And although it&amp;rsquo;s really hard work putting together the programme for a track like this, and although both times I&amp;rsquo;ve said I&amp;rsquo;m Never Doing It Again, when it goes this well it makes you want to do it all over again. &amp;nbsp;After a break. &amp;nbsp;A looong break.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
