<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Mongodb on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/mongodb/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB London</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mongodb_london/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mongodb_london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt;, 6th November, 50% off with discount code &lt;strong&gt;50Trisha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt; is nearly upon us again,
and I&amp;rsquo;m dead disappointed I can&amp;rsquo;t make it this year (I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/berlin-2014/presentation/Party%20Keynote:%20Staying%20Ahead%20of%20the%20Curve&#34;&gt;keynoting at GOTO Berlin&lt;/a&gt; instead,
which I&amp;rsquo;m terrified, I mean, excited, about). The last MongoDB London was really interesting for me - I was fairly new to the company,
I&amp;rsquo;d been here less than six months, and it was a really great way to go both broad and deep on the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was trying to find a blog post where I talked about my experiences, but it looks like I only wrote that In My Mind. In fact,
I only only wrote two whole lines of notes on the conference.  But 18 months later I clearly remember presentations from my colleagues
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Ross&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://derickrethans.nl/&#34;&gt;Derick&lt;/a&gt; demonstrating the geo capabilities in MongoDB,
presentations which heavily influenced the &lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/&#34;&gt;live coding demo&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving
recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also remember Eliot&amp;rsquo;s presentation - Eliot is one of those people who totally gets away with breaking the &amp;ldquo;speak in a measured,
clear fashion&amp;rdquo; presenters rule, he fires fascinating information at you at high speed and it&amp;rsquo;s actually one of the compelling things
about his talks. If you ever get a chance to see him talk about the product, it&amp;rsquo;s totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, the most awesome thing about the conference was the chance to meet, and talk to,
a bunch of different MongoDB people - there are the engineers who work on the product (like me and my colleagues);
the people leading the way with the technology, like Eliot; and finally, but for me most importantly,
you get to meet really interesting people who are using MongoDB in ways that you might not even imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway the point of this sales pitch is, whether you&amp;rsquo;re using MongoDB already or you&amp;rsquo;re keen to find out about it,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.com/events/mongodb-london-2014&#34;&gt;MongoDB London&lt;/a&gt; is only going to take a day from your life,
and you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a bunch of interesting things. And, with a Special Discount Code from me,
it&amp;rsquo;s only £45! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mongodb-london-2014-registration-13140209721&#34;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt; with code &lt;strong&gt;50Trisha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS, HTML5, Groovy, Java and MongoDB All Together - What Could Possibly Go Wrong??</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving an evolving live demonstration of coding a Fully Buzz Word Compliant,
mobile-friendly web application.  The aim of the demo is to show, via a real-world application rather than snippets or a toy example,
where these popular technologies sit in your archtecture, and how they interact with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact code I present has changed a bit over time, but the vJUG has a pretty recent version of the demo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/MRrSAkEAnZQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;ll see there are a number of different branches for the
different versions I&amp;rsquo;ve presented. The current one is the JavaOne version.  With all the branches,
the commits correspond to the user stories in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/i-want-coffeejavaone&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;,
so you can get a feel for how the code builds up throughout the demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the demo I don&amp;rsquo;t get much of a chance to go through the Groovy script I use to import data into MongoDB,
so I have a &lt;a href=&#34;/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/&#34;&gt;whole blog post just on that subject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk has been videod several times, some of these videos aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet, but there are videos of older versions of this talk -
these older versions use a different library to talk to MongoDB and (I hope) you&amp;rsquo;ll see that the most recent code is even simpler than
these initial demos.  If more videos become available I&amp;rsquo;ll add them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago, May 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/demo-java-javascript-mongodb&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding, March 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a full list of this and all my presentations, see &lt;a href=&#34;presentation/public_appearances/&#34;&gt;Public Appearances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Groovy to import XML into MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/groovy_import_to_mongodb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been demonstrating how easy it is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRrSAkEAnZQ&#34;&gt;create modern web apps using AngularJS,
Java and MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.  I also use Groovy during this demo to do the sorts of things Groovy is
really good at - writing descriptive tests, and creating scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the time pressures in the demo, I never really get a chance to go into the details of the script I use,
so the aim of this long-overdue blog post is to go over this Groovy script in a bit more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly I want to clarify that this is not my original work - I &lt;strike&gt;stole&lt;/strike&gt; borrowed most of the ideas for the demo from my
colleague Ross Lawley. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/posts/the-most-popular-pub-name/&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; he goes into detail of how he built
up an application that
finds the most popular pub names in the UK.  There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosslawley.co.uk/posts/the-most-popular-pub-name/#toc_1&#34;&gt;section in there&lt;/a&gt;
where he talks about downloading the open street map data and using python to convert the XML into something more MongoDB-friendly - it&amp;rsquo;s
this process that I basically stole, re-worked for coffee shops, and re-wrote for the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m assuming if you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Java for any period of time, there has come a moment where you needed to use it to parse XML. Since my
demo is supposed to be all about how easy it is to work with Java, I did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; want to do this. When I wrote the demo I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really all
that familiar with Groovy, but what I did know was that it has built in support for parsing and manipulating XML,
which is exactly what I wanted to do. In addition, creating &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/Collections#Collections-Mapsmaps&#34;&gt;Maps&lt;/a&gt; (the
data structures, not the geographical ones) with Groovy is really easy, and this is effectively what we need to insert into
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Goal of the Script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parse an XML file containing open street map data of all coffee shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract latitude and longitude XML attributes and transform into
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-geojson&#34;&gt;MongoDB GeoJSON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform some basic validation on the coffee shop data from the XML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert into MongoDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure MongoDB knows this contains query-able geolocation data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/blob/java-one/src/main/scripts/PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34;&gt;PopulateDatabase.groovy&lt;/a&gt;,
that link will take you to the version I presented at JavaOne:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript.png&#34; alt=&#34;PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34; title=&#34;PopulateDatabase.groovy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Firstly, we need data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the same service Ross used in his blog post to obtain the XML file containing &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rdquo; coffee shops around the world. Now,
the open street map data is somewhat&amp;hellip; raw and unstructured (which is why MongoDB is such a great tool for storing it),
so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I really have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the coffee shops, but I obtained enough data for an interesting demo using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.overpass-api.de/api/xapi?*[amenity=cafe][cuisine=coffee_shop]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/blob/master/src/main/scripts/resources/all-coffee-shops.xml&#34;&gt;resulting XML file&lt;/a&gt; is in the
github project, but if you try this yourself you might (in fact, probably will) get different results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each XML record looks something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;node id=&amp;quot;178821166&amp;quot; lat=&amp;quot;40.4167226&amp;quot; lon=&amp;quot;-3.7069112&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;amenity&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;cafe&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;cuisine&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;coffee_shop&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;name&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;Chocolatería San Ginés&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;wheelchair&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;limited&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tag k=&amp;quot;wikipedia&amp;quot; v=&amp;quot;es:Chocolatería San Ginés&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/node&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each coffee shop has a unique identifier and a latitude and longitude as attributes of a &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt; element.  Within this node is a series
of &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; elements, all with &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; attributes. Each coffee shop has a varying number of these attributes,
and they are not consistent from shop to shop (other than &lt;code&gt;amenity&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;cuisine&lt;/code&gt; which we used to select this data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Initialisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Script Initialisation&#34; title=&#34;Script Initialisation&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything else we want to prepare the database.  The assumption of this script is that either the
collection we want to store the coffee shops in is empty, or full of stale data.  So we&amp;rsquo;re going to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/ecosystem/drivers/java/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt; to get the collection that we&amp;rsquo;re interested in, and then drop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s two interesting things to note here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Groovy script is simply using the basic Java driver.  Groovy can talk quite happily to vanilla Java,
it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to use a Groovy library.  There are Groovy-specific libraries for talking to MongoDB (e.g. the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://grails.org/plugin/mongodb&#34;&gt;MongoDB GORM Plugin&lt;/a&gt;), but the Java driver works perfectly well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-database&#34;&gt;databases&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/glossary/#term-collection&#34;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt; (collections are
a bit like tables, but less structured) explicitly in MongoDB.  You simply use the database and collection you&amp;rsquo;re interested in,
and if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist, the server will create them for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we&amp;rsquo;re just using the default constructor for the &lt;code&gt;MongoClient&lt;/code&gt;, the class that represents the connection to the database
server(s).  This default is localhost:27017, which is where I happen to be running the database.  However you can specify your own
address and port - for more details on this see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94065240033/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-i&#34;&gt;Getting Started With MongoDB and Java&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Turn the XML into something MongoDB-shaped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Parse &amp;amp; Transform XML&#34; title=&#34;Parse &amp;amp; Transform XML&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next we&amp;rsquo;re going to use Groovy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/api/groovy/util/XmlSlurper.html&#34;&gt;XmlSlurper&lt;/a&gt; to read the open street map
XML data that we talked about earlier.  To iterate over every node we use: &lt;code&gt;xmlSlurper.node.each&lt;/code&gt;.  For those of you who are new to
Groovy or new to Java 8, you might notice this is using a closure to define the behaviour to apply for every &amp;ldquo;node&amp;rdquo; element in the XML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Create GeoJSON&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Create GeoJSON&#34; title=&#34;Create GeoJSON&#34; /&gt;

Since MongoDB documents are effectively just maps of key-value pairs, we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a Map &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt; that contains the
document structure that represents the coffee shop that we want to save into the database.  Firstly,
we initialise this map with the attributes of the &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt;. Remember these attributes are something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;node id=&amp;quot;18464077&amp;quot; lat=&amp;quot;-33.8911183&amp;quot; lon=&amp;quot;151.1958773&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to save the ID as a value for a new field called &lt;code&gt;openStreetMapId&lt;/code&gt;. We need to do something a bit more
complicated with the latitude and longitude, since we need to store them as GeoJSON, which looks something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ &#39;location&#39; : { &#39;coordinates&#39;: [&amp;lt;longitude&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;latitude&amp;gt;],
                 &#39;type&#39;       : &#39;Point&#39; } }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lines 12-14 you can see that we create a &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt; that looks like the GeoJSON, pulling the &lt;code&gt;lat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;lon&lt;/code&gt; attributes into the appropriate
places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Insert Remaining Fields&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Insert Remaining Fields&#34; title=&#34;Insert Remaining Fields&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Validate Field Name&#34; title=&#34;Validate Field Name&#34; /&gt;

Now for every &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; element in the XML, we get the &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; attribute and check if it&amp;rsquo;s a valid field name for MongoDB (it won&amp;rsquo;t let us
insert fields with a dot in, and we don&amp;rsquo;t want to override our carefully constructed &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; field). If so we simply add this key as the
field and its the matching &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; attribute as the value into the map. This effectively copies the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; key/value data into key/value pairs in the MongoDB document so we don&amp;rsquo;t lose any data,
but we also don&amp;rsquo;t do anything particularly interesting to transform it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Save Into MongoDB&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Save Into MongoDB&#34; title=&#34;Save Into MongoDB&#34; /&gt;

Finally, once we&amp;rsquo;ve created a simple &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt; Map representing the document we want to save into MongoDB,
we insert it into MongoDB if the map has a field called &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;.  We could have checked this when we were reading the XML and putting it
into the map, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually much easier just to use the pretty Groovy syntax to check for a key called &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;coffeeShop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we want to insert the Map we need to turn this into a &lt;code&gt;BasicDBObject&lt;/code&gt;, the Java Driver&amp;rsquo;s document type,
but this is easily done by calling the constructor that takes a Map.  Alternatively, there&amp;rsquo;s a Groovy syntax which would effectively do
the same thing, which you might prefer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;collection.insert(coffeeShop as BasicDBObject)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Tell MongoDB that we want to perform Geo queries on this data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/GroovyScript7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add Geo Index&#34; title=&#34;Add Geo Index&#34; /&gt;

Because we&amp;rsquo;re going to do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/reference/operator/query/nearSphere/&#34;&gt;nearSphere&lt;/a&gt; query on this data,
we need to add a &amp;ldquo;2dsphere&amp;rdquo; index on our location field. We created the &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; field as GeoJSON,
so all we need to do is call &lt;code&gt;createIndex&lt;/code&gt; for this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it!  Groovy is a nice tool for this sort of script-y thing - not only is it a scripting language,
but its built-in support for XML, really nice Map syntax and support for closures makes it the perfect tool for iterating over XML data
and transforming it into something that can be inserted into a MongoDB collection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with MongoDB and Java</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_started_with_mongodb_and_java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_started_with_mongodb_and_java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been missing an introduction to using MongoDB from Java for a little while now - there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of information in &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mongodb.org/ecosystem/drivers/java/&#34;&gt;the
documentation&lt;/a&gt;, but we were lacking a step-by-step guide to getting started as a Java
developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sought to rectify this with a couple of blog posts for the MongoDB official blog: the first, an introduction to using MongoDB from
Java, including a non-comprehensive list of some of the libraries you can use; the second, an introductory guide to simple CRUD
operations using the Java driver:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94065240033/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-i&#34;&gt;Getting Started with MongoDB and Java, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/94724924068/getting-started-with-mongodb-and-java-part-ii&#34;&gt;Getting Started with MongoDB and Java, Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very much aimed at Java/JVM developers who are new to MongoDB, and want to get a feel for how you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guides are for the current (2.x) driver. When we release 3.x, we&amp;rsquo;ll release updated guides as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, Backwards Compatibility? (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOW recorded me, yet again, talking about the adventure that is the design of the new Java Driver for MongoDB.  This is the same talk I
gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;,
with some updates based on our Journey So Far.  In it, I cover the architecture of the new driver and some of our current thoughts
around where we want the API to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yow.eventer.com/yow-2013-1080/what-do-you-mean-backwards-compatibility-by-trisha-gee-1398&#34;&gt;See the video here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Charles Humble for InfoQ</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/infoq-interview-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/infoq-interview-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/qcon_london_2014/&#34;&gt;QCon London&lt;/a&gt;, I was grabbed for an interview with InfoQ.  It&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasure to be interviewed by Charles,
I think he brings out the best in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the video &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/interviews/trisha-gee-mongdo-java8#.U00BRMNMIC4.blogger&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the interview we refer to the first time we met, which, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested, &lt;a href=&#34;/post/interviewed_for_infoq_at_qcon_london/&#34;&gt;you can also watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla MUG March Madness</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_mug_march_madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/svq_mug_march_madness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-JVIgox7nGXo/UyjIQYxtiSI/AAAAAAAANc4/JV3lj4xwcgk/w919-h689-no/IMG_20140318_193758.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/events/166679892/&#34;&gt;Last night&lt;/a&gt; the Sevilla MUG had our
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lczajkowski.com/2014/02/19/march-madness-comes-to-a-city-near-you/&#34;&gt;March Madness&lt;/a&gt; event.  This was our largest event yet,
with 36 people signed up.  Although the aim of March Madness is to have a MongoDB Engineer at all the user groups this month,
that&amp;rsquo;s not such a big deal for us as I live here, so this was also the first event where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the main attraction - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JvrBaena&#34;&gt;Javier&lt;/a&gt; gave a really great talk about the lessons learnt at &lt;a href=&#34;http://es.socialbro.com/&#34;&gt;SocialBro&lt;/a&gt; after using
MongoDB in production for the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides for my introduction to Replica Sets and Sharding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
 &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/32480708&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 And the slides for the main attraction:

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
 &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/32464459&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px; font-size:small&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare
 .net/fjavierbaena/sevilla-mongo-developers-group-mongodb-cmo-aprendimos-que-la-culpa-era-nuestra&#34; title=&#34;Sevilla Mongo Developers Group
 - MongoDB: Cómo aprendimos que la culpa era nuestra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cómo aprendimos que la culpa era nuestra&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/strong&gt;from&lt;strong&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/fjavierbaena&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Francisco Javier Baena Ríos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event went really well, everyone seemed engaged, and our first talk in Spanish seemed to encourage more questions than normal.  We
were also in a new venue, and although I love the central location of our previous venue and the friendliness of the owners,
the menu of the new location seemed to be a massive win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ESw5r9B24Hs/UyjHcM2M-DI/AAAAAAAANco/hBVhN4IMFew/w919-h689-no/IMG_20140318_220941.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevilla MUG, first event</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/sevilla_mug_first_event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/sevilla_mug_first_event/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ACbZtH8y3pM/Uurim-7CuNI/AAAAAAAAMfU/iR7aAjV3L_E/s1600/IMG_20140130_191433.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ACbZtH8y3pM/Uurim-7CuNI/AAAAAAAAMfU/iR7aAjV3L_E/s1600/IMG_20140130_191433.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last night was the inaugural meeting of the Sevilla MongoDN User Group. &amp;nbsp;An event organised with just over 48 hours notice, in a city where I don&amp;rsquo;t speak the language and where even my best-connected contacts aren&amp;rsquo;t sure they&amp;rsquo;re fully plugged in to the tech scene.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, I had some reservations:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a lightning talk? Will people come all that way for beer and 15 minutes of presentation?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;in English? Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m desperately learning Spanish to get closer to presenting in Spanish, at this point I&amp;rsquo;m just not ready and have to hope people want to listen to me ramble in a foreign language&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a MUG? Are people interested in joining a group that&amp;rsquo;s solely focussed on one technology, a technology that might not have adoption here or even interest?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;two days notice? &amp;nbsp;Are you kidding? &amp;nbsp;I know people here like to figure out their plans at the last minute, but surely this is shooting ourselves in the foot before we even start.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ZxzdtnwGKrk/UurinNqIjZI/AAAAAAAAMfQ/HHbZGT9MCV0/s1600/IMG_20140130_192137.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ZxzdtnwGKrk/UurinNqIjZI/AAAAAAAAMfQ/HHbZGT9MCV0/s1600/IMG_20140130_192137.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And then last night&amp;hellip; &amp;nbsp;The people&amp;hellip; they came. &amp;nbsp;On time. &amp;nbsp;And with their interesting stories and their varied backgrounds. &amp;nbsp;They listened, they asked questions, they wanted more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nU0wPfzI6DE/UuritPmwnDI/AAAAAAAAMfk/R49MwaxAzCk/s1600/IMG_20140130_201313.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nU0wPfzI6DE/UuritPmwnDI/AAAAAAAAMfk/R49MwaxAzCk/s1600/IMG_20140130_201313.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What a great event. &amp;nbsp;What an awesome city. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait for next month. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--soNKu8wqYU/UurimtUlxPI/AAAAAAAAMfM/wh3q9UV1FLQ/s1600/IMG_20140130_192632.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--soNKu8wqYU/UurimtUlxPI/AAAAAAAAMfM/wh3q9UV1FLQ/s1600/IMG_20140130_192632.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;(Slides here, with usual caveats of them being pretty pointless on their own)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/30654613&#34; width=&#34;376&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to MongoDB and Big Data</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/introduction_to_mongodb_and_big_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/introduction_to_mongodb_and_big_data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote an article for the latest edition of Java Magazine which is an introduction to MongoDB for Java developers, and a nod to why it&amp;rsquo;s good in the &amp;ldquo;Big Data&amp;rdquo; space.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;background-color: #d2d2d2; height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; alt=&#34;www.oracle.com/javamagazine&#34; class=&#34;navlogo&#34; src=&#34;http://images-cdn.dashdigital.com/javamagazine/include/icons/navbar_logo.gif?lm=1390425195000&#34; height=&#34;28&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;color: #666666; font-family: tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 11px; font-weight: bold; line-height: 15px; padding-right: 5px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;top_right_text&#34;&gt;Look inside &amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;background-color: white;&#34;&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;padding: 10px 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oraclejavamagazine-digital.com/javamagazine/jan_feb_2014?pg=52&#34; onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://www.oraclejavamagazine-digital.com/javamagazine/jan_feb_2014?pg=52&#39;,&#39;sharewidget&#39;,&#39;toolbar=no,menubar=no,resizable=yes,scrollbars=yes,left=0,top=0,width=&#39;+(screen.width-10)+&#39;,height=&#39;+(screen.height-10)+&#39;&#39;);return false;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;View Magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;51&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://images-cdn.dashdigital.com/javamagazine/jan_feb_2014/data/imgpages/smtn/0052_vyvpwu.gif?lm=1390425195000&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;background-color: #d2d2d2; height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;color: #666666; font-family: tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 11px; font-weight: bold; line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;bottom_text&#34;&gt;MongoDB and Big Data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAX London &amp; MongoDB Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__mongodb_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__mongodb_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous years, JAX London would have been an easy, local conference to go to. This time it took me most of Sunday to get
there, and not because of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://metro.co.uk/2013/10/27/its-ok-to-take-the-morning-off-work-if-storm-hits-michael-fish-says-so-4162862/&#34;&gt;Super Storm&lt;/a&gt;.  Still, that gave me the day to finish off the tutorial I was running there on
Monday morning. Not that I would be so unprofessional as to leave preparing things until the last minute,
oh no&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as in previous years, the main benefit of this conference for me was meeting most of the usual suspects from the London Java
Community. For example, presenting were: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/andy-piper&#34;&gt;Andy Piper&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/barry-cranford&#34;&gt;Barry Cranford&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/james-gough&#34;&gt;Jim
Gough&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/peter-lawrey&#34;&gt;Peter Lawrey&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon
.com/speakers/sandro-mancuso&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/simon-maple&#34;&gt;Simon Maple&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/martijn-verburg&#34;&gt;Martijn Verburg&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/john-oliver&#34;&gt;John
Oliver&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/john-stevenson&#34;&gt;John Stevenson&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon
.com/speakers/richard-warburton&#34;&gt;Richard Warburton&lt;/a&gt;. The Community Night in particular also drew a lot of LJC members (including some
 first-timers) to JAX, and it was a really good &amp;ldquo;networking opportunity&amp;rdquo; (i.e. chance to have free drinks,
 catch up with friends and make new ones). I really enjoyed hanging out with everyone at JAX this year,
 I was tempted to write the names of everyone I spoke to and had fun with because it really made my conference,
 but I think that would make a very boring blog post. But if I spoke to you at JAX, you made my journey from Spain worthwhile,
 thank you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As well as the LJC-types, there were some other really big name speakers too,
 including MongoDB&amp;rsquo;s Chairman &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/dwight-merriman&#34;&gt;Dwight Merriman&lt;/a&gt;. Highlights for me
 were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Sipe&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spockframework.org/&#34;&gt;Spock&lt;/a&gt; talk. I saw this at GeeCON and that&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;/tags/spock/&#34;&gt;I started using
Spock&lt;/a&gt; to test the MongoDB Java driver, but it was great to see it again and pick up some extra tips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ted Neward&amp;rsquo;s talk at the community night about being a CTO at a startup. It was really interesting,
and nice to see a realistic view of the difficulties of that role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Governor&amp;rsquo;s keynote on how Java got its Mojo back. I like seeing facts and figures to back up a viewpoint,
and as you&amp;rsquo;d expect from the founder of an analyst firm, this talk was full of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As James mentioned during his talk, the audience at JAX was, as in previous years, somewhat passive. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why,
 as around 50% of the audience came from outside the UK so we can&amp;rsquo;t even blame English reticence. And in a conference full of
 outspoken LJC-types, it seems an odd thing to have an unresponsive audience. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the venue,
 the main hall in particular seems to lend itself to sitting quietly in the audience and expecting to be entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented four times at JAX, because, well, on home turf one ends up doing more than one expects.
 - Firstly, a tutorial on the new Java driver for MongoDB (more on this later);
 - Secondly, a clinic for novice speakers. This was a lot of fun, and I think it was useful for everyone. I&amp;rsquo;d love to run
 this again (I probably will at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ljcopenconference/&#34;&gt;LJC Open Conference&lt;/a&gt;). The aim
 is to give new speakers confidence, not focus on details like building a slide deck.
 - Thirdly, the third time out for my &amp;ldquo;Design is a Process, not a Document&amp;rdquo; presentation. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively interactive
 presentation, which I don&amp;rsquo;t think worked so well at JAX, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fun presentation to give.
 - Finally, not only did I get roped into being on the panel for &amp;ldquo;How to start a community&amp;rdquo; at the community night, I ended up, somehow,
  moderating it. That was fun, it was the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been a moderator, it&amp;rsquo;s a role I usually avoid as moderators ought to
  limit the amount of talking they do, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound fun to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorial materials are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/mongodb-java-tutorial&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
provided a lot of guidance on how to get started online, but the exercises are there, and the slides which present the concepts and
suggest the order to tackle the tests in. If people use these materials, please feel free to give me feedback on them,
but be nice - they were designed for an in-person tutorial, not an online one. But it is a good way to get a feel for the new
MongoDB Java API (in its current, unfinished, state).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, JAX London - great speakers, and a good conference to meet not only Londoners, but a lot of international people too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New 3.0 Java Driver for MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/resources/the_new_30_java_driver_for_mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/resources/the_new_30_java_driver_for_mongodb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Information related to the currently-ongoing effort to redesign the Java driver for MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Links to more detailed information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/58136652766/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0&#34;&gt;Introduction to the changes in 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/59769560940/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0-whats-changing&#34;&gt;How to get started with the 3.0
not-production-ready snapshot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation from GeeCON about the design of the new MongoDB driver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;
src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/26024765&#34; width=&#34;476&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also available in Chinese:
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/24790295&#34; style=&#34;border-width: 1px 1px 0; border: 1px solid #CCC; margin-bottom: 5px;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;427&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with the new MongoDB Java Driver</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/how_to_get_started_with_the_new_mongodb_java_driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/how_to_get_started_with_the_new_mongodb_java_driver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/59769560940/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0-whats-changing&#34;&gt;second in my short series of blogs&lt;/a&gt; about the new Java driver is now available for your perusal. &amp;nbsp;In it, there&amp;rsquo;s some guidance on how to get started using the new driver, whether you want to use the new (unfinished) API, the existing &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; API, or a blend of both.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The post also shows that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gradle.org/&#34;&gt;Gradle&lt;/a&gt; is prettier than &lt;a href=&#34;http://maven.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Maven&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Sorry Maven.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you are going to play with the new driver, please read all the caveats carefully. &amp;nbsp;I know it looks a bit like the warnings on your prescription medicine, but it serves the same purpose. &amp;nbsp;Short version: the driver is not finished yet, and should not be used in production.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We really want to hear your experiences with the driver - it is an open source project and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; is very much driven by the community, we want to hear from you. &amp;nbsp;But only if you say nice things. &amp;nbsp;No, seriously, please tell us if you have problems, if functionality is missing, if your tests fail if you start to use it, etc etc etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Go play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Stephen Chin about JavaOne 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveonjava&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt;, one of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Java Evangelists and the JavaOne content chair, interviewed me via a live stream about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/58136652766/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0&#34;&gt;new MongoDB Java driver&lt;/a&gt;, and my plans to Change The World.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was a fun interview to do, and I really like the format of being interviewed over Skype and streaming my desktop. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s a slight (OK, 25 seconds, not really low latency) lag between the screen and the speaking which means it&amp;rsquo;s not a great platform for doing live demos, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d like to do more code demos in this way, if I can find a suitable platform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/MdOHjGtITjo?list=PLX8CzqL3ArzXMvt5y8VHXKmr8gDC-xOH_&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3.0 Java Driver - Design Goals</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_30_java_driver__design_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_30_java_driver__design_goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel slightly like a traitor to my own blog, as I&amp;rsquo;ve written a blog post for Somewhere Else. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve written about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/58136652766/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0&#34;&gt;design goals for the 3.0 MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt; in the official MongoDB blog (seems sensible, right?). &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how I feel about cross-posting the entire contents, so I&amp;rsquo;m just linking you to them instead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been to my Backwards Compatibility presentation this year might notice something familiar about the content. &amp;nbsp;The talk covers the design goals of the new driver, and this blog post will let you read them in your own time rather than having me fire them at you at 100mph.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are you using MongoDB with Java?</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/how_are_you_using_mongodb_with_java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/how_are_you_using_mongodb_with_java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, like one of my presentations, I have a question for you. &amp;nbsp;Actually, I have more than one question for you. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to bother with survey monkey or whatever, I want to share the answers so please, answers in the comments:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are you using the Java driver for MongoDB in your application?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are you using the Java driver directly, or are you using a third party library like Morphia, Spring Data, the Scala driver, your own abstraction layer, etc?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using a third party library, why did you choose that over using the Java driver directly?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using the Java driver directly, what do you like about it?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using the Java driver directly, are there any areas that give you pain? &amp;nbsp;Areas for improvement?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Which version of Java are you using?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt;Feel free to leave additional information if you have it. &amp;nbsp;And this is a public blog, so if you&amp;rsquo;re really mean I&amp;rsquo;ll just delete your comment. &amp;nbsp;So there.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
