<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Thoughtworks on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/thoughtworks/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting around a bit</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_around_a_bit</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_around_a_bit</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m honoured to now be listed on three aggregated blog feeds:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The new and somewhat embryonic &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.lmax.com/&#34;&gt;blogs.lmax.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://ljc.aggrity.com/&#34;&gt;London Java Community Aggrity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtworks.com/blogs/alumni&#34;&gt;ThoughtWorks Alumni&lt;/a&gt;, along with a whole host of distinguished names.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;The pressure&amp;rsquo;s on to try and write useful stuff. &amp;nbsp;Oh OK, I&amp;rsquo;ll settle for &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Changing The Image Of Programmers</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/on_changing_the_image_of_programmers</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/on_changing_the_image_of_programmers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gah!!  &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/20/manfest-destiny-2/&#34;&gt;This is &lt;i&gt;exactly&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  what I was &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/01/on-how-not-to-target-girl-geeks.html&#34;&gt;talking about&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- it&amp;rsquo;s pink, it mentions shoes, and it&amp;rsquo;s about as patronising as you can get.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Would&amp;nbsp;the chart&amp;nbsp;be different if your possible outcomes were&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/exec/billg/&#34;&gt;Bill Gates&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/pr/bios/jobs.html&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/markzuckerberg&#34;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linux.org/info/linus.html&#34;&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/a&gt;? &amp;nbsp;I bet for a start it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mention Jimmy Choos or choice of handbags. &amp;nbsp;And it probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in baby blue either.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Which leads me nicely onto the next subject I have strong opinions on: Role models. &amp;nbsp;Why do we need them?&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Do&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;we need them?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;If there is &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; good to be salvaged from that horrific infographic, it&amp;rsquo;s that it gave me what I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to research - some female role models in technology.&amp;nbsp;Unfortunately&amp;nbsp;it hit the other button I was ranting about earlier - they&amp;rsquo;re all very presentable and polished. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt their value as role models, it&amp;rsquo;s great to have people like that to try and emulate. &amp;nbsp;But&amp;nbsp;surely there must be IT women out there who look like real people? &amp;nbsp;And how many of them started as programmers? &amp;nbsp;I know there&amp;rsquo;s a wider issue around women in technical professions, and women at the top of organisations in any business domain, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep focused on the issues faced by girl programmers specifically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do we need role models?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel almost a responsibility to be a role model. &amp;nbsp;I joined &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtworks.com/&#34;&gt;ThoughtWorks&lt;/a&gt; because I felt it would give me a better platform for greater visibility, so I could show that girls could do this job. &amp;nbsp;I feel passionately that the industry desperately needs excellent role models to overcome the stereotypes kids are absorbing (in our western society) about what it means to be a programmer(/developer/techy).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/mnowster&#34;&gt;Mazz&lt;/a&gt; feels&amp;nbsp;quite differently. &amp;nbsp;She doesn&amp;rsquo;t see why she should have a greater responsibility to be a role model simply because of her gender. &amp;nbsp;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be expected of her co-workers. &amp;nbsp;She suggests that by making a career in programming an option for all, or worse, by&amp;nbsp;targeting&amp;nbsp;specific groups (e.g. women) we&amp;rsquo;re devaluing the industry. &amp;nbsp;Surely we&amp;rsquo;re stronger if we only attract people who are interested in the first place? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During a week long trip to Vegas (it&amp;rsquo;s a hard life), Mazz and I realised we actually agreed on fundamentals:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mazz doesn&amp;rsquo;t believe we need female role models to tempt women into programming&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I believe we need more diverse role models than we currently have.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If Mazz doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to be a role model because she&amp;rsquo;s perfectly happy getting on with doing her job bloody brilliantly, then that&amp;rsquo;s totally cool - after all, if minorities are expected to do stuff which distracts them from their day job, it&amp;rsquo;s going to make them less appealing to employers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My aim in being a role model was not specifically to get more girls into programming, but to show to the world that we&amp;rsquo;re not all speccy asexual white boys. &amp;nbsp;Some of us are speccy white girls. &amp;nbsp;And this shows the ridiculousness of trying to encourage girls to be role models - you&amp;rsquo;ve only changed one dimension. And having a token bisexual black disabled older lady is only going to narrow the field you&amp;rsquo;re appealing to.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;So what do we need to change?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Back to the question that started this off - &amp;ldquo;what do we need to do to encourage the girls?&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;The answer, it would seem, is not to roll out the girls, dress them up and parade them around. &amp;nbsp;After all, we got here with no female role models. &amp;nbsp;And we may very well have been put off by role models like us - a teenage Mazz and a teenage Trish would probably not identify with the heel-wearing blonde I&amp;rsquo;ve become, despite my all-round awesomeness.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;When I worked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ford.co.uk/AboutFord/CompanyInformation/FordinBritain&#34;&gt;Ford &lt;/a&gt;they used to tell us a story about marketing. &amp;nbsp;They told us that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.harley-davidson.com/&#34;&gt;Harley Davidson&lt;/a&gt; understood that to market something, you had to market it at the person your customers &lt;i&gt;wanted&lt;/i&gt; to be. &amp;nbsp;A Harley is a statement, a lifestyle choice. &amp;nbsp;They focused on promoting that lifestyle, promoting the image of the Harley biker, all leather and macho attitude. &amp;nbsp;They knew that the majority of their customers were CEOs, lawyers, doctors. &amp;nbsp;Guys who&amp;rsquo;d made it in life and had the cash to spend. But if they&amp;rsquo;d marketed Harley Davidson directly to the stereotypes of these guys they would have lost their market. &amp;nbsp;These men did not buy a Harley as part of their CEO persona. &amp;nbsp;They bought them because they aspired to be the leather-wearing macho guy.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how true that story is, but I do know Harley Davidson revitalised their failing business by focusing on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webpronews.com/topnews/2005/07/28/case-study-harley-davidson&#34;&gt;creating a community around their brand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So back to the question: How do we get more girls into programming?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And the answer is: We&amp;rsquo;re asking the wrong question. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The real question is: How do we attract more than just the &amp;ldquo;typical&amp;rdquo; geeks into programming? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And when you ask that question, you realise it&amp;rsquo;s absurd to assume that attractive female role models and women-centered events are going to fix the problem, or even make any significant headway on it. &amp;nbsp;You&amp;rsquo;re narrowing your field of appeal instead of broadening it. &amp;nbsp;You&amp;rsquo;re being exclusive instead of inclusive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Where can we find appropriate role models to represent us?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;We have diversity amongst geeks. &amp;nbsp;We&amp;rsquo;ve got diversity along the typical dimensions (age/race/sexuality/gender etc etc). &amp;nbsp;But in addition we&amp;rsquo;re all individuals and we&amp;rsquo;re going to appeal to other individuals. &amp;nbsp;I might appeal to someone who likes shoes. &amp;nbsp;I might appeal to someone who likes photography. &amp;nbsp;I might appeal to someone who thinks Java developers should give a toss about the user experience. &amp;nbsp;I might appeal to someone who is massively OCD about the names of their variables.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care what little boxes those people tick on the dimensions that make absolutely no difference to their ability to program. &amp;nbsp;In fact, if we focus less on this and more on our general awesomeness as geeks, we might find so-called minorities are happier to represent us.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;Even with diverse role models we might have trouble getting the media to let go of their stereotype of the geek programming in their bedroom. &amp;nbsp;But we might not - I did a search for &amp;ldquo;geek&amp;rdquo; on The Sun&amp;rsquo;s website, and I found a&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;more references to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikihow.com/Wear-Geek-Chic-Style-(for-Girls)&#34;&gt;geek chic&lt;/a&gt;, and celebrities claiming to be geeks, than to stories of the lonely computer programmer who went crazy and killed everyone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is the time of the geek. &amp;nbsp;Let&amp;rsquo;s ride the wave and bring other people to the party.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;So who should our role models be?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Everyone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All of us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
