<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Video on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/video/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>First presentation at the Virtual JUG!</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had the privilege of presenting the very first session for vJUG, a new virtual Java User Group that allows us to span geographies when sharing talks and stories. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in the vJUG idea, especially now I&amp;rsquo;m not in London - if we can find good ways to share knowledge without having to travel, that will help us reach people who don&amp;rsquo;t normally go to conferences or don&amp;rsquo;t have a local user group to go to. &amp;nbsp;Not to mention cutting travel costs and saving the environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;See the event, and the record of the IRC chat, here:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;  &lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/GixwXNlZ7dI&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The slides are also online, but obviously they&amp;rsquo;re part of the video as well:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/28495923&#34; style=&#34;border-width: 1px 1px 0; border: 1px solid #CCC; margin-bottom: 5px;&#34; width=&#34;427&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 5px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/design-is-a-process-not-a-document&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Design is a process, not a Document&#34;&gt;Design is a process, not a Document&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trisha Gee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make the Future Java</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/make_the_future_java</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/make_the_future_java</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/6a9HAO0Pmkc&#34; width=&#34;420&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think this is a nice example of how to showcase technology and make it relevant and exciting for people. &amp;nbsp;Something with this approach could do more for increasing the number of people interested in programming as a career than any of the traditional approaches of getting kids and &amp;ldquo;minorities&amp;rdquo; interested in IT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Stephen Chin about JavaOne 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveonjava&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt;, one of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Java Evangelists and the JavaOne content chair, interviewed me via a live stream about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/58136652766/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0&#34;&gt;new MongoDB Java driver&lt;/a&gt;, and my plans to Change The World.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was a fun interview to do, and I really like the format of being interviewed over Skype and streaming my desktop. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s a slight (OK, 25 seconds, not really low latency) lag between the screen and the speaking which means it&amp;rsquo;s not a great platform for doing live demos, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d like to do more code demos in this way, if I can find a suitable platform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/MdOHjGtITjo?list=PLX8CzqL3ArzXMvt5y8VHXKmr8gDC-xOH_&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life on both sides of the interview table</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InfoQ has posted the video of Dan North and I opining on the subject of hiring. &amp;nbsp;Most of the talk is spent on how to be a good interviewer, and touches on how to market your company to prospective hires. &amp;nbsp;We spend less time on how to do well as an interviewee, but in theory if you know what&amp;rsquo;s going through the interviewer&amp;rsquo;s mind, you should be in a much better position to take control of the interview and shine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/job-interview-tips#.UiBS9_WZJyU.blogger&#34;&gt;Hire Education - Making Interviews Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of funny because we talk a lot about hiring at ThoughtWorks (where we both worked, and which has one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/hardest-tech-company-job-interviews-2012-8&#34;&gt;toughest interview processes&lt;/a&gt; in the industry) and LMAX, which learnt a lot off ThoughtWorks and shaped its own process for a smaller company that has different goals. &amp;nbsp;Yet neither of us work at those places now. &amp;nbsp;Still, we share stories from many of the places we&amp;rsquo;ve worked (or chose not to work), and if there&amp;rsquo;s one take-home point, it&amp;rsquo;s that hiring (and being hired) is not a simple thing to do well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good overview of the NoSQL hype for Real Developers</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/good_overview_of_the_nosql_hype_for_real_developers</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/good_overview_of_the_nosql_hype_for_real_developers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I went to a London Java Community talk which promised to debunk the hype around NoSQL. &amp;nbsp;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re already bought into a NoSQL technology, or you&amp;rsquo;re just wondering what all the noise is about, it&amp;rsquo;s worth an hour out of your day to see Akmal Chaudhri&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive summary of the technologies out there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Skillsmatter recorded the whole thing, as usual, so you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://skillsmatter.com/podcast/nosql/considerations-for-using-nosql-technology-on-your-next-it-project/mh-7167&#34;&gt;watch the presentation for yourself&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I promise neither I nor anyone else from 10gen paid him to mention MongoDB so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx UK 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_uk_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_uk_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was the first Devoxx UK, bringing the brand from Belgium and, more recently, France. &amp;nbsp;And I think it was a HUGE success.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, disclaimers first - I was on the programme committee, so I might say that the whole thing was awesome. &amp;nbsp;Although in all honesty, even being slightly involved in the organisation of a conference is a lot of work, and you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the back of it (and I didn&amp;rsquo;t do half as much as some people). &amp;nbsp;Note to self - never speak at a conference you&amp;rsquo;re on the programme committee for, it&amp;rsquo;s too much work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=90440057274722849&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/download/attachments/6392384/DevoxxUK-2013.jpg?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1364404914960&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/download/attachments/6392384/DevoxxUK-2013.jpg?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1364404914960&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a speaker and attendee though, Devoxx was really brilliant - great speakers, interesting content, awesome friendly atmosphere, good venue, parties with free drink and good opportunities to speak to people. &amp;nbsp;There were downsides: limited coffee availability, no free croissants, um&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m really struggling to think of anything else, and none of those are show-stoppers (especially&amp;nbsp;when the venue is in Islington, so you can step outside and get whatever you want).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All throughout the run up to the conference we kept hearing it was a conference &amp;ldquo;for developers, by developers&amp;rdquo; until I was nearly sick of it. &amp;nbsp;But it was a mantra that kept us on track when we were deciding on content, and it really came through on the two days of the conference. &amp;nbsp;Pretty much everyone on stage was, or had been, a developer, the talks were a good balance between &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; stuff for our day jobs and &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; stuff for techies &amp;lt;insert joke about some being &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;. &amp;nbsp;The future track excited us with things like like hacking on the Raspberry Pi, and the rest of the conference had a good mix of Java SE, EE, methodology and Other Stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, the highlights were:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Kevlin+Henney&#34;&gt;Kevlin Henney&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s keynote, reminding us that Developers Are Human. &amp;nbsp;Who knew?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Sandro+Mancuso&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s walkthrough of OO principals, and how they apply to us in our actual day jobs. &amp;nbsp;Sandro did a good job of taking quite a dry topic, that many of us dozed through at university, and showing us why we already use these principals and how understanding them will make us better programmers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Mazz+Mosley&#34;&gt;Mazz Mosley&lt;/a&gt; had an entertaining talk about the Dark Side of Agile, walking us through the agile practices in The Government and highlighting many of the unanswered questions that teams have after switching to agile.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Colin+Vipurs&#34;&gt;Colin Vipurs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s talked about Test Driven Development from the trenches - he managed to give a good intro for those who might not have done it in practice, but for those who may have been doing it for a while, this a) was a good reminder of good practice and b) gave a good insight into why we do it. &amp;nbsp;On top of that, he had solid advice on how to write better tests, that we could all take home with us.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Martin Thompson&lt;/a&gt; gave the talk I was attempting to give at JAX London last year - what is performance and how do we achieve high performance in Java? &amp;nbsp;Where I failed, Martin really rocked it. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving that to the professionals.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It would be rude of me not to mention this point - what a diverse conference! &amp;nbsp;We had developers of all shapes and sizes, from the suits to the mohawks, of all colours, and (by technical conference standards) lots of women. &amp;nbsp;Watch the video below and I think you can see it. &amp;nbsp;I was so proud to have been a part of it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;and meeting everyone. &amp;nbsp;What an awesome conference for networking! &amp;nbsp;Of course, there was a large number of London Java Community people there (speaking, volunteering, and attending), and quite a few familiar faces from Devoxx Antwerp - it was brilliant to see them in London. &amp;nbsp;But I was also very pleased to run into people I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with in the past, some I haven&amp;rsquo;t see for ages, and some I still see regularly. &amp;nbsp;And I met dozens of new, interesting people - you guys really made the conference for me.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was giving my new presentation, What Do You Mean, Backwards Compatibility? &amp;nbsp;In this talk I share some of the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had in helping to develop the new MongoDB Java driver. &amp;nbsp;This is not really a MongoDB talk, although there are some examples from the new driver, it&amp;rsquo;s more a talk about design, and how we as developers make design decisions every day, something I don&amp;rsquo;t think we recognise very much. &amp;nbsp;As always, I&amp;rsquo;ll post a link to the video when it becomes available. &amp;nbsp;However, I am hoping to give this presentation a number of times this year, so if you missed it there will be another opportunity to see it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;As usual, my take-away theme from a conference is probably influenced by the sessions I attended, so is as much a function of what I think is important right now as it is an indication of what themes are emerging in the industry. &amp;nbsp;But I came away from Devoxx feeling like there&amp;rsquo;s a desire to focus on the basics - the OO principals that have been around for years; the good design practices that have been written about many times; and, most of all, a reminder that developers have a difficult job - we don&amp;rsquo;t simply turn requirements into code, we are constantly doing tricky stuff like system design, and even trickier stuff like working with other people.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I loved Devoxx UK, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alone in feeling a bit empty when it was all over. &amp;nbsp;To re-live a tiny amount of the event, or get a good feel of what it was like, watch this video by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/62905094&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/62905094&#34;&gt;Devoxx UK 2013 - Long mellow version&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;As with all Devoxx events, the talks will be available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/#home&#34;&gt;Parleys&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;If you watch nothing else, watch Kevlin&amp;rsquo;s keynote.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDL Presents Women Techmakers with Trisha Gee</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/gdl_presents_women_techmakers_with_trisha_gee</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/gdl_presents_women_techmakers_with_trisha_gee</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was flattered a couple of weeks ago to be interviewed by Google as part of their women techmaker&amp;rsquo;s series, as it moves over to Europe.  In this video I talk about going to Mars, education, planning your career, being a developer, and the impact of technology on our lives.  So, not much&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;  &lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/68bsagK7GEM&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed at Devoxx</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_devoxx</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_devoxx</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yolande Poirier from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/index.html&#34;&gt;OTN&lt;/a&gt; interviewed me at Devoxx about my new job at 10gen, Women in IT (bet that surprises you), how to be a role model, and Agile. &amp;nbsp;Enjoy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;395&#34; width=&#34;395&#34;&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;direct&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#222222&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;flashVars&#34; value=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3544&#34;/&gt;  &lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; flashVars=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3544&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#222222&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;395&#34;/&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx: The Problem with Women - A Technical Approach</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As well as talking about, you know, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/12/agile-when-agile-goes-well.html&#34;&gt;actual work-type-stuff&lt;/a&gt;, I was encouraged to give my &amp;ldquo;Technical Approach to Women&amp;rdquo; presentation at Devoxx. &amp;nbsp;This went so well at JavaOne that I thought it would be difficult to top. &amp;nbsp;Also, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t convinced it would work at Devoxx, because the theatres are not well suited to audience participation - the seats are warm and comfy, the room is dark, the speaker is on stage in front of a massive screen&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was incredibly impressed with the audience. &amp;nbsp;There were literally hundreds of people, most of them men. &amp;nbsp;To me, it proved once again that the men in this industry are determined to &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; this problem of gender imbalance. &amp;nbsp;And they&amp;rsquo;re happy to extend that to improving diversity as a whole, once you highlight the bigger problem. &amp;nbsp;It says to me that this is not naturally a misogynistic industry, where you have to fight against the boys club to get anywhere. &amp;nbsp;It says to me that we are all in this together. &amp;nbsp;After all, in the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; world the geeks are still outsiders, and different, so we&amp;rsquo;re used to embracing our different-ness - whether that&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re the only girl in the room, the only Java developer at a .NET conference, or the only techy at a dinner party.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Conferences are a self-selecting audience, I know - these are the people who are investing time and money in advancing their careers, or at least encouraging their employers to do. &amp;nbsp;But for the punchline of this session, these are exactly the right people. &amp;nbsp;We need to go out, tell everyone how much we enjoy our jobs; tell kids that programming is cool, and &lt;i&gt;show&lt;/i&gt; them it&amp;rsquo;s fun; mentor other people, and each other, and be a role model. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t care what gender you are or what colour you are or what your dark secret is - &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; are the role model to inspire someone. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/p/just-do-something.html&#34;&gt;Just do it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;395&#34; width=&#34;395&#34;&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;direct&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#222222&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;flashVars&#34; value=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3513&#34;/&gt;  &lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; flashVars=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3513&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#222222&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;395&#34;/&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NightHacking Tour: The LJC</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_tour_the_ljc</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_tour_the_ljc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the same day &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/interview-and-hacking-session-with.html&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin came to see me&lt;/a&gt; at the 10gen offices, we also ran a NightHacking session in the evening with the London Java Community. &amp;nbsp;Not many people turned up (maybe I need to work on my signage to the office?) but it was a great session. In fact, having less people meant we could all be involved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Expect &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;s and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/overview/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/f2a9XvZNq0o&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview and Hacking session with Stephen Chin</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_and_hacking_session_with_stephen_chin</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_and_hacking_session_with_stephen_chin</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/c5-jyvVnqT0?fs=1&#34; width=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On Monday, &lt;a href=&#34;http://steveonjava.com/&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt; from Oracle visited me at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.10gen.com/&#34;&gt;10gen&lt;/a&gt; offices as part of his &lt;a href=&#34;http://steveonjava.com/nighthacking/&#34;&gt;NightHacking tour&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;In the video we talk about my sessions at JavaOne and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6391499&#34;&gt;Agile presentation&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m giving at Devoxx, and I do some very basic hacking using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Java+Tutorial&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java driver&lt;/a&gt;, attempting to showcase &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gradle.org/&#34;&gt;gradle&lt;/a&gt; at the same time. It was a fun experience, even if it&amp;rsquo;s scary being live-streamed and recorded!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed at GOTO Copenhagen</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_goto_copenhagen</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_goto_copenhagen</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was interviewed at GOTO Copenhagen, about Java, the Disruptor, the Graduate Developer Community &amp;amp; London Java Community, and a whole host of other things. &amp;nbsp;So to make up for the lack of blogging this month, here it is:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/0OcczjVXQQc&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London: Disruptor presentation video</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_disruptor_presentation_video</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_london_disruptor_presentation_video</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Disruptor&amp;rdquo; presentation I gave at QCon London is now available on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Concurrent-Programming-Using-The-Disruptor#.T8-KKWLH1R4.blogger&#34;&gt;InfoQ site&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;This is the same presentation as the one I gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/new-disruptor-presentation-unveiled-to.html&#34;&gt;Skillsmatter in March&lt;/a&gt;, but the questions are different. &amp;nbsp;Plus since I&amp;rsquo;m winging it every time, I probably cover slightly different things or explain some stuff better / worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Why we shouldn&#39;t target women</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/video_why_we_shouldnt_target_women</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/video_why_we_shouldnt_target_women</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/&#34;&gt;Parleys&lt;/a&gt; subscription, you can watch the whole &amp;ldquo;Why we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t target women&amp;rdquo; panel from Devoxx 2011 a month or so ago. &amp;nbsp;Watch me attempt to monopolise the whole panel as if it was my idea or something&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;395&#34; width=&#34;395&#34;&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34;/&gt;     &lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;     &lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;direct&#34;/&gt;     &lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#222222&#34;/&gt;     &lt;param name=&#34;flashVars&#34; value=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=2861&#34;/&gt;     &lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; flashVars=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=2861&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#222222&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;395&#34;/&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview by the Oracle Technology Network at Devoxx</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tori Wieldt from the Oracle Technology Network interviewed me at Devoxx. &amp;nbsp;Because I was there to be on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/11/why-we-shouldnt-target-women.html&#34;&gt;Why We Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Target Women&lt;/a&gt; panel, the interview is just another platform for me to air my views on this subject again. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;395&#34; width=&#34;395&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;direct&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#222222&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;flashVars&#34; value=&#34;sv=true&amp;pageId=2769&#34; &gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; flashVars=&#34;sv=true&amp;pageId=2769&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#222222&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;395&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, I am actually wearing pink&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
