<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Video on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/video/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nighthacking at Sevilla Java User Group</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_jug_sevilla</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_jug_sevilla</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday &lt;a href=&#34;http://steveonjava.com/&#34;&gt;Mr Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt; came to Sevilla on his crazy European tour to show us Lego and Robots.  This was our largest turnout yet
for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Java User Group&lt;/a&gt; event in Sevilla, which surprised me as it was on a weekend,
and the weekend before the spectacle that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Week_in_Seville&#34;&gt;Semana
Santa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/I5rnDZGNJW8&#34;&gt;in Sevilla&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also the first event that we&amp;rsquo;ve had videoed (apologies for the horrible focus at times on the video,
I&amp;rsquo;m just learning and used to relying heavily on auto-focus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/q3OKs08X3oo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks very much to Stephen for visiting, and thank you to those who came, you&amp;rsquo;re making me re-think the idea of running events at
weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/photos/all_photos/?photoAlbumId=21306622&#34;&gt;photos on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, Backwards Compatibility? (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOW recorded me, yet again, talking about the adventure that is the design of the new Java Driver for MongoDB.  This is the same talk I
gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;,
with some updates based on our Journey So Far.  In it, I cover the architecture of the new driver and some of our current thoughts
around where we want the API to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yow.eventer.com/yow-2013-1080/what-do-you-mean-backwards-compatibility-by-trisha-gee-1398&#34;&gt;See the video here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Advice for Programmers (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I have a tendancy to bang on every now and again about how we, as developers, could do better in managing our careers (for example,
by &lt;a href=&#34;/post/how_to_make_your_cv_not_suck/&#34;&gt;creating CVs that don&amp;rsquo;t suck&lt;/a&gt;, and by &lt;a href=&#34;/post/staying_ahead_of_the_curve/&#34;&gt;staying ahead of the curve&lt;/a&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davethomas.net/&#34;&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/a&gt; asked me to speak for a mere 50 minutes on the subject at &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon
.com/video#36&#34;&gt;GOTO Aarhus&lt;/a&gt;, a talk I wasn&amp;rsquo;t enormously happy with as there was no way to cover a lifetime of hard-fought experience in such a short
time.  Dave seemed to like something in it though, as he gave me the opportunity to present the topic again at YOW last December,
and this time I think I managed to distill the important points into the (still ridiculously short) time allotted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yow.eventer.com/yow-2013-1080/career-advice-for-programmers-by-trisha-gee-1380&#34;&gt;See the video here&lt;/a&gt;,
and please give me any feedback you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recognise there are many many more topics I could cover, so I&amp;rsquo;d better start making a list.  Suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Charles Humble for InfoQ</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/infoq-interview-march-2014</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/infoq-interview-march-2014</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/qcon_london_2014/&#34;&gt;QCon London&lt;/a&gt;, I was grabbed for an interview with InfoQ.  It&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasure to be interviewed by Charles,
I think he brings out the best in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the video &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/interviews/trisha-gee-mongdo-java8#.U00BRMNMIC4.blogger&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the interview we refer to the first time we met, which, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested, &lt;a href=&#34;/post/interviewed_for_infoq_at_qcon_london/&#34;&gt;you can also watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First presentation at the Virtual JUG!</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had the privilege of presenting the very first session for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/virtualJUG/&#34;&gt;vJUG&lt;/a&gt;, a new virtual Java User Group that allows us to span
geographies when sharing talks and stories. I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in the vJUG idea, especially now I&amp;rsquo;m not in London - if we can find
good ways to share knowledge without having to travel, that will help us reach people who don&amp;rsquo;t normally go to conferences or don&amp;rsquo;t have
a local user group to go to. Not to mention cutting travel costs and saving the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the event, and the record of the IRC chat, here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/GixwXNlZ7dI&#34;
width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides are also online, but obviously they&amp;rsquo;re part of the video as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;356&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/28495923&#34; style=&#34;border-width: 1px 1px 0; border: 1px solid #CCC; margin-bottom: 5px;&#34; width=&#34;427&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 5px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/design-is-a-process-not-a-document&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Design is a process, not a Document&#34;&gt;Design is a process, not a Document&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trisha Gee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make the Future Java</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/make_the_future_java</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/make_the_future_java</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/6a9HAO0Pmkc&#34; width=&#34;420&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think this is a nice example of how to showcase technology and make it relevant and exciting for people. &amp;nbsp;Something with this approach could do more for increasing the number of people interested in programming as a career than any of the traditional approaches of getting kids and &amp;ldquo;minorities&amp;rdquo; interested in IT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Stephen Chin about JavaOne 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveonjava&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin&lt;/a&gt;, one of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Java Evangelists and the JavaOne content chair, interviewed me via a live stream about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mongodb.org/post/58136652766/the-mongodb-java-driver-3-0&#34;&gt;new MongoDB Java driver&lt;/a&gt;, and my plans to Change The World.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was a fun interview to do, and I really like the format of being interviewed over Skype and streaming my desktop. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s a slight (OK, 25 seconds, not really low latency) lag between the screen and the speaking which means it&amp;rsquo;s not a great platform for doing live demos, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d like to do more code demos in this way, if I can find a suitable platform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/MdOHjGtITjo?list=PLX8CzqL3ArzXMvt5y8VHXKmr8gDC-xOH_&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life on both sides of the interview table</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InfoQ has posted the video of Dan North and I opining on the subject of hiring. &amp;nbsp;Most of the talk is spent on how to be a good interviewer, and touches on how to market your company to prospective hires. &amp;nbsp;We spend less time on how to do well as an interviewee, but in theory if you know what&amp;rsquo;s going through the interviewer&amp;rsquo;s mind, you should be in a much better position to take control of the interview and shine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/job-interview-tips#.UiBS9_WZJyU.blogger&#34;&gt;Hire Education - Making Interviews Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of funny because we talk a lot about hiring at ThoughtWorks (where we both worked, and which has one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/hardest-tech-company-job-interviews-2012-8&#34;&gt;toughest interview processes&lt;/a&gt; in the industry) and LMAX, which learnt a lot off ThoughtWorks and shaped its own process for a smaller company that has different goals. &amp;nbsp;Yet neither of us work at those places now. &amp;nbsp;Still, we share stories from many of the places we&amp;rsquo;ve worked (or chose not to work), and if there&amp;rsquo;s one take-home point, it&amp;rsquo;s that hiring (and being hired) is not a simple thing to do well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Summary of GeeCON, Krakow</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_summary_of_geecon_krakow</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_summary_of_geecon_krakow</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in Krakow, Poland for &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.geecon.org/&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Which was excellent! &amp;nbsp;I find it really
interesting that conferences all have their own personalities, that they are not all the same.
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QGi20Kv1QL0/UZyWDc9hzVI/AAAAAAAALj0/ZlJ-1o1rLBk/s1600/2013-05-18+19.35.58.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QGi20Kv1QL0/UZyWDc9hzVI/AAAAAAAALj0/ZlJ-1o1rLBk/s320/2013-05-18+19.35.58.jpg&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
GeeCON had its own distinct personality. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re a Java/JVM person based in Poland, I would highly recommend it - more than 90%
of the attendees were Polish (probably the remainder were largely speakers) so this conference is very much for you. &amp;nbsp;The quality
of the speakers was really good too, I learnt a lot off many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a speaker&amp;rsquo;s point of view, there were some cultural things which took a bit of getting used to. One of the good things was that the
audience was very keen on asking questions, they were much more interactive than a typical London audience (for example). However,
I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to quite short questions, and I found that the audience liked to give a lot of detail in their questions and frequently
ask more than one at once - this meant that all the speakers really needed to allocate a lot more time for Q &amp;amp; A than expected. One
of the other things I found unusual was the number of people who would walk in and out of the room during sessions - this wasn&amp;rsquo;t just
everyone fleeing my session (I hope!), I saw it happen in all the talks, even the keynotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;My stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day I was on a panel about diversity in IT, which was basically about women programmers (again). It was a good panel to be
on, actually, because there were a range of opinions, including downright disagreement, which made for a more interesting discussion.
Sadly it left the audience with too little time to contribute though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day I was presenting &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean, backwards compatibility?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;,
which elicited a lot of responses from the audience. &amp;nbsp;I think I got the balance right between providing food for thought for any
Java programmer, and enough of a look into what we&amp;rsquo;re considering for the new MongoDB Java driver,
that it felt like I satisfied the two audiences - those who are interested in MongoDB with Java,
and those who&amp;hellip; aren&amp;rsquo;t (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t my experience as a speaker which really made GeeCON for me. &amp;nbsp;For the first time in ages I felt like I learnt
something as an attendee. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that&amp;rsquo;s because a) I only had one presentation to prepare so I had time for a lot of
sessions b) we have some specific problems we&amp;rsquo;re trying to solve on our code right now that we&amp;rsquo;re looking for answers to or c) the
conference inspired it, but I came out of a lot of sessions excited about things to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first take-away point is to try &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/spock/&#34;&gt;Spock&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told for ages that I need to give it a
 go, but the session really sold it to me. &amp;nbsp;It seems to have features that will solve specific things we&amp;rsquo;re looking at right now,
 including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplifying mocking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annotating tests with properties (e.g. &lt;code&gt;@Slow&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running the same test with different sets of data, instead of having to copy-paste the test a bunch of times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting of failures, particularly power assert and &lt;code&gt;@Unroll&lt;/code&gt;, make diagnosing failures much simpler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using BDD terms as keywords (given/when/then) means the tests really do document themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m totally sold on it. &amp;nbsp;I was concerned, because we&amp;rsquo;re writing an open source Java library and I want the unit/integration tests
to be understandable to Java developers, and I worried that adding Groovy tests might make the learning curve steeper. &amp;nbsp;But I think
it&amp;rsquo;s an idea worth playing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Asynchronous IO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one of the things we&amp;rsquo;re working on is trying to figure out the best way to provide an async Java driver. &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.geecon
.org/speakers/erik-onnen&#34;&gt;Erik Onnen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s talk around performance network programming on the JVM was really interesting. &amp;nbsp;Most
usefully, it compared sync to async communication, outlining the pros and cons, and how you can do it on the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Build the right thing before you build the thing right&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first keynote was about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pretotyping.org/&#34;&gt;Pretotyping&lt;/a&gt; - Patrick Copeland from Google was talking
about ideas and innovators, and blowing away the myth that all it takes to make money is a single great idea. He highlighted how
really great ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily successes, and some ideas that sound great don&amp;rsquo;t feel right in practice. Pretotyping is a
way to test things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pgXRSN4oq0k/UZyVTqpUoFI/AAAAAAAALjk/1evlD4F4nYY/s1600/2013-05-15+10.30.13.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right;
margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pgXRSN4oq0k/UZyVTqpUoFI/AAAAAAAALjk/1evlD4F4nYY/s320/2013-05-15+10.30.13.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Would you use it / do it?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How would you interact with it?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is it socially acceptable to use it in the
circumstances?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s very low tech, very low effort (think post-its and note pads, not HTML prototypes) it facilitates fast failure (therefore
reducing the cost).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session was videoed, so hopefully it will be available to see. If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of An Idea, I highly recommend this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Many users = anthropology, not user experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/&#34;&gt;Joel Spolksy&lt;/a&gt;, the man who inspired me to start this very blog (well,
earlier incarnations of it) talked about the experiences of growing stack exchange. This was interesting because it was not about
the technology, but about subtle things you can do to influence user&amp;rsquo;s behaviour - for example, reputation rewards &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; behaviour,
and a better reputation means you are trusted to do more on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was another inspiring talk if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in creating a product or company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-P-ejmRc3bsg/UZyUtEyArWI/AAAAAAAALjc/qP2tXp-nZkY/s1600/2013-05-18+20.09.07.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em;
margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-P-ejmRc3bsg/UZyUtEyArWI/AAAAAAAALjc/qP2tXp-nZkY/s400/2013-05-18+20.09.07.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I also met a lot of really interesting people who gave me a lot to think about. I&amp;rsquo;ve come back more motivated than ever to work on my various projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Krakow is beautiful, and GeeCON is a good learning experience. &amp;nbsp;Go next year if you can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good overview of the NoSQL hype for Real Developers</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/good_overview_of_the_nosql_hype_for_real_developers</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/good_overview_of_the_nosql_hype_for_real_developers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I went to a London Java Community talk which promised to debunk the hype around NoSQL. &amp;nbsp;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re already bought into a NoSQL technology, or you&amp;rsquo;re just wondering what all the noise is about, it&amp;rsquo;s worth an hour out of your day to see Akmal Chaudhri&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive summary of the technologies out there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Skillsmatter recorded the whole thing, as usual, so you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://skillsmatter.com/podcast/nosql/considerations-for-using-nosql-technology-on-your-next-it-project/mh-7167&#34;&gt;watch the presentation for yourself&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I promise neither I nor anyone else from 10gen paid him to mention MongoDB so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx UK 2013</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_uk_2013</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_uk_2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was the first Devoxx UK, bringing the brand from Belgium and, more recently, France. And I think it was a HUGE success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, disclaimers first - I was on the programme committee, so I might say that the whole thing was awesome. Although in all
honesty, even being slightly involved in the organisation of a conference is a lot of work, and you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the back of it
(and I didn&amp;rsquo;t do half as much as some people). Note to self - never speak at a conference you&amp;rsquo;re on the programme committee for,
it&amp;rsquo;s too much work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=90440057274722849&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/download/attachments/6392384/DevoxxUK-2013.jpg?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1364404914960&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/download/attachments/6392384/DevoxxUK-2013.jpg?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1364404914960&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a speaker and attendee though, Devoxx was really brilliant - great speakers, interesting content, awesome friendly atmosphere,
good venue, parties with free drink and good opportunities to speak to people. There were downsides: limited coffee availability,
no free croissants, um&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m really struggling to think of anything else, and none of those are show-stoppers (especially when the
venue is in Islington, so you can step outside and get whatever you want).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All throughout the run up to the conference we
kept hearing it was a conference &amp;ldquo;for developers, by developers&amp;rdquo; until I was nearly sick of it. But it was a mantra that kept us
on track when we were deciding on content, and it really came through on the two days of the conference. Pretty much everyone on
stage was, or had been, a developer, the talks were a good balance between &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; stuff for our day jobs and &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; stuff for
techies &amp;lt;insert joke about some being &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;. The future track excited us with things like like hacking
on the Raspberry Pi, and the rest of the conference had a good mix of Java SE, EE, methodology and Other Stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the highlights were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Kevlin+Henney&#34;&gt;Kevlin Henney&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s keynote, reminding us that Developers Are Human. Who knew?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Sandro+Mancuso&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s walkthrough of OO principals,
and how they apply to us in our actual day jobs. Sandro did a good job of taking quite a dry topic,
that many of us dozed through at university, and showing us why we already use these principals and how understanding them
will make us better programmers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Mazz+Mosley&#34;&gt;Mazz Mosley&lt;/a&gt; had an entertaining talk about the Dark Side of Agile,
walking us through the agile practices in The Government and highlighting many of the unanswered questions that teams have after
switching to agile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Colin+Vipurs&#34;&gt;Colin Vipurs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s talked about Test Driven Development from the trenches -
he managed to give a good intro for those who might not have done it in practice, but for those who may have been doing it for a while,
this a) was a good reminder of good practice and b) gave a good insight into why we do it. On top of that,
he had solid advice on how to write better tests, that we could all take home with us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Martin Thompson&lt;/a&gt; gave the talk I was attempting to give at JAX London last
year - what is performance and how do we achieve high performance in Java? Where I failed,
Martin really rocked it.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving that to the professionals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be rude of me not to mention this point - what a diverse conference! We had developers of all shapes and sizes,
from the suits to the mohawks, of all colours, and (by technical conference standards) lots of women. Watch the video below and I think
you can see it. I was so proud to have been a part of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;and meeting everyone. What an awesome conference for networking! Of course, there was a large number of London Java
Community people there (speaking, volunteering, and attending), and quite a few familiar faces from Devoxx Antwerp - it was brilliant to
see them in London. But I was also very pleased to run into people I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with in the past, some I haven&amp;rsquo;t see for ages,
and some I still see regularly. And I met dozens of new, interesting people - you guys really made the conference for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was giving my new presentation,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;What Do You Mean, Backwards Compatibility?&lt;/a&gt;. In this talk I share
some of the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had in helping to develop the new MongoDB Java driver. This is not really a MongoDB talk,
although there are some examples from the new driver, it&amp;rsquo;s more a talk about design, and how we as developers make design decisions
every day, something I don&amp;rsquo;t think we recognise very much. I am hoping to give this presentation a number of times this year,
so if you missed it there will be another opportunity to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, my take-away theme from a conference is probably influenced by the sessions I attended,
so is as much a function of what I think is important right now as it is an indication of what themes are emerging in the industry. But
I came away from Devoxx feeling like there&amp;rsquo;s a desire to focus on the basics - the OO principals that have been around for years; the
good design practices that have been written about many times; and, most of all, a reminder that developers have a difficult job - we
don&amp;rsquo;t simply turn requirements into code, we are constantly doing tricky stuff like system design,
and even trickier stuff like working with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved Devoxx UK, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alone in feeling a bit empty when it was all over. To re-live a tiny amount of the event,
or get a good feel of what it was like, watch this video by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/62905094&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/62905094&#34;&gt;Devoxx UK 2013 - Long mellow version&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/royvanrijn&#34;&gt;Roy van Rijn&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Devoxx events, the talks will be available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/#home&#34;&gt;Parleys&lt;/a&gt;. If you watch nothing else, watch Kevlin&amp;rsquo;s keynote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDL Presents Women Techmakers with Trisha Gee</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/gdl_presents_women_techmakers_with_trisha_gee</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/gdl_presents_women_techmakers_with_trisha_gee</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was flattered a couple of weeks ago to be interviewed by Google as part of their women techmaker&amp;rsquo;s series,
as it moves over to Europe.  In this video I talk about going to Mars, education, planning your career, being a developer,
and the impact of technology on our lives.  So, not much&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/68bsagK7GEM&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed at Devoxx</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interviewed_at_devoxx</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interviewed_at_devoxx</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yolande Poirier from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/index.html&#34;&gt;OTN&lt;/a&gt; interviewed me at Devoxx about my new job at 10gen,
Women in IT (bet that surprises you), how to be a role model, and Agile. Enjoy.
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;395&#34; width=&#34;395&#34;&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;direct&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#222222&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;flashVars&#34; value=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3544&#34;/&gt;  &lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; flashVars=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3544&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#222222&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;395&#34;/&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx: The Problem with Women - A Technical Approach</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_problem_with_women__a_technical_approach</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As well as talking about, you know, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/12/agile-when-agile-goes-well.html&#34;&gt;actual work-type-stuff&lt;/a&gt;, I was encouraged to give my &amp;ldquo;Technical Approach to Women&amp;rdquo; presentation at Devoxx. &amp;nbsp;This went so well at JavaOne that I thought it would be difficult to top. &amp;nbsp;Also, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t convinced it would work at Devoxx, because the theatres are not well suited to audience participation - the seats are warm and comfy, the room is dark, the speaker is on stage in front of a massive screen&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was incredibly impressed with the audience. &amp;nbsp;There were literally hundreds of people, most of them men. &amp;nbsp;To me, it proved once again that the men in this industry are determined to &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; this problem of gender imbalance. &amp;nbsp;And they&amp;rsquo;re happy to extend that to improving diversity as a whole, once you highlight the bigger problem. &amp;nbsp;It says to me that this is not naturally a misogynistic industry, where you have to fight against the boys club to get anywhere. &amp;nbsp;It says to me that we are all in this together. &amp;nbsp;After all, in the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; world the geeks are still outsiders, and different, so we&amp;rsquo;re used to embracing our different-ness - whether that&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re the only girl in the room, the only Java developer at a .NET conference, or the only techy at a dinner party.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Conferences are a self-selecting audience, I know - these are the people who are investing time and money in advancing their careers, or at least encouraging their employers to do. &amp;nbsp;But for the punchline of this session, these are exactly the right people. &amp;nbsp;We need to go out, tell everyone how much we enjoy our jobs; tell kids that programming is cool, and &lt;i&gt;show&lt;/i&gt; them it&amp;rsquo;s fun; mentor other people, and each other, and be a role model. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t care what gender you are or what colour you are or what your dark secret is - &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; are the role model to inspire someone. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/p/just-do-something.html&#34;&gt;Just do it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;395&#34; width=&#34;395&#34;&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;direct&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#222222&#34;/&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;flashVars&#34; value=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3513&#34;/&gt;  &lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/dist/share/parleysshare.swf&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; flashVars=&#34;sv=true&amp;amp;pageId=3513&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#222222&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;395&#34;/&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NightHacking Tour: The LJC</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_tour_the_ljc</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_tour_the_ljc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the same day &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/interview-and-hacking-session-with.html&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin came to see me&lt;/a&gt; at the 10gen offices, we also ran a NightHacking session in the evening with the London Java Community. &amp;nbsp;Not many people turned up (maybe I need to work on my signage to the office?) but it was a great session. In fact, having less people meant we could all be involved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Expect &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;s and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/overview/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/f2a9XvZNq0o&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
