<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>presenting on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/presenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in presenting on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/presenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Tips - Focus on Either Content or Delivery</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/st_content_or_delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/st_content_or_delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re a new speaker, or just starting to consider speaking at conferences or user groups 
for the first time, it&#39;s easy to become overwhelmed by all the things you worry 
about when delivering a talk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Tips - What to Wear</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/st_what_to_wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/st_what_to_wear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years I&#39;ve avoided talking about the topic of what to wear when presenting. I didn&#39;t want to cover it because I 
didn&#39;t want people to think that I only worried about this topic because I was a woman. I also didn&#39;t want other 
women to inherit any of my neuroses around deciding what to wear. I&#39;m the sort of person who always enjoyed thinking
long and hard about what to wear the next day at work, and I know that&#39;s not how everyone works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Tips - Wearing a Roaming Mic is More Complicated Than I Realised</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/st_mic_fitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/st_mic_fitting/</guid>
      <description>I realise I have a bunch of experience and advice for speakers and potential speakers that I simply haven&#39;t written down or shared. Here&#39;s the first piece on things to consider that you might not have thought about.
Note: as usual, my advice is from the point of view of a woman (me) and is aimed mostly at women, but also as usual it&#39;s probably useful for others to know too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Conferences Do To Attract More Women Speakers?</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/more_women_speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/more_women_speakers/</guid>
      <description>Now I&#39;ve been speaking at (mostly Java) conferences for a while (six years now), I get asked to present at a lot of conferences. Obviously all these conferences are mostly interested in my terribly educational talks, but it&#39;s also because I&#39;m a technical woman and there aren&#39;t very many technical women speaking at conferences.
In my experience, conferences want to do the right thing - they want a diverse line up of speakers, they want to attract diverse attendees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>