<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaZone 2016</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javazone_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javazone_2016/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote a conference write up. The short version of &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; is because I got a bit bored of doing it. Plus, I found I was attending conferences as a speaker &amp;ldquo;on the circuit&amp;rdquo;, and my experience of hanging out, catching up with my friends, chatting to other attendees to see what they&amp;rsquo;re up to and so forth, didn&amp;rsquo;t seem as useful to share with people who might want to find out whether a conference is worth attending from a content or atmosphere point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Xtended</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed that the more I go to conferences, the less I write about them. I could claim lack of time, but the fact is that all my write-ups will be something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Loved &amp;lt;city&amp;gt;, went to talks that made me think, met interesting people, gave a talk or two that seemed to go well&amp;rdquo;. Not sure if people get bored of reading that, but I get bored of writing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2014, Day One</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m at JavaOne again, and after only one day I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt stuff.  And, of course,
had a great time catching up with interesting people.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the first day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could possibly go wrong? (GOTO Chicago)</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, I was given the chance to chat a bit about the presentation I was giving,
which happens to be the same one I&amp;rsquo;m giving at a number of conferences this year (although of course I&amp;rsquo;m evolving it as I go along).
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>