<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Conference on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/conference/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Xtended</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6771.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34; alt=&#34;The 
calm before the storm&#34; title=&#34;The calm before the storm&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the more I go to conferences, the less I write about them.  I could claim lack of time, but
the fact is that all my write-ups will be something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Loved &amp;lt;city&amp;gt;, went to talks that made me
think, met interesting people, gave a talk or two that seemed to go well&amp;rdquo;. Not sure if people get bored of reading
that, but I get bored of writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6803.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Conferences are fun&#34; title=&#34;Conferences are fun&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I&amp;rsquo;m bored of conferences. On the contrary - since I work from home, travelling to new places and
meeting Real Human Beings keeps me sane. Plus conferences are fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6753.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; alt=&#34;The 
setup&#34; title=&#34;The setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I went to a conference on Saturday that makes me feel compelled to write something, and not just because it was
organised by my two fellow &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Sevilla JUG&lt;/a&gt; organisers.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/israkaos&#34;&gt;@IsraKaos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rgdav&#34;&gt;@RGDav&lt;/a&gt; are both doing more Android day-to-day than
server-side Java, so this is an area they&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about. Not content with organising
Android events every other month, they decided they had so many interesting speakers they wanted to have speaking here
in Sevilla that they wanted to run a whole day, single track conference, on behalf of &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/communities/114997118727600981533&#34;&gt;GDG Sevilla&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidxtended.com/&#34;&gt;Android Xtended&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6848.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Android Xtended&#34; title=&#34;Android Xtended&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;As a Java &amp;ldquo;Technical Advocate&amp;rdquo;, I suppose I should keep an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the Android space, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a
huge part of the ecosystem&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/androidxtended#footnote1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to go in any sort
of official capacity (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t speaking, manning a booth, organising or sponsoring), so I could just enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/registration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hola...&#34; title=&#34;Hola...&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, they roped me into doing registrations. Me! I was concerned my Spanish wasn&amp;rsquo;t up for it, but apparently I only
needed two words: &amp;ldquo;nombre&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;talla&amp;rdquo; (for the t-shirt). Oh, and &amp;ldquo;treinta y uno b&amp;rdquo; - there was such demand for the
conference the initial venue wasn&amp;rsquo;t big enough, so it was being hosted at two sites on the same road. Not
surprisingly, some turned up to the wrong one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6813.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@inmaculadaalcon&#34; title=&#34;@inmaculadaalcon&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike a large number of our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/&#34;&gt;MUG&lt;/a&gt; events, all the talks were in Spanish. So feel
free to ignore my analysis if you like - my Spanish comprehension is pretty good, but sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t realise when
I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand something and just make up my own story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;float:left; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6794.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
alt=&#34;@flipper83&#34; title=&#34;@flipper83&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far in the Android space is Getting Started type material - a lot of tutorials and
examples that show you how to achieve a particular goal. There seems to be less of an emphasis on areas that
interest me as an experienced Java person - easy automation of testing, good design practices, craftsmanship etc. Now,
 it may be that because those areas (apart from testing) apply to both back-end Java and Android, there&amp;rsquo;s less of a
 need to re-iterate it in the Android space. Or it may be that I don&amp;rsquo;t see the entry-level Java stuff any more,
 because I don&amp;rsquo;t need it, and I seek out the topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6892.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
 alt=&#34;@JMPergar&#34; title=&#34;@JMPergar&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or it may be that as Android is one of those
 platforms that&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start as a fairly novice developer (because you can write self-contained code with
 a visible UI and get results fairly easily), lots of the focus is on the needs of new developers.  Whatever the
 reason, I had been starting to feel like the Android ecosystem was missing people taking developers beyond that
 initial step of getting something to work and up to the level of creating maintainable code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6880.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@pedro_g_s&#34; title=&#34;@pedro_g_s&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Xtended put my mind at rest. Here was a range of talks that led attendees through the things that will make
them more effective developers - tools and libraries to use; testing approaches; integration with persistence; clean
(code) design for the UI; design patterns and domain driven design to simplify your code, and so on. As an employee
of JetBrains, I was obviously very happy to see both
&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/tools/studio/index.html&#34;&gt;Android Studio&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; mentioned and used throughout as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6863.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@davilagrau&#34; title=&#34;@davilagrau&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as fantastic speakers (they knew their stuff, were clearly practitioners, and all had great individual
presentation styles), there were three mob-programming sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6853.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mob Programming&#34; title=&#34;Mob Programming&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an ambitious attempt to not just preach to
a passive audience, but to involve them in creating real, working code to teach fundamental practices - dependency
injection, testing and Gradle.  An hour is barely enough time to give a practiced demo of real code, to create
something collaboratively with an audience of 30 people was a challenge. But I thought it did give people a flavour
of not just how to use the technologies, but what they were for. I also saw a lot of the audience starting to
realise the power of refactoring using an IDE - I firmly believe the best way to teach the power of a tool is by
pair programming or, at least, using the tool in real use cases in front of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6921.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More collaboration&#34; title=&#34;More collaboration&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mob programming was kinda
like a half day tutorial squished into an hour. I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to hear how the attendees found it. For me, since
this was a full day conference that cost &amp;euro;10, I thought getting three short tutorials as well as five excellent
talks was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good value for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6896.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Happy developers&#34; title=&#34;Happy developers&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6883.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
alt=&#34;Interesting...&#34; title=&#34;Interesting...&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be remiss in talking about the conference if I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention the venue.  We were at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://espaciores.org/&#34;&gt;Espacio RES&lt;/a&gt;, which was pretty easy to get to, and a really nice, airy, comfortable
space&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/androidxtended#footnote2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
And they let us rearrange their whole place just for us. The only downside is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hold more people, which
is a shame, and the reason we had to host on two sites (I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on the other site as I stayed
at RES the whole day, but we&amp;rsquo;re very grateful to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitnami.com/&#34;&gt;Bitnami&lt;/a&gt; for lending us their offices as well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6831.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Collaboration&#34; title=&#34;Collaboration&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did I learn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://espaciores.org/&#34;&gt;Espacio RES&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice space that hopefully we can use more regularly for events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is possible to use Good Practices to write Android code, and Real Developers are doing so for Real Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are very talented and expert technical speakers in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to two conferences in Spain in
the last month, but as they were all in English I think it puts some people off presenting. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see Spanish
talent being showcased, it gives developers here good role models and shows that experts aren&amp;rsquo;t just from outside
Spain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sevilla has a very healthy tech scene with people more than happy to give up a Saturday to learn new things. In
fact, for some set of people, they prefer Saturdays to weekday
evenings&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/post/androidxtended#footnote3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I have a feeling I&amp;rsquo;m about to lose more weekends in the
future&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;People like Saturdays?&#34; title=&#34;People like 
 Saturdays?&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Xtended was a fantastic event, with great speakers and engaged attendees.  I loved how social
 everyone was during the breaks, how people were happy to chat and share stories, even though most of the attendees
 didn&amp;rsquo;t know each other beforehand. It was brilliantly organised, and although I did see how much work went into
 arranging it, you would never believe from how smoothly it went that this two-venue event was organised by just two
 guys. Well done &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/israkaos&#34;&gt;@IsraKaos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rgdav&#34;&gt;@RGDav&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://trishagee.github.io/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6927.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Drinks&#34; title=&#34;Drinks&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Although in my experience Android and &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; Java user groups and events tend not to
 overlap much - not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a function of the relationship between Google and Oracle or just because large cities like
 London tend to split groups along technology lines to keep group and event sizes manageable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The downside was there are not a lot of places nearby open for coffee at 8am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; This is completely alien to me as someone who built her career largely in London - you
 do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; host events on a Saturday, except for maybe the annual LJC Open Conference, because many people have a
 long commute into the city. Doing that 5 days a week is plenty, most people don&amp;rsquo;t want to do it on a Saturday as
 well. But they will give up a couple of hours in the evening, as it costs far less in time overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2014, Day One</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m at JavaOne again, and after only one day I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt stuff.  And, of course,
had a great time catching up with interesting people.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=10289&#34;&gt;Superpowered CI with Git - Sarah Goff-Dupont&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Continuous Integration we did at LMAX is quite different to what we do at MongoDB, and I was hoping to get some tips on better CI with
Git, especially given feature branches.  There was a good overview of development process using branch-per-feature,
 and a comment that it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible to do &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; CI in this sort of environment.  But there was pragmatic advice on how to manage
 the process and run automated builds in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The take-home point for me is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to investigate &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks&#34;&gt;git hooks&lt;/a&gt; to try and
  streamline our process and run some fast checks more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Sarah showed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hipchat.com&#34;&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt; in anger - I&amp;rsquo;ve now heard this mentioned enough that I&amp;rsquo;m going to look into it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2276&#34;&gt;Advanced Unit Testing with Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve [spoken before about Spock](&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/tags/spock/), and how much I love it.  The first section of this talk was a recap
of some of the basics, but the second part went on to some features I either previously ignored or wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of.  For example, in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt;, we do use annotations to denote slower-running tests so we can select which environments to run in,
but we&amp;rsquo;re not using Spock annotations for this.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more we could do with both custom annotations like our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/blob/3.0.x/util/src/main/category/Slow.java&#34;&gt;@Slow&lt;/a&gt; annotation,
Spock&amp;rsquo;s built in annotations like &lt;code&gt;@Issue&lt;/code&gt;, and some others which may not yet be in maven central like &lt;code&gt;@Requires&lt;/code&gt; for running
language-version tests (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/JavaLanguageSpec
.groovy&#34;&gt;e.g. Java 8 tests&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;@IgnoreRest&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also liked the example of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/OldExampleSpec.groovy&#34;&gt;checking the new value against an old
value&lt;/a&gt;,
I can totally see this being useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other bits and pieces in this talk I&amp;rsquo;d like to dig into in more detail that I think will be very useful for the Java Driver.
But even more importantly, I learnt how to zoom into my screen so I can use that in my own presentation. Pro presentation top tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you have even minor testing pains, it&amp;rsquo;s worth finding Ken&amp;rsquo;s talks on Spock, they&amp;rsquo;re great! And a source of inspiration for
better testing, as well as a sneaky way to understand why Groovy is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCP Awards and Party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But it&amp;rsquo;s not all work at these events.  For me, the highlight was the music at at the JCP Awards party.  Firstly,
we had an award-winning beat-box guy from the UK (sadly I don&amp;rsquo;t remember his name so I can&amp;rsquo;t link to his stuff).  An unusual choice for
an event like this, but it was a lot of fun. Then there was the live super-band, The Null Pointers, made up of JUG leaders from around the
world (including &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matkar&#34;&gt;@matkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/frankgreco&#34;&gt;@frankgreco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fguime&#34;&gt;@fguime&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit,
 I was a little concerned about this idea, but the guys were fantastic, and it was a lot of fun singing along to Free&amp;rsquo;s Alright Now and
 Radiohead&amp;rsquo;s Creep. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/openworld/appreciation-event/index.html&#34;&gt;Aerosmith&lt;/a&gt; is going to have to work hard to compete with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;and a quick plug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=1703&#34;&gt;main presentation is on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a keyword-tastic live demo of AngularJS, Java &amp;amp; MongoDB.  Something &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; goes wrong in
this presentation, so I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://doodle.com/fvrasw9vrpxyb9dm&#34;&gt;taking bets right now on what that will be&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could possibly go wrong? (GOTO Chicago)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, I was given the chance to chat a bit about the presentation I was giving,
which happens to be the same one I&amp;rsquo;m giving at a number of conferences this year (although of course I&amp;rsquo;m evolving it as I go along).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation leaves very little time for anything other than coding, as it&amp;rsquo;s quite challenging to create a full app in 50
minutes, so it was great to have the chance to talk about the motivations for the demo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/sZee7lRAUF4&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video of the actual talk is also available now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/kmVnhyWqozA&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning it doesn&amp;rsquo;t clearly show the screen, but it does improve.  You can see an earlier version from the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/demo-java-javascript-mongodb#anch110035&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding&lt;/a&gt; as well,
so if something&amp;rsquo;s not clear on one of the videos, hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s better in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/tree/goto-chicago&#34;&gt;code for the Chicago version is on Github&lt;/a&gt;,
and if you look through the history you can see how it builds up, the same as it does in the demo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
