<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Conference on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/conference/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2014, Day One</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/java_one_2014_day_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m at JavaOne again, and after only one day I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt stuff.  And, of course,
had a great time catching up with interesting people.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=10289&#34;&gt;Superpowered CI with Git - Sarah Goff-Dupont&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Continuous Integration we did at LMAX is quite different to what we do at MongoDB, and I was hoping to get some tips on better CI with
Git, especially given feature branches.  There was a good overview of development process using branch-per-feature,
 and a comment that it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible to do &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; CI in this sort of environment.  But there was pragmatic advice on how to manage
 the process and run automated builds in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The take-home point for me is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to investigate &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks&#34;&gt;git hooks&lt;/a&gt; to try and
  streamline our process and run some fast checks more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Sarah showed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hipchat.com&#34;&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt; in anger - I&amp;rsquo;ve now heard this mentioned enough that I&amp;rsquo;m going to look into it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2276&#34;&gt;Advanced Unit Testing with Spock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve [spoken before about Spock](&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/tags/spock/), and how much I love it.  The first section of this talk was a recap
of some of the basics, but the second part went on to some features I either previously ignored or wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of.  For example, in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/&#34;&gt;MongoDB Java Driver&lt;/a&gt;, we do use annotations to denote slower-running tests so we can select which environments to run in,
but we&amp;rsquo;re not using Spock annotations for this.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more we could do with both custom annotations like our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-java-driver/blob/3.0.x/util/src/main/category/Slow.java&#34;&gt;@Slow&lt;/a&gt; annotation,
Spock&amp;rsquo;s built in annotations like &lt;code&gt;@Issue&lt;/code&gt;, and some others which may not yet be in maven central like &lt;code&gt;@Requires&lt;/code&gt; for running
language-version tests (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/JavaLanguageSpec
.groovy&#34;&gt;e.g. Java 8 tests&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;@IgnoreRest&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also liked the example of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kensipe/spock-javaone2014/blob/master/test/com/example/OldExampleSpec.groovy&#34;&gt;checking the new value against an old
value&lt;/a&gt;,
I can totally see this being useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other bits and pieces in this talk I&amp;rsquo;d like to dig into in more detail that I think will be very useful for the Java Driver.
But even more importantly, I learnt how to zoom into my screen so I can use that in my own presentation. Pro presentation top tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you have even minor testing pains, it&amp;rsquo;s worth finding Ken&amp;rsquo;s talks on Spock, they&amp;rsquo;re great! And a source of inspiration for
better testing, as well as a sneaky way to understand why Groovy is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCP Awards and Party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But it&amp;rsquo;s not all work at these events.  For me, the highlight was the music at at the JCP Awards party.  Firstly,
we had an award-winning beat-box guy from the UK (sadly I don&amp;rsquo;t remember his name so I can&amp;rsquo;t link to his stuff).  An unusual choice for
an event like this, but it was a lot of fun. Then there was the live super-band, The Null Pointers, made up of JUG leaders from around the
world (including &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matkar&#34;&gt;@matkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/frankgreco&#34;&gt;@frankgreco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fguime&#34;&gt;@fguime&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit,
 I was a little concerned about this idea, but the guys were fantastic, and it was a lot of fun singing along to Free&amp;rsquo;s Alright Now and
 Radiohead&amp;rsquo;s Creep. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/openworld/appreciation-event/index.html&#34;&gt;Aerosmith&lt;/a&gt; is going to have to work hard to compete with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;and a quick plug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=1703&#34;&gt;main presentation is on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a keyword-tastic live demo of AngularJS, Java &amp;amp; MongoDB.  Something &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; goes wrong in
this presentation, so I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://doodle.com/fvrasw9vrpxyb9dm&#34;&gt;taking bets right now on what that will be&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could possibly go wrong? (GOTO Chicago)</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, I was given the chance to chat a bit about the presentation I was giving,
which happens to be the same one I&amp;rsquo;m giving at a number of conferences this year (although of course I&amp;rsquo;m evolving it as I go along).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation leaves very little time for anything other than coding, as it&amp;rsquo;s quite challenging to create a full app in 50
minutes, so it was great to have the chance to talk about the motivations for the demo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/sZee7lRAUF4&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video of the actual talk is also available now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/kmVnhyWqozA&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning it doesn&amp;rsquo;t clearly show the screen, but it does improve.  You can see an earlier version from the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/demo-java-javascript-mongodb#anch110035&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding&lt;/a&gt; as well,
so if something&amp;rsquo;s not clear on one of the videos, hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s better in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito/tree/goto-chicago&#34;&gt;code for the Chicago version is on Github&lt;/a&gt;,
and if you look through the history you can see how it builds up, the same as it does in the demo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
