<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Videos on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/videos/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS, HTML5, Groovy, Java and MongoDB All Together - What Could Possibly Go Wrong??</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/presentation/angularjs_html5_groovy_java_mongodb_wcpgw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving an evolving live demonstration of coding a Fully Buzz Word Compliant,
mobile-friendly web application.  The aim of the demo is to show, via a real-world application rather than snippets or a toy example,
where these popular technologies sit in your archtecture, and how they interact with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact code I present has changed a bit over time, but the vJUG has a pretty recent version of the demo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/MRrSAkEAnZQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/cafelito&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;ll see there are a number of different branches for the
different versions I&amp;rsquo;ve presented. The current one is the JavaOne version.  With all the branches,
the commits correspond to the user stories in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/i-want-coffeejavaone&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;,
so you can get a feel for how the code builds up throughout the demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk has been videod several times, some of these videos aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet, but there are videos of older versions of this talk -
these older versions use a different library to talk to MongoDB and (I hope) you&amp;rsquo;ll see that the most recent code is even simpler than
these initial demos.  If more videos become available I&amp;rsquo;ll add them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago, May 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/demo-java-javascript-mongodb&#34;&gt;Joy of Coding, March 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a full list of this and all my presentations, see &lt;a href=&#34;presentation/public_appearances/&#34;&gt;Public Appearances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
