<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>...but most of all, it&#39;s fun</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/most_of_all_its_fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/most_of_all_its_fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I loved this analogy: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@nkkl/ride-like-a-girl-1d5524e25d3a&#34;&gt;Cycling is awfully similar to being a woman&lt;/a&gt;.
It nicely describes how it feels to be marginalised and not quite &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo;. But there are some things that I&amp;rsquo;d like to
add:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New 3.0 Java Driver for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/resources/the_new_30_java_driver_for_mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/resources/the_new_30_java_driver_for_mongodb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Information related to the currently-ongoing effort to redesign the Java driver for MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Do Something</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/resources/just_do_something/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/resources/just_do_something/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I constantly talk about in my how-to-get-more-women-into-technology talks, we, the developers, the people who do this job,
need to get out there and tell people what&amp;rsquo;s so great about what we do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 8 - Introduction to Lambdas Article</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/java_8__introduction_to_lambdas_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/java_8__introduction_to_lambdas_article/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s Java Magazine features an article by me, Ben Evans and Martijn Verburg about the new lambdas&amp;nbsp;coming in Java 8.
The aim of the article is to give an overview to normal, human Java developers, who don&amp;rsquo;t need to know the theory behind what they are or how they work under the covers, but want to know how to use them when they get the shiny new version of Java next year (or even get ahead of the curve and try them now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Links</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/resources/performance_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/resources/performance_resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hastily thrown-together list of some of the places to get more information on how to write performant code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on events</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/update_on_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/update_on_events/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to say I was interviewed for another podcast, again to talk about all-female events. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s only a short one and there&amp;rsquo;s probably not much in there that I haven&amp;rsquo;t said before, either on here or in person.
From the 21st May, I&amp;rsquo;m at GOTO, both Copenhagen and Amsterdam. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about code &amp;amp; the Disruptor, thank goodness, and will be trying not to rant about the subject of women in technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview by the Oracle Technology Network at Devoxx</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx/</guid>
      <description>Tori Wieldt from the Oracle Technology Network interviewed me at Devoxx. &amp;nbsp;Because I was there to be on the Why We Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Target Women panel, the interview is just another platform for me to air my views on this subject again. 
Yes, I am actually wearing pink&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike and I debut our new Disruptor presentation</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/mike_and_i_debut_our_new_disruptor_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/mike_and_i_debut_our_new_disruptor_presentation/</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday&amp;nbsp;Mike and I unveiled our brand shiny new presentation: Understanding the Disruptor, a Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Hardcore Concurrency. &amp;nbsp;This was a preview of the talk we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing at JAX London on the 2nd November.
A video of the session is available, as are the slides. &amp;nbsp;I promise not to say &amp;ldquo;so&amp;rdquo; anywhere near as many times when I repeat my performance at JAX (is there anything more painful than watching yourself on video?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chance to see some of my actual code (even if it is C#)</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/a_chance_to_see_some_of_my_actual_code_even_if_it_is_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/a_chance_to_see_some_of_my_actual_code_even_if_it_is_c/</guid>
      <description>Remember I posted about having to write .NET?
Well, the code and the tutorial are available for you, my lucky readers, to rip to pieces view.
I am not the only person responsible for this code though, so be kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting around a bit</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_around_a_bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/getting_around_a_bit/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m honoured to now be listed on three aggregated blog feeds:
The new and somewhat embryonic blogs.lmax.com.The London Java Community Aggrity.ThoughtWorks Alumni, along with a whole host of distinguished names.The pressure&amp;rsquo;s on to try and write useful stuff. &amp;nbsp;Oh OK, I&amp;rsquo;ll settle for &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments on representations of our industry</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/comments_on_representations_of_our_industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/comments_on_representations_of_our_industry/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;nbsp;have not (yet) seen the presentation this post is referring to.&amp;nbsp; But I think many of the comments Ted makes are very valid, and our industry as a whole should occasionally stop and think.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Ted speak at QCon, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of time for his comments ever since.
I&amp;rsquo;m aware that this blog is rapidly filling with comments about gender and perceptions and people-y stuff, when I originally wanted it to be a purely technical blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why changing jobs frequently is not necessarily a bad thing...</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/why_changing_jobs_frequently_is_not_necessarily_a_bad_thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/why_changing_jobs_frequently_is_not_necessarily_a_bad_thing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s actually a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum but...</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/scrum_but/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/scrum_but/</guid>
      <description>Having experience Flaccid Scrum, I find this article interesting, and agree with most of it.
I&amp;rsquo;d also like to add though, that if you do the scrum practices&amp;nbsp;(story cards, stand ups, retrospectives, etc) but don&amp;rsquo;t buy into the fundamental principals, you will not succeed.&amp;nbsp; And that means everyone on the team, not just the people in charge. &amp;nbsp;In particular, if the team is not empowered, is not committing to the estimates and the iteration plan in its heart, and and does not trust, then you are probably better off using traditional processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/why_to_start_a_startup_in_a_bad_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/why_to_start_a_startup_in_a_bad_economy/</guid>
      <description>Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Stereotyping</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/gender_stereotyping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/gender_stereotyping/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very interested in the subject of gender stereotyping, which probably isn&amp;rsquo;t surprising as I&amp;rsquo;m a girl in a predominantly male industry.&amp;nbsp; And I&amp;nbsp;like cars, and&amp;nbsp;sports, and get irritated if people assume I&amp;rsquo;m not &amp;quot;allowed&amp;quot; to be interested in these things.
Far from being discriminated against, however, I&amp;nbsp;find many people ask me why there aren&amp;rsquo;t more women in the industry and what can be done to encourage girls into IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics and Incentives.</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/metrics_and_incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/metrics_and_incentives/</guid>
      <description>This&amp;nbsp;is a great example of what&amp;nbsp;happens when you try to incentivise intelligent people on very simple metrics.
They cheat.
This was well described in Freakonomics, and something Mr On Software bangs on about regularly.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s clear that there isn&amp;rsquo;t really a good answer to the problem - actually that&amp;rsquo;s not true.&amp;nbsp; The answer to the problem is to have everyone working in a job they are happy in and proud of, one where they are intrinsically motivated, and give them enough information to allow them to make the correct calls when it comes to prioritising work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Infection Growing</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/agile_infection_growing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/agile_infection_growing/</guid>
      <description>This is a bloody good idea.
It builds upon my own Virgoen tendancies to write lists and tick things off, but what the list model lacks is the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; state. Plus occasionally my lists get confused. See today&amp;rsquo;s notebook page:ThursdayFix bugs in Test DirectorMerge fixes upDo buildMerge downRead terms of contractE-mail solicitorGo to Robert DyasOrder DAB RadioFinish business analysis docsCarry on with QCon note consolidationHow do I know which ones I&amp;rsquo;ve started?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon: Blogger&#39;s Summary</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_bloggers_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/qcon_bloggers_summary/</guid>
      <description>I might be too late in writing my own thoughts on QCon, but a bunch of other people have done a pretty good job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certifiction</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/certifiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/certifiction/</guid>
      <description>From spellfecker&amp;nbsp;today:Certifiction (n.) : a professional endorsement which states only that the holder had the money to pay for the exam.&amp;hellip;which reminded me of this debate, particularly the first comment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing the Agile froth...</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/continuing_the_agile_froth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/continuing_the_agile_froth/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;there are a number of points in this interview with Paul Oldfield which are interesting to consider when thinking about &amp;ldquo;doing Agile right&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; It seems to be compatible with my &amp;ldquo;people over process&amp;rdquo; view - I&amp;rsquo;m not stating that having good people negates the need for any form of process or discipline, I have seen that this is simply not the case.&amp;nbsp; I do however think that agile techniques in particular rely heavily upon the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; people / team, for some nebulous definition of&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>