<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ljc on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/ljc/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAX London &amp; MongoDB Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__mongodb_tutorial</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__mongodb_tutorial</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous years, JAX London would have been an easy, local conference to go to. This time it took me most of Sunday to get
there, and not because of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://metro.co.uk/2013/10/27/its-ok-to-take-the-morning-off-work-if-storm-hits-michael-fish-says-so-4162862/&#34;&gt;Super Storm&lt;/a&gt;.  Still, that gave me the day to finish off the tutorial I was running there on
Monday morning. Not that I would be so unprofessional as to leave preparing things until the last minute,
oh no&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as in previous years, the main benefit of this conference for me was meeting most of the usual suspects from the London Java
Community. For example, presenting were: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/andy-piper&#34;&gt;Andy Piper&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/barry-cranford&#34;&gt;Barry Cranford&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/james-gough&#34;&gt;Jim
Gough&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/peter-lawrey&#34;&gt;Peter Lawrey&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon
.com/speakers/sandro-mancuso&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/simon-maple&#34;&gt;Simon Maple&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/martijn-verburg&#34;&gt;Martijn Verburg&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/john-oliver&#34;&gt;John
Oliver&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/john-stevenson&#34;&gt;John Stevenson&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon
.com/speakers/richard-warburton&#34;&gt;Richard Warburton&lt;/a&gt;. The Community Night in particular also drew a lot of LJC members (including some
 first-timers) to JAX, and it was a really good &amp;ldquo;networking opportunity&amp;rdquo; (i.e. chance to have free drinks,
 catch up with friends and make new ones). I really enjoyed hanging out with everyone at JAX this year,
 I was tempted to write the names of everyone I spoke to and had fun with because it really made my conference,
 but I think that would make a very boring blog post. But if I spoke to you at JAX, you made my journey from Spain worthwhile,
 thank you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As well as the LJC-types, there were some other really big name speakers too,
 including MongoDB&amp;rsquo;s Chairman &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/speakers/dwight-merriman&#34;&gt;Dwight Merriman&lt;/a&gt;. Highlights for me
 were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Sipe&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spockframework.org/&#34;&gt;Spock&lt;/a&gt; talk. I saw this at GeeCON and that&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;/tags/spock/&#34;&gt;I started using
Spock&lt;/a&gt; to test the MongoDB Java driver, but it was great to see it again and pick up some extra tips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ted Neward&amp;rsquo;s talk at the community night about being a CTO at a startup. It was really interesting,
and nice to see a realistic view of the difficulties of that role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Governor&amp;rsquo;s keynote on how Java got its Mojo back. I like seeing facts and figures to back up a viewpoint,
and as you&amp;rsquo;d expect from the founder of an analyst firm, this talk was full of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As James mentioned during his talk, the audience at JAX was, as in previous years, somewhat passive. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why,
 as around 50% of the audience came from outside the UK so we can&amp;rsquo;t even blame English reticence. And in a conference full of
 outspoken LJC-types, it seems an odd thing to have an unresponsive audience. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the venue,
 the main hall in particular seems to lend itself to sitting quietly in the audience and expecting to be entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented four times at JAX, because, well, on home turf one ends up doing more than one expects.
 - Firstly, a tutorial on the new Java driver for MongoDB (more on this later);
 - Secondly, a clinic for novice speakers. This was a lot of fun, and I think it was useful for everyone. I&amp;rsquo;d love to run
 this again (I probably will at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ljcopenconference/&#34;&gt;LJC Open Conference&lt;/a&gt;). The aim
 is to give new speakers confidence, not focus on details like building a slide deck.
 - Thirdly, the third time out for my &amp;ldquo;Design is a Process, not a Document&amp;rdquo; presentation. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively interactive
 presentation, which I don&amp;rsquo;t think worked so well at JAX, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fun presentation to give.
 - Finally, not only did I get roped into being on the panel for &amp;ldquo;How to start a community&amp;rdquo; at the community night, I ended up, somehow,
  moderating it. That was fun, it was the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been a moderator, it&amp;rsquo;s a role I usually avoid as moderators ought to
  limit the amount of talking they do, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound fun to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorial materials are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trishagee/mongodb-java-tutorial&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
provided a lot of guidance on how to get started online, but the exercises are there, and the slides which present the concepts and
suggest the order to tackle the tests in. If people use these materials, please feel free to give me feedback on them,
but be nice - they were designed for an in-person tutorial, not an online one. But it is a good way to get a feel for the new
MongoDB Java API (in its current, unfinished, state).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, JAX London - great speakers, and a good conference to meet not only Londoners, but a lot of international people too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LJC Open Conference 2012</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/ljc_open_conference_2012</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/ljc_open_conference_2012</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday I had the pleasure of being part of the 5th &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/events/89353112/&#34;&gt;London Java Community Open Conference&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;This is a great event to end the conference season on - it made me feel good about being part of the LJC, and &amp;nbsp;got me excited about the prospects for 2013.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The fantastic thing about an open conference is that a) you don&amp;rsquo;t have to prepare like mad for it and b) the short sessions and wide variety of subjects mean that you learn stuff you didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Given how much I&amp;rsquo;ve been presenting lately, and with the conferences piling on top of each other back-to-back leaving little time for preparation, I had decided not to speak at the open conference, but to sit and learn for a change - it&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity for new speakers to present for a start. &amp;nbsp;But that resolution lasted all of 3.54 milliseconds. &amp;nbsp;After all, if people don&amp;rsquo;t like the sessions I propose, they won&amp;rsquo;t come, so I lose nothing by suggesting some.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KsBmTFUz6Q8/ULNWmfp96wI/AAAAAAAALVY/LCj0GtWn5iA/s1600/highres_182314542.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;285&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KsBmTFUz6Q8/ULNWmfp96wI/AAAAAAAALVY/LCj0GtWn5iA/s320/highres_182314542.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Photo by Ged Byrne&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;First up, it was a very great honour to be giving my very first Keynote. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kittylyst&#34;&gt;Ben Evans&lt;/a&gt; and I presented on the State of Java - a summary of this last year from the point of view of our community and globally, and a view to next year. &amp;nbsp;I know we&amp;rsquo;ve had an incredible year as the LJC, it was really satisfying to be able to summarise this for everyone there, to present what we&amp;rsquo;ve achieved locally and globally. &amp;nbsp;And looking forward to the future, there&amp;rsquo;s so much more we can do as individuals trying to improve our skills (especially with Java 8 due), as a London-focussed community (with our own events, our sister communities, and with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.com/display/UK13/Home&#34;&gt;Devoxx UK&lt;/a&gt;), and globally (with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jcp.org/en/home/index&#34;&gt;JCP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/&#34;&gt;OpenJDK&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next, I was roped into a Java Performance panel, with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jclarity.com/&#34;&gt;JClarity&lt;/a&gt; guys (Ben, Richard and John). &amp;nbsp;I was surprised to see that not many in the audience were working on low latency systems - in London you&amp;rsquo;ll frequently find a room full of Java developers who are all working in finance on things that have specific performance requirements. &amp;nbsp;It was good that we had a this variety of developers, because it meant we covered a much broader range of subjects, and could discuss what to think about and where to get started when you&amp;rsquo;re considering your non-functional requirements. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Immediately after that I was on &lt;i&gt;another&lt;/i&gt; panel, with some of the same suspects, talking about the LJC&amp;rsquo;s involvement in the Java Community Process and the Open JDK. &amp;nbsp;I really like these sessions because it&amp;rsquo;s easy for us, who are dealing with these things at least on a weekly basis, to forget that most of our members aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with either of these two things. &amp;nbsp;What&amp;rsquo;s encouraging though is that after just a short introduction to what they are and how we can impact them, most people want to be involved in some way. &amp;nbsp;The hack days are particularly appealing to developers (not surprising). &amp;nbsp;Although we&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of very successful hack days, we still need to work out a way to scale them - how do we attract more people? &amp;nbsp;How do we make the best use of their time? &amp;nbsp;In particular, we need to work out how to cater for people with different timetables (weekends vs evenings vs week days), and how to handle the split between beginners and those who have already been to at least one hack day. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m excited about what we&amp;rsquo;ve achieved so far with the hack days, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s so much more that can be done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-I3N9vqPNKi4/ULNhpWcXKkI/AAAAAAAALVs/h3s24OgDDzY/s1600/2012-11-24+15.22.04.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-I3N9vqPNKi4/ULNhpWcXKkI/AAAAAAAALVs/h3s24OgDDzY/s320/2012-11-24+15.22.04.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t tell from this photo, but there were girls this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Over lunch there was a series of lightning talks. &amp;nbsp;I really like the way the lightning talks are presented to everyone in the conference. &amp;nbsp;I like the variety of topics, and I like that it&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy for a new speaker to give a 5 minute talk, with as little or as much preparation as they want. &amp;nbsp;The one I remember most was on software for elections from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/flor3scu&#34;&gt;Alex Florescu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- I thought that looked like an interesting (and difficult!) business domain, which needs novel solutions in order to get acceptance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next up, I gave an intro to NoSQL &amp;nbsp;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/11/devoxx-2012_22.html&#34;&gt;Devoxx&lt;/a&gt;, it was clear that while a lot of developers have heard of the NoSQL movement, and of databases like MongoDB, it&amp;rsquo;s not clear to them why you&amp;rsquo;d chose these over traditional databases. Which is a relief to me, because that&amp;rsquo;s exactly where I was three months ago. &amp;nbsp;So this was a really quick (30 minute) overview of the different flavours of NoSQL, what they&amp;rsquo;re good for and why you might pick one over another. &amp;nbsp;Obviously there was a focus on MongoDB, since this is the one I know most about, but I also covered the strengths of some of the others. &amp;nbsp;I really enjoyed giving this session - the audience was perfect for the topic, the questions were intelligent and drove the direction of the discussion, and I had a number of positive comments from people who felt like they had learnt something.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I gave another session which was a recap of the JavaOne and Devoxx &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/javaone-problem-with-women-technical.html&#34;&gt;Problem with Women&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; talk, but even shorter. &amp;nbsp;The fantastic thing about this was the energy from the people in the room - these guys like what they do and they&amp;rsquo;re keen to tell other people how great it is to work as a developer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-TlnmMCGMwU8/ULNwvqNx6fI/AAAAAAAALWE/2R3nLfmcLzg/s1600/2012-11-24+13.06.00.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-TlnmMCGMwU8/ULNwvqNx6fI/AAAAAAAALWE/2R3nLfmcLzg/s320/2012-11-24+13.06.00.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Finally, I managed to actually attend a couple of talks too. &amp;nbsp;Barry led &amp;ldquo;Why is technical recruitment so broken?&amp;rdquo;, and we had some interesting discussions around the problems employers and developers face, in trying to get the right people into the right roles. &amp;nbsp;Clearly there is no easy solution, and there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a role for recruitment agents of all kinds in this space, but it would be awesome if we stop floundering around in the dark and actually be able to match the right people to the right jobs more easily. &amp;nbsp;In seems to me that there is a huge educational piece here: developers can find resources around &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2011/12/how-to-make-your-cv-not-suck.html&#34;&gt;how to write their CVs&lt;/a&gt;, how to stand out from the crowd, how to network to increase their chances of finding a good job, but they need to know to start looking for these resources. &amp;nbsp;Worse, though, is the problem of the employers - if you&amp;rsquo;re a big company you have a non-technical HR department standing between the team needing a developer and the candidates themselves, and smaller companies don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to invest in the hiring process, or going out and networking to meet people at things like LJC events. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s a tough problem, and one I&amp;rsquo;m extremely interested in. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://qconlondon.com/london-2013/tracks/show_track.jsp?trackOID=766&#34;&gt;Attracting Great People&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; track I&amp;rsquo;m running at QCon London will look at some of these issues, and give some advice from those who are doing a good job.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The last session was an exploration of all that is wrong with Agile, led by Ged Byrne. &amp;nbsp;It was an interesting discussion, the only disappointing thing about it was that everyone agreed with each other! &amp;nbsp;Certifications Are Meaningless; external Agile coaches and consultants aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily invested in improving your business; a formal Agile process is really defeating the point; and, most importantly, let&amp;rsquo;s try to remember the original &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemanifesto.org/&#34;&gt;agile manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In summary, it was a really great day! &amp;nbsp;I enjoyed it as much as I enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2011/11/london-java-community-open-conference.html&#34;&gt;last year&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, for many of the same reasons - we have a fantastic community, it&amp;rsquo;s a great event for meeting people, it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant for encouraging new speakers, and if you are speaking you get much better feedback than you do at the large events, because you can involve your audience directly and give them what they really want. &amp;nbsp;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe how much I personally have achieved since my first solo talk at the LJC Open Conference last year, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what the next year holds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewblack/sets/72157632093043391/&#34;&gt;More photos&lt;/a&gt; from Andrew Black)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NightHacking Tour: The LJC</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_tour_the_ljc</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/nighthacking_tour_the_ljc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the same day &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/10/interview-and-hacking-session-with.html&#34;&gt;Stephen Chin came to see me&lt;/a&gt; at the 10gen offices, we also ran a NightHacking session in the evening with the London Java Community. &amp;nbsp;Not many people turned up (maybe I need to work on my signage to the office?) but it was a great session. In fact, having less people meant we could all be involved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Expect &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;s and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/overview/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/f2a9XvZNq0o&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAX London 2012</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london_2012</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london_2012</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seemed like a quiet conference this year. &amp;nbsp;Not really sure why, maybe it was the layout of the massive (and extremely dark) main room; maybe it was the awkward L-shape of the communal space; or maybe this year people were more interested in listening to the (really very good) sessions rather than participating or meeting other people. &amp;nbsp;Whatever the reason, it felt quiet and almost low-key.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Performance seemed pretty high on the agenda, as you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a London conference, with a number of things on offer:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A great keynote from &lt;a href=&#34;http://kirk.blog-city.com/&#34;&gt;Kirk Pepperdine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karianna&#34;&gt;Martijn Verburg&lt;/a&gt;, covering a massive range of things to care about when thinking about performance on the first night&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A high-level talk about Java Performance from yours truly (which I may run again for the LJC if there&amp;rsquo;s interest, but it&amp;rsquo;s more likely to be a one-off)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A deep dive into writing lock-free coding by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bad-concurrency.blogspot.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Mike Barker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;And a talk from Kirk exploring your GC logs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It was great to see a number of LJC regulars presenting, especially as my own schedule has been so crazy I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen many of them for a long time. &amp;nbsp;So I missed sessions from &lt;a href=&#34;http://JAxlondon.com/2012/speaker/&#34;&gt;Bruce, John, Sandro, Russell, James &amp;amp; Richard&lt;/a&gt;, but I heard good things about the sessions and was really pleased to chat to all of them.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The highlight of the conference for me though was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.briangoetz.com/&#34;&gt;Brian Goetz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s keynote and subsequent session on &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/lambda/&#34;&gt;lambdas&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into lambdas because I think it&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting addition to the language and I&amp;rsquo;ve heard a lot of noise about them. &amp;nbsp;What I thought was most interesting about Brian&amp;rsquo;s talks though was less the information on what they were and how to use them, and more the challenges that face language designers when they have a language which is used by 10 million developers and has been going for nearly 20 years. &amp;nbsp;Ouch. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing they get anything done, let alone something like lambdas which the language was never designed to support.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In keeping with the new job, I went to a few sessions on the Big Data Con - frankly an unfortunate name I feel. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rit&#34;&gt;Brendan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Mongo &amp;amp; JVM talk was useful, especially given that I might actually be presenting that at some point. &amp;nbsp;What I&amp;rsquo;d love to see though is a more interesting story around the Java driver. &amp;nbsp;It seems people believe the Java driver needs a little love.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The other interesting NoSql talk was from &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/tlberglund&#34;&gt;Tim Berglund&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s NoSql Smackdown, which was a really great way of highlighting that the NoSql databases are not all solving the same types of problems. &amp;nbsp;The room was packed and the questions were intelligent, so it seems there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of interest in this kind of introduction to the technology.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lessons learned:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commuting through Victoria Station sucks. &amp;nbsp;I knew this last year but it&amp;rsquo;s just got worse.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The iPad + stylus combo is not as precise as the graphics tablet, so I&amp;rsquo;m probably going back to that for illustrations. &amp;nbsp;But I&amp;rsquo;d still love to do free-drawing with the iPad on the projector at some point.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not everyone can follow the deep-dive tech talks, but they still prefer them to introductory talks, maybe because they feel like they&amp;rsquo;re learning something (well, that&amp;rsquo;s my opinion).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I took practically no photos because I kept forgetting I had my camera. &amp;nbsp;I think it&amp;rsquo;s the weird subterranean effect of the hotel basement. &amp;nbsp;Either that or I&amp;rsquo;ve turned into a conference zombie - not an unlikely suggestion. &amp;nbsp;And I&amp;rsquo;ve still got Devoxx round the corner&amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: User Group Sunday</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_user_group_sunday</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4uvOXlKEyfE/UGnku_oqLLI/AAAAAAAALK0/rdugE0GC4nY/s1600/DSC_0295.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4uvOXlKEyfE/UGnku_oqLLI/AAAAAAAALK0/rdugE0GC4nY/s640/DSC_0295.JPG&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well this is exciting! &amp;nbsp;JavaOne 2011 is the first conference I spoke at, so this the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve covered the same conference two years running. &amp;nbsp;I think.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very nice to be back at JavaOne. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2011/10/javaone-2011-roundup.html&#34;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;it was my first opportunity to meet so many people - the guys at Oracle who work really hard to make sure Java has its own identity; the JUG Leaders and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jduchess.org/&#34;&gt;Duchess&lt;/a&gt; folk; the JCP EC committee members; and loads of people who live and work in the area who I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally get a chance to speak to in person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;m here with several other&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;people, and it&amp;rsquo;s great to be a member of the Alumni, to have the privilege of showing other guys around and introducing people to each other. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s nice to run into people I met here for the first time last year, some of whom I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to see at other events this year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, Sunday, is an interesting day. &amp;nbsp;The focus is on community, so I get to hear what other JUGs are doing, some of their pain points, and learn some of the things they&amp;rsquo;re doing that maybe we should think about. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lm0BeJifdNs/UGnYYDgNbVI/AAAAAAAALKI/rWANg1dfTks/s1600/DSC_0279.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;212&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lm0BeJifdNs/UGnYYDgNbVI/AAAAAAAALKI/rWANg1dfTks/s320/DSC_0279.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The day started well, with Jim and Richard de-mystifying the business and technology&amp;nbsp;terminology&amp;nbsp;we&amp;rsquo;re bound to come across at this conference. &amp;nbsp;8:15am is a really harsh time to have to do your first presentation, but it had a good turnout and was a great way to kick off the conference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;I followed this with a talk about why you would open source&amp;nbsp;your secrets, a short presentation detailing the benefits to your business of opening up parts of your codebase. &amp;nbsp;It went better than expected, given my voice has all but disappeared due to a stupid cold and plane travel and jet lag (and noisy bars). &amp;nbsp;I had contingency plans on how to present via typing or drawing on my iPad, but in the end I managed even despite the microphone not being turned on. &amp;nbsp;Doh.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-y3i2xpoKxdM/UGnapgQNiiI/AAAAAAAALKQ/SRkBw51f9Kk/s1600/DSC_0289.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-y3i2xpoKxdM/UGnapgQNiiI/AAAAAAAALKQ/SRkBw51f9Kk/s400/DSC_0289.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There were a series of presentations on how to make your JUG successful and how to run Adopt a JSR/OpenJDK programmes in your user group, before &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kittylyst&#34;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt; and I had to dash off to the public EC meeting. &amp;nbsp;This was not as well-attended as last year, but it meant that I had a chance to talk to all the EC members, and to drink more free champagne than one really ought to in the afternoon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-j-qDgQoK7EQ/UGncAE5vqYI/AAAAAAAALKY/F6R2jOURWjc/s1600/DSC_0291.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-j-qDgQoK7EQ/UGncAE5vqYI/AAAAAAAALKY/F6R2jOURWjc/s320/DSC_0291.JPG&#34; width=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Next on the packed schedule was a trip to yet another location (seriously, that&amp;rsquo;s 4 different locations just on Sunday) for the keynotes. &amp;nbsp;Note: next time I say &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not far, let&amp;rsquo;s walk&amp;rdquo; in San Francisco, hit me with sticks. &amp;nbsp;That&amp;rsquo;s the second time in as many days I&amp;rsquo;ve been hit with a vertical distance that was further than the horizontal. &amp;nbsp;At least this time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t wheeling my luggage up the hill like I was on Friday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The keynotes were definitely better than last year. &amp;nbsp;I really enjoyed how the technical keynote put the shiny new stuff into an everyday context - seeing JavaFX running on all the platforms, including embedded, and seeing lambdas used in anger, was really engaging. &amp;nbsp;In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s much more likely to get &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; developers using these things. &amp;nbsp;I particularly enjoyed the interplay between Mark Reinhold and Brian Goetz, it&amp;rsquo;s great to see people like that so passionate about what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, it really humanizes them and their projects.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ODxw1aQyY-E/UGnlEk2QI4I/AAAAAAAALK8/DLZYaOE33kI/s1600/DSC_0311.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ODxw1aQyY-E/UGnlEk2QI4I/AAAAAAAALK8/DLZYaOE33kI/s320/DSC_0311.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The last trip of the day was back down the hill to one of the many parties scheduled this week. &amp;nbsp;Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not in every party that you get given an award, so this was particularly sweet - the London Java Community has been honoured with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.java.net/dukeschoice&#34;&gt;Duke&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;This is the first year a community has won a &amp;ldquo;Dukey&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to be part of a group of people who are actively contributing to the language I work with daily, and to be recognised for this. &amp;nbsp;So yes, I was on stage getting an award again. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s addictive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, a really great kick off to this year&amp;rsquo;s JavaOne, and I&amp;rsquo;m back at the apartment well before my coach (well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://uber.com/invite/w2rk7&#34;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt;) turns into a pumpkin and resting my voice in time for my Disruptor presentation tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nkfHDUEb_qU/UGnlcHCHk-I/AAAAAAAALLE/gCqr9CtoGk4/s1600/DSC_0316.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nkfHDUEb_qU/UGnlcHCHk-I/AAAAAAAALLE/gCqr9CtoGk4/s640/DSC_0316.JPG&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed at GOTO Copenhagen</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_goto_copenhagen</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_goto_copenhagen</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was interviewed at GOTO Copenhagen, about Java, the Disruptor, the Graduate Developer Community &amp;amp; London Java Community, and a whole host of other things. &amp;nbsp;So to make up for the lack of blogging this month, here it is:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/0OcczjVXQQc&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The birth of a new community</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/the_birth_of_a_new_community</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topping off my mini-tour at the end of May, I was invited to Rotterdam to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://010dev.nl/post/social-tech-event-the-disruptor-and-the-perfect-programmer&#34;&gt;present to a brand new community&lt;/a&gt; of developers. &amp;nbsp;I was really interested in attending because my experience with user groups is pretty much limited to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;, and I knew this would be different due to being a) across a wider range of technologies and b) shiny and new.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was hosted (rather awesomely) in a brewery, and until then I&amp;rsquo;d never given a presentation in a pub. &amp;nbsp;Frankly it&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m keen to do more of. &amp;nbsp;Due to a total technology fail on the part of all of us, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the projector working with any of the various laptops. &amp;nbsp;However, with 30-odd techies, free wireless and slides &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/concurrent-programming-using-the-disruptor-copenhagen&#34;&gt;available on Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;, we managed a novel and collaborative presentation approach, with people clustered around the laptops with the largest screens, and someone at each one&amp;nbsp;valiantly&amp;nbsp;keeping up with my quick pace through over 100 slides of stick-men drawings (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.objectify.be/wordpress/?p=488&#34;&gt;a review of the evening is available&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I really enjoyed it, it was quite a change of pace from the conferences - my first attempt at presenting after imbibing probably a little toooo much wine, and a much more intimate venue which encouraged a lot of questions and discussion. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s actually a format that worked, and maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a way to get it to work even more smoothly, if the slides on all the laptops were synchronised, and there was some way for me to gesture wildly at the appropriate parts of the slides like I do when I&amp;rsquo;m on stage. &amp;nbsp;Hmmm, maybe that&amp;rsquo;s actually a webcast now I think about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I had an excellent time, thanks to the hospitality of the rather awesome Rotterdam-ians. &amp;nbsp;What I found fascinating &amp;nbsp;- as well as the venue and the novel presenting style - is the formation of a group of people with broadly similar interests. &amp;nbsp;One of the great strengths of a place like London is its size - you will find a number of people here with&amp;nbsp;interests&amp;nbsp;like yours, and sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; make it ridiculously easy to find them. &amp;nbsp;One of the weaknesses of London, however, is its size - there are so many people you could attract that you end up narrowing your search field. &amp;nbsp;You pick a very specific technology, a tiny geographical area, a single interest, to build a community around.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking for a while it would be nice to have a community of people who aren&amp;rsquo;t all the same, who share overlapping but different passions. &amp;nbsp;But how do you create something like that? &amp;nbsp;You need a single thing to draw those people together, otherwise they&amp;rsquo;ll never find each other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In smaller cities the geography limits the numbers, so you can have a broader range of interests represented. &amp;nbsp;In London, I can see something as (relatively) specific as a Java User Group becoming even more specific. &amp;nbsp;With nearly 2500 members, you could easily spin off Java-for-banking, Java-for-gaming, Java-in-west-London-zone-2 etc etc. &amp;nbsp;In fact, we&amp;rsquo;ve already spawned off a number of groups like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/grad-dc/&#34;&gt;Graduate Developer Community&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/&#34;&gt;London Scala Users&amp;rsquo; Group&lt;/a&gt; and so forth. &amp;nbsp;With nearly 2500 members, you cannot possibly meet them all, you can&amp;rsquo;t even get a feel for what everyone&amp;rsquo;s into. &amp;nbsp;How do you get the intimacy from a smaller user group without narrowing the scope so much that all of you might as well be clones? &amp;nbsp;The awesome thing about user groups is coming across new ideas, seeing solutions to problems you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know existed, hearing about things people are working on that never occurred to you. &amp;nbsp;For that, you need diversity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And one of the nice things about a city as large as London is you get plenty of diversity. &amp;nbsp;But how do you pull together that diversity? &amp;nbsp;How do you create a group that is diverse, when by necessity you need something central for those people to gravitate towards? &amp;nbsp;And if the diversity creates a large group, how do you create intimacy and feel personally involved, the stuff that comes for free if you belong to a smaller group where you know everyone?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In Rotterdam, at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.co.uk/2012/04/in-which-i-defend-male-species-at-all.html&#34;&gt;Girl Geek meetup&lt;/a&gt;, I saw the advantage of using something other than a specific technology to gather together a group of interesting people - you get a wider range of experiences and passions. &amp;nbsp;How you can achieve this without using&amp;nbsp;geography&amp;nbsp;or genetics to select your&amp;nbsp;participants?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is it even possible to build a community when your goal is diversity?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Disruptor Presentation Unveiled to the LJC!</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/new_disruptor_presentation_unveiled_to_the_ljc</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/new_disruptor_presentation_unveiled_to_the_ljc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I presented my new &amp;ldquo;User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Disruptor&amp;rdquo; talk to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://londonjavacommunity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Since it was very kindly hosted at Skillsmatter, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://skillsmatter.com/podcast/home/the-disruptor/js-3798&#34;&gt;video of the presentation&lt;/a&gt; available, and the slides are below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;width:425px&#34; id=&#34;__ss_12091737&#34;&gt; &lt;strong style=&#34;display:block;margin:12px 0 4px&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/a-users-guide-to-the-disruptor&#34; title=&#34;Concurrent Programming Using the Disruptor&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Concurrent Programming Using the Disruptor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/12091737&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;padding:5px 0 12px&#34;&gt; View more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trisha Gee&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The presentation is a little different to the ones we&amp;rsquo;ve done before. &amp;nbsp;Previously we&amp;rsquo;ve gone into how it works and why it&amp;rsquo;s fast. &amp;nbsp;This time I wanted to step back a little from the internals and show how real developers might actually use it. &amp;nbsp;The example is somewhat contrived, but the idea is to give some hints on how to break your problem down into something that will work with a Disruptor at the heart of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I thought the event went really well. &amp;nbsp;It was a tiny bit &lt;i&gt;completely&lt;/i&gt; intimidating, as there were no lightning talks and I was the only attraction. &amp;nbsp;Seeing over a hundred people turn up after work, before beer, to hear you talk is a humbling experience. &amp;nbsp;Fortunately, I think the audience was perfect for the presentation - they had heard of the Disruptor but hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen anything very detailed about it, so my walkthrough of how you might use it seemed to go down well. &amp;nbsp;I certainly got a lot of very sensible questions (which hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve remembered to repeat for the benefit of the recording), and people had some good ideas about how and when to use it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran the same presentation to a different audience at QCon London a week later, I&amp;rsquo;ll post a link to that if/when it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Java Community Open Conference</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/london_java_community_open_conference</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/london_java_community_open_conference</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday was, hopefully, my last conference of the year. &amp;nbsp;My lucky readers should start to see some posts which are not simply me gushing about another opportunity to hang out with awesome people and learn about interesting &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo;.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pY5RNaGdzKc/TtP9CtxtxzI/AAAAAAAAIu0/JTuUubrCF6g/s1600/DSC_0035.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pY5RNaGdzKc/TtP9CtxtxzI/AAAAAAAAIu0/JTuUubrCF6g/s320/DSC_0035.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Who wants to propose a session?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;In many ways the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt; Open Conference was my favourite one so far, and not just because it&amp;rsquo;s near home and I helped to organise it. &amp;nbsp;One of the awesome things about both &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/10/javaone-2011-roundup.html&#34;&gt;Java One&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/11/devoxx-story-so-far.html&#34;&gt;Devoxx&lt;/a&gt; was the opportunity to travel, to see new places and to meet people you might not meet in London. &amp;nbsp;The scale, and the opportunities to meet key players in the Java world, were the things I probably appreciated the most from both of those conferences. &amp;nbsp;And you can tell from my posts I really enjoyed them.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But the LJC conference was probably perfect as my last one for 2011:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-W-M-FpMSB8o/TtP9R2P6uiI/AAAAAAAAIu8/ZXAGUEuhb7Y/s1600/DSC_0065.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-W-M-FpMSB8o/TtP9R2P6uiI/AAAAAAAAIu8/ZXAGUEuhb7Y/s320/DSC_0065.jpg&#34; width=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;How do you spell &amp;lsquo;lightning&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being on home turf with awesome people who have really helped drag me kicking and screaming into the conference scene really brought home to me what an amazing year this has been. &amp;nbsp;This time last year, I felt I barely had the credentials to be a behind-the-scenes organiser for the LJC, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend last year&amp;rsquo;s conference because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how much I would get out of it. &amp;nbsp;This year, I&amp;rsquo;m at the conference giving two sessions, having made my international&amp;nbsp;début&amp;nbsp;already.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;With 120 people you feel like you can talk to everyone at some point if you want to. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I managed that, but I probably chatted in one way or another with maybe half the attendees. &amp;nbsp;The great thing about this is you see the wide variety of things people are working on - the technologies, the business problems, the team and company sizes, the methodologies. It&amp;rsquo;s eye-opening and quite exciting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It seemed that a small, open conference like this drives content based on relevance. &amp;nbsp;We had no vendor pitches, although John was contractually obliged to mention Atlassian at least once every half hour (but as they paid for the beer, this was only fair). &amp;nbsp;People vote with their feet, and attend the sessions that they will get the most out of. &amp;nbsp;I liked this format a lot.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I presented alone for the first time, not hiding behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikes-tech.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I found this surprisingly liberating. &amp;nbsp;I love working with those guys, but without them providing a safety net I actually found my confidence increasing as I realised I was perfectly capable of answering things I would probably have let them field.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;My second session was more workshop-like, and I wanted the audience to guide what we covered. &amp;nbsp;I thought it went really well, I loved letting the audience guide it, and I enjoyed giving it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was honoured (and terrified) to be asked to be part of a Meet the Experts panel with people who actually know what they&amp;rsquo;re talking about. &amp;nbsp;I was very very pleased to get away with not being asked any questions about being a girl or the length of my skirt. &amp;nbsp;We had a great discussion around writing high performance code, about different technologies and their applicability, and about the future of Java and JVM-based languages.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I loved the venue. &amp;nbsp;The rooms were a nice range of sizes, all with projectors of course, but also whiteboard space and flip charts. &amp;nbsp;It looked like a 1960s version of the future - all shiny white surfaces and curving lines. &amp;nbsp;But it felt like a space to create and innovate in.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mike&amp;rsquo;s Hacking the Open JDK session in the morning was excellent. &amp;nbsp;Again, this was another example of a workshop format working really well. &amp;nbsp;He gave some good background to compilers in general, and a good walk through of some of the code that&amp;rsquo;s there at the moment. &amp;nbsp;He was happy to share stuff he&amp;rsquo;d learnt the hard way, and it made me want to get more involved in that side of things.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The food was &lt;i&gt;awesome&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-T2mIA_BATOs/TtP-H7zXG0I/AAAAAAAAIvE/zpPILN-XR1A/s1600/DSC_0054.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-T2mIA_BATOs/TtP-H7zXG0I/AAAAAAAAIvE/zpPILN-XR1A/s320/DSC_0054.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Clearly people haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough coffee yet.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;My sessions were User&amp;rsquo;s Guides to the Disruptor - a beginner&amp;rsquo;s and a more advanced one. &amp;nbsp;The beginner&amp;rsquo;s was&amp;nbsp;an updated summary of the Disruptor stuff already covered in this blog - the ring buffer, writing to and reading from it, and configuration. &amp;nbsp;The second session covered &amp;nbsp;more advanced ideas: you don&amp;rsquo;t need a ring buffer any more; cache lines and false sharing; worker pools; aggregate event handlers. This session was a lot less prepared and more collaborative, and I loved giving it. &amp;nbsp;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s my teacher-genetics coming out.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The aim of both sessions was to give people an idea of how to actually use the Disruptor - developers are definitely interested in how and why it works, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been evangelising a lot and now there are very sensible questions being asked about how to get it to do various things. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;d like to run some more of these sessions in future, and to add more material to the blog.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6Fzn_ybxqys/TtP_H1sV-ZI/AAAAAAAAIvM/2Vx-NmjgLT4/s1600/DSC_0117.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6Fzn_ybxqys/TtP_H1sV-ZI/AAAAAAAAIvM/2Vx-NmjgLT4/s320/DSC_0117.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;And finally, a proper meal before more beer.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;Back to the conference. &amp;nbsp;Were there any downsides? &amp;nbsp;Personally I had none. &amp;nbsp;If I had to suggest an improvement for next year, it&amp;rsquo;s that we would like to see more novice speakers presenting. &amp;nbsp;The LJC has always been about nurturing this talent, and a small conference like this one with a friendly audience, many of whom you may already know, is a great place to practice. &amp;nbsp;The lightning talks showed the great variety (and abilities) of our members, it would be nice to expand this to full sessions. &amp;nbsp;As I found, filling a 30 minute session is not anywhere near as hard as you think!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to next year&amp;rsquo;s LJC conference, and I&amp;rsquo;m totally buzzing from the positive vibe from this year&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-jrd5fzdD4Jg/TtP7_O_05CI/AAAAAAAAIus/nnx_gab0UEk/s1600/DSC_0096.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-jrd5fzdD4Jg/TtP7_O_05CI/AAAAAAAAIus/nnx_gab0UEk/s400/DSC_0096.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The LJC Associates modelling their lovely new t-shirts. &amp;nbsp;Mine fits!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx: The story so far</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_story_so_far</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/devoxx_the_story_so_far</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z5FCR4QblNk/TsUvDD-bLYI/AAAAAAAAIWE/9t29vnc03dw/s1600/DSC_0051.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z5FCR4QblNk/TsUvDD-bLYI/AAAAAAAAIWE/9t29vnc03dw/s400/DSC_0051.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stephan wearing the Brazilian flag at the opening keynote&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;European conferences are different (and cool) because you get to hear even more languages spoken than you usually do in London (apparently the most diverse city in the world for spoken languages). &amp;nbsp;I think the idea of a Paris Devoxx with 75% of the talks in French is brilliant - I&amp;rsquo;m always banging on about diversity, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect developers to learn&amp;nbsp;in English only.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Really great to meet up with some of the people I met at Java One and am starting to feel more a part of the global community.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seems to me there are slightly more women here than at the other conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve been to, and not just because &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/reginatb38&#34;&gt;Regina&lt;/a&gt; and I pulled together four women for a panel on women technologists. &amp;nbsp;And once again, a lot of guys asking why this is, because they want things to change.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A highlight was seeing my namesake, AutoTrish, up on a cinema-sized screen in front of hundreds of people at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davefarley.net/&#34;&gt;Dave Farley&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Continuous Delivery presentation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Building on from my twitter revelation at JAX London, I&amp;rsquo;ve found twitter very useful here for messaging people I want to meet up with, but also for chatting to new people and making new friends. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as intimate as JAX London though because there are billions more people here, so the chances of actually bumping into the twitter friends is much lower.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have had lots of interesting conversations with people about the Open JDK, which I guess is the logical extension of the interesting conversations I had about the JCP In San Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A community event like this is different to an event like Java One, because a single organisation isn&amp;rsquo;t calling the shots. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting (and great) that Oracle and Google can both be here talking about the cool stuff they&amp;rsquo;re up to.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZiS6GQB_8No/TsUvuKMEJuI/AAAAAAAAIWM/RnQ3792tbsQ/s1600/DSC_0054.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZiS6GQB_8No/TsUvuKMEJuI/AAAAAAAAIWM/RnQ3792tbsQ/s400/DSC_0054.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;The Diabolical Developer&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Conferences are clearly something that appeal to me - I love meeting people and chatting about interesting and (sometimes) intelligent things; I love learning stuff and indexing it away, possibly for future references; I love hanging out with people like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; guys (Ben, Martijn and John); I love kicking around ideas of what more we can do at LMAX with our lot (&lt;a href=&#34;http://mikes-tech.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davefarley.net/&#34;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;, Dali). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NbOeHExh7WA/TsUv-XFma8I/AAAAAAAAIWU/UJxlYEKYLLs/s1600/DSC_0059.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NbOeHExh7WA/TsUv-XFma8I/AAAAAAAAIWU/UJxlYEKYLLs/s400/DSC_0059.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Dave&amp;rsquo;s Continuous Delivery&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to my panel this afternoon, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be ranting about how we target women for tech jobs. &amp;nbsp;Should be fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-gCXKwCpl4j4/TsUwoP2jU3I/AAAAAAAAIWc/4eE8egAKUkM/s1600/DSC_0072.JPG&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-gCXKwCpl4j4/TsUwoP2jU3I/AAAAAAAAIWc/4eE8egAKUkM/s320/DSC_0072.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Nice &amp;lsquo;tash!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Shameless plug: Mike and Dali are raising money for men&amp;rsquo;s health with their rather awesome &amp;lsquo;tashes. &amp;nbsp;It took guts to stand up on stage and present with that handlebar, please &lt;a href=&#34;http://uk.movember.com/mospace/2544604/&#34;&gt;give a penny or two&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAX London - I learn stuff and meet people</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__i_learn_stuff_and_meet_people</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/jax_london__i_learn_stuff_and_meet_people</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/&#34;&gt;JAX London&lt;/a&gt; along with a number of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt; regulars (&lt;a href=&#34;http://martijnverburg.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martijn&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/kittylyst&#34;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://jr0cket.com/&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/members/5737653/&#34;&gt;Sandro&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://devangelist.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://zoah.co.uk/jax-london&#34;&gt;Zoe&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you&amp;hellip;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IjhCGApfG_A/TrlkKBsNZQI/AAAAAAAAIV0/Dsei_5U3TBY/s1600/IMGP0035.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IjhCGApfG_A/TrlkKBsNZQI/AAAAAAAAIV0/Dsei_5U3TBY/s400/IMGP0035.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;My purpose for attending was largely to present the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/10/mike-and-i-debut-our-new-disruptor.html&#34;&gt;Hardcore Concurrency for Beginners&lt;/a&gt; talk that &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikes-tech.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I debuted at an LJC event a few weeks back.  Almost as important was catching up with the aforementioned LJCers and meeting with as many people as would talk to me.  After the disappointment of the sessions at Java One, sitting in a room being talked at was quite low down on my list of priorities.  Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be wrong.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sessions at JAX were of a very high standard, and I learnt something from every one.  I was pleasantly surprised by the calibre of international speakers that were there, and the sessions seemed to be pitched right for me personally, which was nice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Downsides:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover these first because I like to end on a high note. &amp;nbsp;Firstly, although I was interested in the Open JDK session at the community night, it was really on way too late (and after too much beer - i.e. more than none) to get the most out of it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a shame that our session was the last presentation on the final day, by that time people&amp;rsquo;s brains are fried and we didn&amp;rsquo;t get as many questions, or as much interaction, as we usually would. &amp;nbsp;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s because everyone understood and agreed with us. &amp;nbsp;But we did get great feedback so I could be scraping the barrel for things to complain about.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;The following sections outline the main takeaway points for me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Software Craftsmanship / Design&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/members/5737653/&#34;&gt;Sandro&lt;/a&gt; did a great job emphasising that Software Craftsmanship is about professionalism, not beauty. &amp;nbsp;We should be doing the right thing because we want to, because it makes everyone&amp;rsquo;s lives easier in the long run, and because it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the right thing to do, not because some process dictates that we do it. &amp;nbsp;The other thing that really struck me was how having a craftsman&amp;rsquo;s mindset leads to us taking ownership of our career and investing in it. &amp;nbsp;He also challenged us to stop being miserable and negative. &amp;nbsp;If we&amp;rsquo;re happy, we&amp;rsquo;ll attract more (presumably happy) people into our circle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://codemanship.co.uk/parlezuml/blog/&#34;&gt;Jason Gorman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Slow and Dirty presentation showed that ignoring quality slows down delivery not just in the long run, in terms of maintainability, but also in the short run - a TDD exercise of approximately 30 minutes took less time to get right when done in a test driven fashion, despite that fact that we all still think writing tests takes too much time.  He pointed out that Twitter and Facebook are statistical aberrations - not every startup can afford to assume they will be bought out of their scalability problems.  There was lots of interesting stuff here about quality, which was pretty inspiring at the time but in retrospect, as a team that already does Test Driven Development almost to the extreme, I wonder what&amp;rsquo;s next for us to improve our quality even further.&lt;br /&gt;Simon Ritter&amp;rsquo;s keynote stated that code should be a joy to read, not simply easy to read, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/AdamBien&#34;&gt;Adam Bien&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s presentation talking about simplifying code: thinking about design, and not getting bogged down in unnecessary design patterns in order to implement something simple.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Concurrency / Parallelism / Performance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-LZf05BIgfGY/Tr_GwtTq6zI/AAAAAAAAIV8/3GnJFWQYCig/s1600/5634379146_9838de9e9d_z.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-LZf05BIgfGY/Tr_GwtTq6zI/AAAAAAAAIV8/3GnJFWQYCig/s400/5634379146_9838de9e9d_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Russel Winder&amp;rsquo;s session around message passing had me thinking.  It was particularly interesting to see him say things that are possibly the opposite of what we (the LMAX/Disruptor types) are preaching.  For example, that programmers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care about the low-level details; that we should be using models (i.e. abstraction) to deal with parallelism; that you should let the JVM deal with thread management.  However, I think he&amp;rsquo;s fundamentally coming from the same place as us: &amp;ldquo;concurrency&amp;rdquo; in the past was not a good model, it was designed for old hardware that was trying to run multiple processes on a single core.  With multi-core systems you need to be running code in parallel instead. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dan Hardiker&amp;rsquo;s performance testing presentation was another one that reinforced that testing first, finding what the real performance is, profiling and then targeted experimentation are all fundamental to getting good performance.  There was a lot of good advice to how to write good performance tests too.&lt;br /&gt;Another point from Simon Ritter&amp;rsquo;s keynote reiterated that the performance free lunch was over, and we need to get better at writing parallel code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshops&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Both the Open JDK session and Ben and Martijn&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Spring cleaning your code base with Java 7&amp;rdquo; had me attempting to do things with my mac I never intended to do (i.e. write code).  Thanks to Ben and Martijn&amp;rsquo;s patience, I finally got IntelliJ playing nicely on the mac with Java 7, which was a challenge but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved it.  The Open JDK one was not as successful for me personally, but I got a good feel for the process of building it (i.e. it&amp;rsquo;s hard and it takes a very long time).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other great stuff:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The keynote by James Governor from &lt;a href=&#34;http://redmonk.com/&#34;&gt;Redmonk&lt;/a&gt; was really thought-provoking. &amp;nbsp;So thought-provoking I wrote no notes and can&amp;rsquo;t remember any of it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;As last time, the Community night was really great. &amp;nbsp;I met new people and I hung out with some old favourites. &amp;nbsp;Dear God I must stop drinking with those guys. Hotel bars are particularly awful for losing track of time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I heard about the Java 7+ features enough times from various people to be able to give an overview of the release plan to my geek friends in the pub on Friday (hey, they asked).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I learnt how to use twitter to bridge that gap between me and other&amp;nbsp;attendees, and made new friends without having to do the scary thing of approaching strangers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The lunches we rather good.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Going to a conference 20 minutes from home is a bonus. &amp;nbsp;Nice to meet other London devs as well as the European ones too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;To me, it seems as if the relevance of the JCP is starting to seep out into the real(er) world.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The tables for laptops at the front of the rooms was an awesome idea. &amp;nbsp;For a start, it encouraged people to get into the room early to get one of those seats.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had a great time at the conference, I learnt stuff and met people, which is all I really want.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For once, the photos aren&amp;rsquo;t mine.  &lt;i&gt;Images courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/&#34;&gt;JAX London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike and I debut our new Disruptor presentation</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mike_and_i_debut_our_new_disruptor_presentation</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/mike_and_i_debut_our_new_disruptor_presentation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mikes-tech.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I unveiled our brand shiny new presentation: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/events/32877942/&#34;&gt;Understanding the Disruptor, a Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Hardcore Concurrency&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;This was a preview of the talk we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaxlondon.com/2011/sessions/?tid=2175&#34;&gt;JAX London&lt;/a&gt; on the 2nd November.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/30781988&#34;&gt;video of the session&lt;/a&gt; is available, as are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/understanding-the-disruptor&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I promise not to say &amp;ldquo;so&amp;rdquo; anywhere near as many times when I repeat my performance at JAX (is there anything more painful than watching yourself on video?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I thought the session went really really well. &amp;nbsp;We got some great questions at the end, we had an audience that was engaged, and I was dead pleased we didn&amp;rsquo;t lose anyone with the assembly language. &amp;nbsp;We had some very valuable feedback afterwards too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As well as our presentation, there were three great lightning talks:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;Somay Nakhal on&amp;nbsp;Java Thread States&lt;/b&gt; - Somay gave a nice overview of thread lifecycles with code and some great diagrams. &amp;nbsp;I liked how he made this more applicable to the real world than the sort of book examples you get.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/gedb&#34;&gt;Ged Byrne&lt;/a&gt; on the shiny new&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ljcbookclub.wordpress.com/2011/10/11/coherence-3-5-book-review/&#34;&gt;LJC Book Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - Ged reminded us how great it is to read an actual, paper book. &amp;nbsp;How committing to reading page by page forces you to learn in a different way to jumping around internet references that might not give you the context you need. &amp;nbsp;I thought this was a great presentation with humour, and I liked the way he challenged us to &amp;ldquo;expand our minds&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;Although the actual book he was reviewing was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/%3Ca%20href=%22http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1847196128/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1847196128%22%3EOracle%20Coherence%203.5%3C/a%3E%3Cimg%20src=%22http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1847196128&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369%22%20width=%221%22%20height=%221%22%20border=%220%22%20alt=%22%22%20style=%22border:none%20!important;%20margin:0px%20!important;%22%20/%3E&#34;&gt;Oracle Coherence 3.5&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I need to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/%3Ca%20href=%22http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1456438786/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399373&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1456438786%22%3EBeautiful%20Software%3C/a%3E%3Cimg%20src=%22http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1456438786&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399373%22%20width=%221%22%20height=%221%22%20border=%220%22%20alt=%22%22%20style=%22border:none%20!important;%20margin:0px%20!important;%22%20/%3E&#34;&gt;Beautiful Software&lt;/a&gt;, which Ged quoted at the end of the talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vanillajava.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Peter Lawrey&lt;/a&gt; on&amp;nbsp;Common Java Misconceptions&lt;/b&gt; - A session which plays well with what we&amp;rsquo;re trying to preach when we talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/amsterdam-2011/presentation/Tackling%20the%20folklore%20surrounding%20high%20performance%20computing&#34;&gt;Tackling Folklore&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;He covered a few topics that are assumed to be &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo;. &amp;nbsp;For example, dealing with garbage collection is not a &lt;i&gt;mandatory&lt;/i&gt; part of writing Java - you could write GC-friendly code for a start. &amp;nbsp;Also it&amp;rsquo;s naive to assume the JDK is written in an efficient way, anyone who&amp;rsquo;s actually dug around it for a while will realise that newer, more efficient methods of programming have not been applied to all areas of the (massive) existing code base. &amp;nbsp;I think it&amp;rsquo;s great to have people out there talking about this stuff, it&amp;rsquo;s too easy to make assumptions and take things for granted. &amp;nbsp;The most important thing he said: &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re told something, don&amp;rsquo;t just believe it - test it yourself first&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/ul&gt;All of us (me, Mike and the lightning talk presenters) got such a great response it has encouraged us at the LJC to try and push for more real developers presenting their experiences. &amp;nbsp;We have a lot of great presentations from vendors, but what&amp;rsquo;s more applicable to Java guys and girls across the board is other developers sharing the problems they&amp;rsquo;re trying to solve and how they go about that process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very much looking forward to presenting this again at JAX. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2011: Roundup</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having been back in London for a few days I&amp;rsquo;ve had some time to digest the madness that was last week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My lasting impression of JavaOne is almost entirely positive. &amp;nbsp;Granted, it was my first major conference, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just not jaded yet. &amp;nbsp;But let me tell you what I loved about it (yes, I did cover some of these in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/10/java-one-initial-observations.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RlwrbbMeTWI/TpWq7Aw_7OI/AAAAAAAAIQ0/UiDjINFvXjo/s1600/bruno.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;219&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RlwrbbMeTWI/TpWq7Aw_7OI/AAAAAAAAIQ0/UiDjINFvXjo/s320/bruno.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First and foremost, the people. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember meeting a single grumpy person. Everyone I spoke to was there to get the most out of the experience, regardless of how many times they&amp;rsquo;d been previously. &amp;nbsp;In my experience, techies are not conditioned to be socially comfortable, yet&amp;nbsp;introductions were made and&amp;nbsp;the conversations flowed easily.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Of course it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just the attendees who were friendly, the staff and organisers were approachable and helpful, and it was nice to have people hanging around to direct you.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;One of the (few) advantages of having the event over multiple hotels was the outdoor space between them. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that it rained, &amp;nbsp;but I really liked being able to hang around outside. &amp;nbsp;I especially liked that they had provided power points for your laptop, so you didn&amp;rsquo;t have to be cooped up indoors to update your blog. &amp;nbsp;I also thought that having to walk between the venues was good exercise, given I didn&amp;rsquo;t make it to the gym last week. However I can see why people want to move the event back to one central location.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UOsWpFnYjSw/TpWrGSgqheI/AAAAAAAAIQ8/Hx8nyX5S3uA/s1600/martijn.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UOsWpFnYjSw/TpWrGSgqheI/AAAAAAAAIQ8/Hx8nyX5S3uA/s200/martijn.jpg&#34; width=&#34;177&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I personally found the sessions less useful than the networking. &amp;nbsp;I mostly attended the high-performance / concurrency sessions, but I probably should have been to ones about things I &lt;i&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/i&gt; know (e.g. other JVM languages). &amp;nbsp;My favourite session was &lt;a href=&#34;http://martijnverburg.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martijn&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Diabolical Developer session, but then I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of stand-up comedy. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Another favourite was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://javaposse.com/&#34;&gt;Java Posse&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;live podcast. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed to admit that I&amp;rsquo;ve never listened to one before (my excuse: I don&amp;rsquo;t listen to podcasts at all because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a long commute to work, which would be the ideal time). &amp;nbsp;I thought it was great how everyone felt like a part of the Java Posse and not a passive audience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8az7qiRldX8/TpWro5J2Z2I/AAAAAAAAIRM/fCD-liE8g9o/s1600/javaposse.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8az7qiRldX8/TpWro5J2Z2I/AAAAAAAAIRM/fCD-liE8g9o/s320/javaposse.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I really felt that Oracle was trying its best to invoke the spirit of community. &amp;nbsp;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s because when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in sessions or having random conversations, I was in Java User Group or &lt;a href=&#34;http://jcp.org/en/home/index&#34;&gt;Java Community Process&lt;/a&gt; events. &amp;nbsp;It seems pretty clear to me that the inclusion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://soujava.org.br/&#34;&gt;SouJava&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;London Java Community&lt;/a&gt; in the JCP EC has shaken things up a bit. &amp;nbsp;But then, I would say that - I&amp;rsquo;m biased. &amp;nbsp;But the vibe I was getting across the whole conference was that having the community involved in this key decision-making organisation is a step forward. &amp;nbsp;I would even go so far as to claim that it inspired a number of other players to seriously consider getting on board rather than complaining from the sidelines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vuIJB2I4Elo/TpWrcuMqwoI/AAAAAAAAIRE/M8Y6MkPZW6E/s1600/jduchess.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;145&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vuIJB2I4Elo/TpWrcuMqwoI/AAAAAAAAIRE/M8Y6MkPZW6E/s320/jduchess.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On a related note, I really enjoyed the final &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/ocom/groups/systemobject/@mktg_admin/documents/webcontent/videoplayer-ocom.html?bctid=1176404830001&amp;amp;playerID=single-social&amp;amp;size=events&#34;&gt;keynote on community&lt;/a&gt;. To me, that was an indication that Oracle takes our participation very seriously. &amp;nbsp;I liked that it was split into a lot of different interviews and panels, all quite short, which showcased the variety of the Java platform community. &amp;nbsp;I came out of that feeling pretty warm and fluffy about the future of our technology, and proud to be an active part of it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Stuff I was not so bothered about:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Vendor keynotes. &amp;nbsp;Pretty dull to be honest. &amp;nbsp;I understand why they had them but after the first one I didn&amp;rsquo;t turn up to any more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The other bad points I already mentioned in the last post.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Personal highlights:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aovhDAhVoKI/TpWryE1AKMI/AAAAAAAAIRU/vnwMqPGquSQ/s1600/intro-to-disruptor.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;154&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aovhDAhVoKI/TpWryE1AKMI/AAAAAAAAIRU/vnwMqPGquSQ/s200/intro-to-disruptor.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Picking up the Duke&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/ocom/groups/public/@ocom/documents/digitalasset/512339.jpg&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- note: only seems to work in Firefox for me) for &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/&#34;&gt;the Disruptor&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ll shut up about it at some point, let me have my moment of glory.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Co-presenting a session on the Disruptor with &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;He invited me to stand up with him when we realised I could go to the event, and I was terrified of the thought. &amp;nbsp;So I did it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Meeting and being interviewed by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jduchess.org/&#34;&gt;JDuchess&lt;/a&gt; ladies. &amp;nbsp;The video doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be available, so maybe I was rubbish, but it was a cool thing for me all the same.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Talking about the Disruptor for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.oracle.com/javaspotlight/entry/java_spotlight_episode_51_live&#34;&gt;Java Spotlight Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the Oracle news guys (again, I can&amp;rsquo;t find the content for this yet).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had a really brilliant time, and would love to repeat the experience again as soon as possible!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2011</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m off to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/javaone/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaOne&lt;/a&gt; next week!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is an unexpected and very pleasant surprise. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll be there with &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt; (of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/&#34;&gt;Disruptor&lt;/a&gt; fame), and &lt;a href=&#34;http://martijnverburg.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Martijn&lt;/a&gt; (that&amp;rsquo;s not going to get confusing at all). &amp;nbsp;Martin will be talking about the Disruptor on Thursday, and Martijn is busy talking about&amp;hellip; everything. &amp;nbsp;Most importantly for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/&#34;&gt;LJC&lt;/a&gt; he&amp;rsquo;s representing us in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/05/london-java-community-elected-to-jcp.html&#34;&gt;shiny new JCP Executive Committee&lt;/a&gt; role.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to meeting pretty much anyone and everyone who&amp;rsquo;ll talk to me. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s the first international conference I&amp;rsquo;ve been to and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to meet people I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally get a chance to see in London. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s also really cool to be able to represent both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lmaxtrader.co.uk/&#34;&gt;LMAX&lt;/a&gt; and the London Java Community. Hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t lead to some sort of split personality syndrome.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Almost more excitingly, I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a spot of shopping in New York on the way there and back. Because, well, it would be rude to fly over to the States and not drop in on my old home.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get a chance to catch up with some of you in one of those amazing cities&amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First public appearance caught on video</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/first_public_appearance_caught_on_video</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/first_public_appearance_caught_on_video</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; class=&#34;BLOG_video_class&#34; id=&#34;BLOG_video-287f97612eb2190a&#34; classid=&#34;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&#34; codebase=&#34;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;//www.youtube.com/get_player&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#FFFFFF&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;flashvars&#34; value=&#34;flvurl=http://redirector.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?id%3D287f97612eb2190a%26itag%3D5%26source%3Dblogger%26app%3Dblogger%26cmo%3Dsensitive_content%253Dyes%26ip%3D0.0.0.0%26ipbits%3D0%26expire%3D1396950053%26sparams%3Did,itag,source,ip,ipbits,expire%26signature%3D20ED37B720D3E3058754AA38FB5BF2EFC71B4AA8.7FFBEB86F5896865B7B52EF09DDEABDE4FDF1AC1%26key%3Dck2&amp;amp;iurl=http://video.google.com/ThumbnailServer2?app%3Dblogger%26contentid%3D287f97612eb2190a%26offsetms%3D5000%26itag%3Dw160%26sigh%3DzHzyKS8xvdgfqY81PzOmfaF842E&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;ps=blogger&#34;&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/get_player&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#FFFFFF&#34; flashvars=&#34;flvurl=http://redirector.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?id%3D287f97612eb2190a%26itag%3D5%26source%3Dblogger%26app%3Dblogger%26cmo%3Dsensitive_content%253Dyes%26ip%3D0.0.0.0%26ipbits%3D0%26expire%3D1396950053%26sparams%3Did,itag,source,ip,ipbits,expire%26signature%3D20ED37B720D3E3058754AA38FB5BF2EFC71B4AA8.7FFBEB86F5896865B7B52EF09DDEABDE4FDF1AC1%26key%3Dck2&amp;iurl=http://video.google.com/ThumbnailServer2?app%3Dblogger%26contentid%3D287f97612eb2190a%26offsetms%3D5000%26itag%3Dw160%26sigh%3DzHzyKS8xvdgfqY81PzOmfaF842E&amp;autoplay=0&amp;ps=blogger&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Remember a while back I talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com/2011/05/my-first-public-appearance.html&#34;&gt;my first public appearance&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well, I chased down the video, because I&amp;rsquo;m masochistic, and here it is for you all to enjoy. &amp;nbsp;Pleasingly my mannerisms are slightly less of a camp man trapped in a woman&amp;rsquo;s body, which was my impression the last time I saw myself presenting. &amp;nbsp;It helps that YouTube has made the video so dark you can&amp;rsquo;t see me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Slides are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/trishagee/introduction-to-the-java-community-process&#34;&gt;available for all to enjoy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.playfish.com/&#34;&gt;Playfish&lt;/a&gt; for hosting the event - as always, their hospitality was awesome. &amp;nbsp;The fact that they didn&amp;rsquo;t serve wine is probably a Good Thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
