<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work environment on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/work-environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work environment on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/work-environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to show your employees how much you hate them</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/how_to_show_your_employees_how_much_you_hate_them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/how_to_show_your_employees_how_much_you_hate_them/</guid>
      <description>Due to a combination of my restlessness, my consulting experience, and employers that insist on moving offices frequently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the dubious honour of working in a variety of environments.
Today I will teach you, the employer, how to show your staff just how much you hate them.
The Kitchen Is Not For Eating In
Since eating and drinking is unfortunately a fundamental part of being human and staying alive, you will need to provide your staff with a space that pretends to address these needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Environment</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/working_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/working_environment/</guid>
      <description>How important to you is your working environment? - Type of desk - What&amp;rsquo;s on it - Position / type of mouse, keyboard, monitor(s) - Music / background sound (or lack of it) - Open plan vs team room vs cube vs personal office - etc&amp;hellip; These physical items could be extended to include your virtual environment: - Eclipse / IntelliJ Idea / Visual Studio (is it still called this?) / other dev enviornment - setup, preferences, window positions - OS - Desktop icons - do you care what / how many / positioning - Which software is always open when you&amp;rsquo;re working, and does it matter what order you open them in (so they&amp;rsquo;re in the correct place on your task bar) (additional: does not having enough RAM cripple you because you have to constantly shut and re-open software?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
