<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Android on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/android/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Xtended</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/android_xtended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6771.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34; alt=&#34;The 
calm before the storm&#34; title=&#34;The calm before the storm&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the more I go to conferences, the less I write about them.  I could claim lack of time, but
the fact is that all my write-ups will be something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Loved &amp;lt;city&amp;gt;, went to talks that made me
think, met interesting people, gave a talk or two that seemed to go well&amp;rdquo;. Not sure if people get bored of reading
that, but I get bored of writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6803.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Conferences are fun&#34; title=&#34;Conferences are fun&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I&amp;rsquo;m bored of conferences. On the contrary - since I work from home, travelling to new places and
meeting Real Human Beings keeps me sane. Plus conferences are fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6753.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; alt=&#34;The 
setup&#34; title=&#34;The setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I went to a conference on Saturday that makes me feel compelled to write something, and not just because it was
organised by my two fellow &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;Sevilla JUG&lt;/a&gt; organisers.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/israkaos&#34;&gt;@IsraKaos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rgdav&#34;&gt;@RGDav&lt;/a&gt; are both doing more Android day-to-day than
server-side Java, so this is an area they&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about. Not content with organising
Android events every other month, they decided they had so many interesting speakers they wanted to have speaking here
in Sevilla that they wanted to run a whole day, single track conference, on behalf of &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/communities/114997118727600981533&#34;&gt;GDG Sevilla&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidxtended.com/&#34;&gt;Android Xtended&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6848.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Android Xtended&#34; title=&#34;Android Xtended&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;As a Java &amp;ldquo;Technical Advocate&amp;rdquo;, I suppose I should keep an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the Android space, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a
huge part of the ecosystem&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/post/androidxtended#footnote1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to go in any sort
of official capacity (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t speaking, manning a booth, organising or sponsoring), so I could just enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/registration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hola...&#34; title=&#34;Hola...&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, they roped me into doing registrations. Me! I was concerned my Spanish wasn&amp;rsquo;t up for it, but apparently I only
needed two words: &amp;ldquo;nombre&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;talla&amp;rdquo; (for the t-shirt). Oh, and &amp;ldquo;treinta y uno b&amp;rdquo; - there was such demand for the
conference the initial venue wasn&amp;rsquo;t big enough, so it was being hosted at two sites on the same road. Not
surprisingly, some turned up to the wrong one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6813.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@inmaculadaalcon&#34; title=&#34;@inmaculadaalcon&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike a large number of our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SVQJUG/&#34;&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Sevilla-MongoDB-User-Group/&#34;&gt;MUG&lt;/a&gt; events, all the talks were in Spanish. So feel
free to ignore my analysis if you like - my Spanish comprehension is pretty good, but sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t realise when
I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand something and just make up my own story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;float:left; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6794.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
alt=&#34;@flipper83&#34; title=&#34;@flipper83&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far in the Android space is Getting Started type material - a lot of tutorials and
examples that show you how to achieve a particular goal. There seems to be less of an emphasis on areas that
interest me as an experienced Java person - easy automation of testing, good design practices, craftsmanship etc. Now,
 it may be that because those areas (apart from testing) apply to both back-end Java and Android, there&amp;rsquo;s less of a
 need to re-iterate it in the Android space. Or it may be that I don&amp;rsquo;t see the entry-level Java stuff any more,
 because I don&amp;rsquo;t need it, and I seek out the topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6892.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
 alt=&#34;@JMPergar&#34; title=&#34;@JMPergar&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or it may be that as Android is one of those
 platforms that&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start as a fairly novice developer (because you can write self-contained code with
 a visible UI and get results fairly easily), lots of the focus is on the needs of new developers.  Whatever the
 reason, I had been starting to feel like the Android ecosystem was missing people taking developers beyond that
 initial step of getting something to work and up to the level of creating maintainable code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6880.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@pedro_g_s&#34; title=&#34;@pedro_g_s&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Xtended put my mind at rest. Here was a range of talks that led attendees through the things that will make
them more effective developers - tools and libraries to use; testing approaches; integration with persistence; clean
(code) design for the UI; design patterns and domain driven design to simplify your code, and so on. As an employee
of JetBrains, I was obviously very happy to see both
&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/tools/studio/index.html&#34;&gt;Android Studio&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; mentioned and used throughout as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6863.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;@davilagrau&#34; title=&#34;@davilagrau&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as fantastic speakers (they knew their stuff, were clearly practitioners, and all had great individual
presentation styles), there were three mob-programming sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6853.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mob Programming&#34; title=&#34;Mob Programming&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an ambitious attempt to not just preach to
a passive audience, but to involve them in creating real, working code to teach fundamental practices - dependency
injection, testing and Gradle.  An hour is barely enough time to give a practiced demo of real code, to create
something collaboratively with an audience of 30 people was a challenge. But I thought it did give people a flavour
of not just how to use the technologies, but what they were for. I also saw a lot of the audience starting to
realise the power of refactoring using an IDE - I firmly believe the best way to teach the power of a tool is by
pair programming or, at least, using the tool in real use cases in front of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6921.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More collaboration&#34; title=&#34;More collaboration&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mob programming was kinda
like a half day tutorial squished into an hour. I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to hear how the attendees found it. For me, since
this was a full day conference that cost &amp;euro;10, I thought getting three short tutorials as well as five excellent
talks was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good value for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6896.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Happy developers&#34; title=&#34;Happy developers&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;div style=&#34;float:right; padding: 10px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6883.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; 
alt=&#34;Interesting...&#34; title=&#34;Interesting...&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be remiss in talking about the conference if I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention the venue.  We were at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://espaciores.org/&#34;&gt;Espacio RES&lt;/a&gt;, which was pretty easy to get to, and a really nice, airy, comfortable
space&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/post/androidxtended#footnote2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
And they let us rearrange their whole place just for us. The only downside is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hold more people, which
is a shame, and the reason we had to host on two sites (I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on the other site as I stayed
at RES the whole day, but we&amp;rsquo;re very grateful to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitnami.com/&#34;&gt;Bitnami&lt;/a&gt; for lending us their offices as well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6831.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Collaboration&#34; title=&#34;Collaboration&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did I learn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://espaciores.org/&#34;&gt;Espacio RES&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice space that hopefully we can use more regularly for events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is possible to use Good Practices to write Android code, and Real Developers are doing so for Real Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are very talented and expert technical speakers in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to two conferences in Spain in
the last month, but as they were all in English I think it puts some people off presenting. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see Spanish
talent being showcased, it gives developers here good role models and shows that experts aren&amp;rsquo;t just from outside
Spain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sevilla has a very healthy tech scene with people more than happy to give up a Saturday to learn new things. In
fact, for some set of people, they prefer Saturdays to weekday
evenings&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/post/androidxtended#footnote3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I have a feeling I&amp;rsquo;m about to lose more weekends in the
future&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;People like Saturdays?&#34; title=&#34;People like 
 Saturdays?&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Xtended was a fantastic event, with great speakers and engaged attendees.  I loved how social
 everyone was during the breaks, how people were happy to chat and share stories, even though most of the attendees
 didn&amp;rsquo;t know each other beforehand. It was brilliantly organised, and although I did see how much work went into
 arranging it, you would never believe from how smoothly it went that this two-venue event was organised by just two
 guys. Well done &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/israkaos&#34;&gt;@IsraKaos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rgdav&#34;&gt;@RGDav&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/androidxtended/DSC_6927.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Drinks&#34; title=&#34;Drinks&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Although in my experience Android and &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; Java user groups and events tend not to
 overlap much - not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a function of the relationship between Google and Oracle or just because large cities like
 London tend to split groups along technology lines to keep group and event sizes manageable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The downside was there are not a lot of places nearby open for coffee at 8am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;footnote3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; This is completely alien to me as someone who built her career largely in London - you
 do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; host events on a Saturday, except for maybe the annual LJC Open Conference, because many people have a
 long commute into the city. Doing that 5 days a week is plenty, most people don&amp;rsquo;t want to do it on a Saturday as
 well. But they will give up a couple of hours in the evening, as it costs far less in time overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experiences with Android Development</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_experiences_with_android_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_experiences_with_android_development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I was missing coding, and because my friend and I had an awesome phone app idea at the weekend, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try my hand at developing an Android application this week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I want to give a quick overview of my preliminary thoughts on getting started on this endeavour. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Background: I&amp;rsquo;ve got more than 10 years Java experience, but any UI for the applications I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on was always a web UI. &amp;nbsp;I am &lt;i&gt;completely&lt;/i&gt; new to mobile app development.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Getting Started&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I spent maybe a day and a half reading the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/basics/what-is-android.html&#34;&gt;Android developer documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and attempting to hack out a quick &amp;lsquo;droid app.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was surprised to find the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/fundamentals.html&#34;&gt;Application Fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; section actually made sense to me. &amp;nbsp;There appears to be a clear architecture with design guidelines laid out for developers to follow. &amp;nbsp;This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t really be a surprise I suppose, but years of hacking around with web UIs with poorly implemented MVC architectures must have left me thinking that all frameworks are less &amp;ldquo;frame&amp;rdquo; and more &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I remember the disaster of trying to get my first JDK working on my 486 - what a nightmare! &amp;nbsp;And getting Tomcat 3 installed and running? &amp;nbsp;Forget it. &amp;nbsp;I also remember the last time I made a serious stab at a learning a new technology. &amp;nbsp;I tried develop a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grails.org/&#34;&gt;Grails&lt;/a&gt;/Groovy application in Eclipse. &amp;nbsp;The IS guys had to rescue my laptop from me during that enterprise before I could do it any serious damage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Installing the SDK on my mac was surprisingly simple, especially bearing in mind I&amp;rsquo;m new both to OSX and to mobile development. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s because Android development has been well thought out and well supported, or if it&amp;rsquo;s a function of both the industry&amp;rsquo;s maturity and my own experience. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The integration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; was much slicker than I expected, especially since I&amp;rsquo;m using the freebie Community edition. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact steps to tell it I wanted to create an Android project, but it must have been ridiculously easy otherwise I would remember the trauma. &amp;nbsp;I do remember a little confusion around installing the Android platform - I hadn&amp;rsquo;t understood the difference between installing the SDK and then installing a specific API for it. &amp;nbsp;But the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/other-ide.html&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/tools/othertools.html#android&#34;&gt;android&lt;/a&gt; application got me on the right track in the end. &amp;nbsp;And then when I clicked the &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; button in IntelliJ, hey presto! &amp;nbsp;The emulator appeared and there was my app!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;I loved the emulator. &amp;nbsp;I had some confused idea that I would have to plug my own phone into the laptop to see my application. &amp;nbsp;Instead, the emulator looks enough like my actual phone to give me decent feedback on how the app is going to behave. &amp;nbsp;The downside is I was trying to play with the camera, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see how that would really work in the emulator, but I got a fair idea.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did it work?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;I managed to get a rudimentary application running, with a button and some descriptive text (it&amp;rsquo;s not about to win any awards). &amp;nbsp;The button was supposed to launch the camera viewer, but my first few attempts just resulted in the crash notification. &amp;nbsp;It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to figure out how to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/debug-tasks.html&#34;&gt;logcat&lt;/a&gt; to see the stack trace and see I hadn&amp;rsquo;t set the permissions correctly to use the camera, so I rooted through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/ApiDemos/src/com/example/android/apis/graphics/CameraPreview.html&#34;&gt;CameraPreview&lt;/a&gt; example in &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/ApiDemos/index.html&#34;&gt;APIDemos &lt;/a&gt;to figure out how to set up the AndroidManifest.xml correctly, and rather amazingly it all worked!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Any downsides?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;I was surprised (and slightly disappointed) at the amount of XML configuration. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen plenty of evil Spring and Ant XML in the enterprise and I thought frameworks were moving away from that. &amp;nbsp;The manifest I can understand I suppose, but it felt a bit weird to be defining the UI in XML. &amp;nbsp;It seemed like a bit of an afterthought tagged on after all the well-defined architecture behind the scenes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;But maybe this will make more sense to me as I develop my application further.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;In Summary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was pleasantly surprised to be able to get an Android application (albeit a very basic one) working in only a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Development in IntelliJ was &lt;i&gt;much &lt;/i&gt;easier than I expected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The documentation is actually very good.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll see how I feel about it when I start trying to do more than a very simple example application.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
