<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Android on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/android/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experiences with Android Development</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_experiences_with_android_development</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/my_experiences_with_android_development</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I was missing coding, and because my friend and I had an awesome phone app idea at the weekend, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try my hand at developing an Android application this week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I want to give a quick overview of my preliminary thoughts on getting started on this endeavour. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Background: I&amp;rsquo;ve got more than 10 years Java experience, but any UI for the applications I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on was always a web UI. &amp;nbsp;I am &lt;i&gt;completely&lt;/i&gt; new to mobile app development.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Getting Started&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I spent maybe a day and a half reading the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/basics/what-is-android.html&#34;&gt;Android developer documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and attempting to hack out a quick &amp;lsquo;droid app.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was surprised to find the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/fundamentals.html&#34;&gt;Application Fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; section actually made sense to me. &amp;nbsp;There appears to be a clear architecture with design guidelines laid out for developers to follow. &amp;nbsp;This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t really be a surprise I suppose, but years of hacking around with web UIs with poorly implemented MVC architectures must have left me thinking that all frameworks are less &amp;ldquo;frame&amp;rdquo; and more &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I remember the disaster of trying to get my first JDK working on my 486 - what a nightmare! &amp;nbsp;And getting Tomcat 3 installed and running? &amp;nbsp;Forget it. &amp;nbsp;I also remember the last time I made a serious stab at a learning a new technology. &amp;nbsp;I tried develop a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grails.org/&#34;&gt;Grails&lt;/a&gt;/Groovy application in Eclipse. &amp;nbsp;The IS guys had to rescue my laptop from me during that enterprise before I could do it any serious damage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Installing the SDK on my mac was surprisingly simple, especially bearing in mind I&amp;rsquo;m new both to OSX and to mobile development. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s because Android development has been well thought out and well supported, or if it&amp;rsquo;s a function of both the industry&amp;rsquo;s maturity and my own experience. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The integration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; was much slicker than I expected, especially since I&amp;rsquo;m using the freebie Community edition. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact steps to tell it I wanted to create an Android project, but it must have been ridiculously easy otherwise I would remember the trauma. &amp;nbsp;I do remember a little confusion around installing the Android platform - I hadn&amp;rsquo;t understood the difference between installing the SDK and then installing a specific API for it. &amp;nbsp;But the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/other-ide.html&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/tools/othertools.html#android&#34;&gt;android&lt;/a&gt; application got me on the right track in the end. &amp;nbsp;And then when I clicked the &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; button in IntelliJ, hey presto! &amp;nbsp;The emulator appeared and there was my app!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;I loved the emulator. &amp;nbsp;I had some confused idea that I would have to plug my own phone into the laptop to see my application. &amp;nbsp;Instead, the emulator looks enough like my actual phone to give me decent feedback on how the app is going to behave. &amp;nbsp;The downside is I was trying to play with the camera, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see how that would really work in the emulator, but I got a fair idea.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did it work?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;I managed to get a rudimentary application running, with a button and some descriptive text (it&amp;rsquo;s not about to win any awards). &amp;nbsp;The button was supposed to launch the camera viewer, but my first few attempts just resulted in the crash notification. &amp;nbsp;It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to figure out how to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/debug-tasks.html&#34;&gt;logcat&lt;/a&gt; to see the stack trace and see I hadn&amp;rsquo;t set the permissions correctly to use the camera, so I rooted through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/ApiDemos/src/com/example/android/apis/graphics/CameraPreview.html&#34;&gt;CameraPreview&lt;/a&gt; example in &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/ApiDemos/index.html&#34;&gt;APIDemos &lt;/a&gt;to figure out how to set up the AndroidManifest.xml correctly, and rather amazingly it all worked!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Any downsides?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;I was surprised (and slightly disappointed) at the amount of XML configuration. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen plenty of evil Spring and Ant XML in the enterprise and I thought frameworks were moving away from that. &amp;nbsp;The manifest I can understand I suppose, but it felt a bit weird to be defining the UI in XML. &amp;nbsp;It seemed like a bit of an afterthought tagged on after all the well-defined architecture behind the scenes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;But maybe this will make more sense to me as I develop my application further.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;In Summary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was pleasantly surprised to be able to get an Android application (albeit a very basic one) working in only a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Development in IntelliJ was &lt;i&gt;much &lt;/i&gt;easier than I expected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The documentation is actually very good.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll see how I feel about it when I start trying to do more than a very simple example application.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
