<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>process on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/process/</link>
    <description>Recent content in process on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Handover</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/the_handover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/the_handover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I walked into the kitchen to see how lunch was going and my boyfriend handed me a knife, 
a part-chopped hard boiled egg and said &amp;ldquo;finish this, I need to have a shower&amp;rdquo;. As you do. Apparently there were two things that needed 
doing - &amp;ldquo;this&amp;rdquo; needed finishing, and I needed to keep an eye on the fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting to Working Remotely</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/adjusting_to_working_remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/adjusting_to_working_remotely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most obvious differences I faced when I moved from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lmax.com/&#34;&gt;LMAX&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.10gen .com/&#34;&gt;10gen&lt;/a&gt; were the working conditions.  I don&amp;rsquo;t mean like being deep underground in some dangerous situation vs being pampered by beautiful slave boys and girls.  What I mean is that the working practices at one company necessitated being in the office for core hours, and at the other flexible hours and remote-working are practically mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Other Side: Confessions of an Offshore Resource</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/tales_from_the_other_side_confessions_of_an_offshore_resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/tales_from_the_other_side_confessions_of_an_offshore_resource/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the acquisition of a company with offices in New York, I pestered my company outrageously until they got fed up and finally relented – they agreed to send me to the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ease the transition, I chose to move onto a project which would allow me to start working in London and continue on the same team after I had moved to New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the extreme over-excitement that followed my relocation, it took me a little while to realise that effectively I was an offshore resource, no different really from any of our Indian test team, and the team needed to manage this appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt a number of lessons whilst playing this game.  Some of these points are also valid for teams with remote resources (e.g. people working from home).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
