<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>YOW on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/yow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in YOW on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/yow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, Backwards Compatibility? (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_backwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOW recorded me, yet again, talking about the adventure that is the design of the new Java Driver for MongoDB.  This is the same talk I
gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/72982916&#34;&gt;GeeCON&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parleys.com/play/51c325c3e4b0d38b54f4624f/chapter1/about&#34;&gt;DevoxxUK&lt;/a&gt;,
with some updates based on our Journey So Far.  In it, I cover the architecture of the new driver and some of our current thoughts
around where we want the API to go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Advice for Programmers (YOW 2013)</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/yow_2013_career_advice_for_programmers/</guid>
      <description>Since I have a tendancy to bang on every now and again about how we, as developers, could do better in managing our careers (for example, by creating CVs that don&#39;t suck, and by staying ahead of the curve), Dave Thomas asked me to speak for a mere 50 minutes on the subject at [GOTO Aarhus](http://gotocon .com/video#36), a talk I wasn&#39;t enormously happy with as there was no way to cover a lifetime of hard-fought experience in such a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YOW</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/yow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/yow/</guid>
      <description>December disappeared in a rush of vacation and a fleeting tour of Australia. It&#39;s hard to believe that it&#39;s the eve of Christmas Eve already, it&#39;s almost impossible to feel Christmassy when you&#39;re getting sunburnt on a boat and seeing people in swim-suits wearing santa hats. A mid-winter festival (complete with trees and fake snow) just feels very odd in summer.I cannot take Christmas seriously in this weatherYOW!is a unique conference, in that it&#39;s the same agenda in three different cities: Melbourne, Brisbane and Sydney.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>