<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interview on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interview on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What could possibly go wrong? (GOTO Chicago)</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interview_at_goto_chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://gotocon.com/chicago-2014/&#34;&gt;GOTO Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, I was given the chance to chat a bit about the presentation I was giving, 
which happens to be the same one I&amp;rsquo;m giving at a number of conferences this year (although of course I&amp;rsquo;m evolving it as I go along).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Charles Humble for InfoQ</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/infoq-interview-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/infoq-interview-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/qcon_london_2014/&#34;&gt;QCon London&lt;/a&gt;, I was grabbed for an interview with InfoQ.  It&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasure to be interviewed by Charles,
I think he brings out the best in me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Stephen Chin about JavaOne 2013</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_by_stephen_chin_about_javaone_2013/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Stephen Chin, one of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Java Evangelists and the JavaOne content chair, interviewed me via a live stream about JavaOne, the new MongoDB Java driver, and my plans to Change The World.
It was a fun interview to do, and I really like the format of being interviewed over Skype and streaming my desktop. There&amp;rsquo;s a slight (OK, 25 seconds, not really low latency) lag between the screen and the speaking which means it&amp;rsquo;s not a great platform for doing live demos, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d like to do more code demos in this way, if I can find a suitable platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDL Presents Women Techmakers with Trisha Gee</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/gdl_presents_women_techmakers_with_trisha_gee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/gdl_presents_women_techmakers_with_trisha_gee/</guid>
      <description>I was flattered a couple of weeks ago to be interviewed by Google as part of their women techmaker&amp;rsquo;s series, as it moves over to Europe. In this video I talk about going to Mars, education, planning your career, being a developer, and the impact of technology on our lives. So, not much&amp;hellip;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed at Devoxx</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interviewed_at_devoxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interviewed_at_devoxx/</guid>
      <description>Yolande Poirier from OTN interviewed me at Devoxx about my new job at 10gen, Women in IT (bet that surprises you), how to be a role model, and Agile. Enjoy.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview and Hacking session with Stephen Chin</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_and_hacking_session_with_stephen_chin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_and_hacking_session_with_stephen_chin/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, Stephen Chin from Oracle visited me at the 10gen offices as part of his NightHacking tour. &amp;nbsp;In the video we talk about my sessions at JavaOne and the Agile presentation I&#39;m giving at Devoxx, and I do some very basic hacking using the MongoDB Java driver, attempting to showcase gradle at the same time. It was a fun experience, even if it&#39;s scary being live-streamed and recorded!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed at GOTO Copenhagen</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_goto_copenhagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interviewed_at_goto_copenhagen/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed at GOTO Copenhagen, about Java, the Disruptor, the Graduate Developer Community &amp;amp; London Java Community, and a whole host of other things. So to make up for the lack of blogging this month, here it is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Do and How Did You Get There?</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/what_do_you_do_and_how_did_you_get_there/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/what_do_you_do_and_how_did_you_get_there/</guid>
      <description>So yet another interview with me is available, but this one is in written form. It&amp;rsquo;s for the Graduate Developer Community, the aim is to show undergraduates and graduates what real techies jobs are like, and how people doing them they got there.
It&amp;rsquo;s long, but if you know anyone just starting out their career who wants to get a feel for where they might want to go, please point them at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed for InfoQ at QCon London</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interviewed_for_infoq_at_qcon_london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/interviewed_for_infoq_at_qcon_london/</guid>
      <description>I was flattered to be interviewed for InfoQ at QCon London. It was a fun interview actually, and didn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything like the half an hour it actually took. In it, I get to talk about Agile at LMAX, the Disruptor (of course) and diversity in IT (again).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on events</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/update_on_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/update_on_events/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to say I was interviewed for another podcast, again to talk about all-female events. It&amp;rsquo;s only a short one and there&amp;rsquo;s probably not much in there that I haven&amp;rsquo;t said before, either on here or in person.
From the 21st May, I&amp;rsquo;m at GOTO, both Copenhagen and Amsterdam. I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about code &amp;amp; the Disruptor, thank goodness, and will be trying not to rant about the subject of women in technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured on a BBC Podcast</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/featured_on_a_bbc_podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/featured_on_a_bbc_podcast/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s BBC Outriders podcast features yours truly venting about The Subject That Won&amp;rsquo;t Go Away, Women in Technology. I was interviewed at Sunday&amp;rsquo;s Girl Geek conference, and got a chance to voice my opinions once again. For those who can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to listen, they can probably be summarised as:
There are genuine problems that face people in our industry, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about those that you have actually faced, not ones that you imagine exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview by the Oracle Technology Network at Devoxx</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/interview_by_the_oracle_technology_network_at_devoxx/</guid>
      <description>Tori Wieldt from the Oracle Technology Network interviewed me at Devoxx. Because I was there to be on the Why We Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Target Women panel, the interview is just another platform for me to air my views on this subject again. 
Yes, I am actually wearing pink&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>