<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaOne11 on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaOne11 on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/javaone11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More videos from Java One 2011</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/more_videos_from_java_one_2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/more_videos_from_java_one_2011/</guid>
      <description>It must be time for me to move on from talking about Java One, it has dominated my blog of late. But also I want to talk about JAX London from this week.
But before I move on, it&amp;rsquo;s probably worth rounding off with the last two resources from the conference.
1) Martin Thompson and I are interviewed about the Disruptor winning the Duke Award (we come in halfway through):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Similarities Between Girls And Aliens</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/on_the_similarities_between_girls_and_aliens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/on_the_similarities_between_girls_and_aliens/</guid>
      <description>I discovered, through the power of the search words that lead to my blog, that there was an incident at JavaOne that once again opens the can of worms that is Sexism In IT.
This Makes Me Sad. I had a really positive experience at JavaOne. In fact, I would say it was the one conference I&amp;rsquo;ve been to in the last 12 months where I felt like my gender wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem - I even got away with wearing hotpants (tweed is business-casual, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne 2011: Roundup</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_2011_roundup/</guid>
      <description>Having been back in London for a few days I&amp;rsquo;ve had some time to digest the madness that was last week.
My lasting impression of JavaOne is almost entirely positive. Granted, it was my first major conference, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just not jaded yet. But let me tell you what I loved about it (yes, I did cover some of these in my last post):
First and foremost, the people. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember meeting a single grumpy person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaOne: Initial Observations</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_initial_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/javaone_initial_observations/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been at JavaOne for the better part of three days, it&amp;rsquo;s time to record some of my observations so far:
The wireless access is rubbish.&amp;lt;Gross generalisation&amp;gt; technical people are not natural public speakers. Makes me feel better about the presentations I&amp;rsquo;m going to be giving (see A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Hardcore Concurrency).The sessions are less useful than getting out and chatting. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a really excellent time, I&amp;rsquo;ve met: people from other Java User Groups; the Duchess girls; other Duke Award winners; the Azul guys; guys (well, girls) from O&amp;rsquo;Reilly books; JCP members and many random and awesome people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>