<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Kids on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/kids/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids These Days</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/kids_these_days</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/kids_these_days</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I&#39;m a great believer in getting kids to code early - after all, I&#39;m of that generation that was taught&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/trishagee/6702297.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;at the age of 9.&amp;nbsp; There are quite a few approaches to teaching today&#39;s kids in an engaging way, but I&#39;m a bit wary of the sandbox solutions that teach kids things like how to navigate a virtual thingie around the screen, or lets them create things in a limited virtual world.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t think kids will easily make the leap between these sort of games to seeing the full potential of programming - they&#39;re too limited and have no context for the kids. &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s just another game.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Kids need to understand how programming fits into their world, they need to understand the context of coding, if they&#39;re going to fall in love with it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;I like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codemanship.co.uk/parlezuml/blog/&#34;&gt;Jason Gorman&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s comparison of programming to music.&amp;nbsp; Most people learn an instrument because they want to make the sort of music they hear on the radio.&amp;nbsp; But you give them a recorder and teach them to play &#34;snug as a bug in a rug&#34; and they go off the idea entirely.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;So, is this a sexy tune, Mrs. Badcrumble? I just don’t think, Mrs. Badcrumble, that this is really gonna be a sexy tune.&#34;. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00065HKFW/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00065HKFW&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=trissramb-20&#34;&gt;Eddie Izzard - Definite Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=trissramb-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00065HKFW&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Similarly, you give kids a sandbox environment specifically to learn programming for the sake of programming, and they&#39;re not going to see how this turns into Facebook or Google or the apps on their phones.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re going to continue seeing computer programs as something that magicians in a land far, far away made just for them.&amp;nbsp; The same way breakfast cereal is grown in box only for them.&amp;nbsp; They don&#39;t see programming as something &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;can do, they don&#39;t see the computer as something they can influence.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Just the slightest hint, the slightest push, to show them that they can be the magician, that they can have power over this world. That&#39;s the way in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;Many of my generation of programmers learnt by coding those godawful choose-your-own adventure games.&amp;nbsp; They weren&#39;t pretty or elegant, but in a single lesson we learnt that a short magic incantation could create something that looked like those games we played.&amp;nbsp; With a bit of persistence we could truly create our &lt;i&gt;own&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;adventure, with a story that we created, not just follow someone else&#39;s paths.&amp;nbsp; And then we could inflict that on our little sisters.&amp;nbsp; It was such a short distance from the BBC command line to a game that many of us saw what programming could create, and that programming was something we could do.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;There&#39;s an argument these days that computers got so complicated, so elegant, so perfected, that &#34;kids these days&#34; don&#39;t have that.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;This is not true.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;It&#39;s just not.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t be fooled by this.&amp;nbsp; Sure, PCs in the 1990s made it more tricky to simply program the thing.&amp;nbsp; And IDEs felt, to those of us who learnt from a blinking prompt, like cheating somehow.&amp;nbsp; Or, at the very least, they divorced us from the internals of the machine, provided us with too much separation (what nonsense, by the way - an IDE must be much closer to the command line than&amp;nbsp; BASIC is from ones and zeros).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;But those days are waaay behind us.&amp;nbsp; Several more levels of indirection later, and actually it&#39;s much &lt;i&gt;easier&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;to write something that gives the immediate feedback, something that has real context, that will help kids get it.&amp;nbsp; This will help kids see &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re the same as us, they can&#39;t just be expected to do it &lt;i&gt;because,&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;they want to know what&#39;s the point.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;And these days it&#39;s easier. You&#39;ve got:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arduino.cc/&#34;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mindstorms.lego.com/en-us/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Lego mindstorms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; games&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://minecraft.net/&#34;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt; plugins&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/index.html&#34;&gt;Android apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;To name but a few. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s not even including the fact that you can get coding web pages and python code pretty quickly and see instant feedback, or even use an IDE to create a UI in something like C#.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The first three items in the list are great for people who are very touchy-feely, who want to see something in the real world.&amp;nbsp; Can you imagine how exciting it would be for your kid to see that they wrote a program that closes the curtains?&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a tiny, stupid thing, but you just gave them control of the physical world they live in.&amp;nbsp; Let their imagination do the rest.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;The other ideas are probably more directly related to the stuff they use the computer for.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;re really providing them with a way to customise the tools they already use.&amp;nbsp; Who doesn&#39;t want to imprint a bit of themselves on the virtual world?&amp;nbsp; These sorts of thing let them control a world they understand - in the context of a tool they know (e.g. Facebook), they create a game or a plugin or whatever that works within that world.&amp;nbsp; And they start to see that this tool they use to talk to their friends, this tool that is there to fill their spare time, is something &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;can control.&amp;nbsp; Maybe they&#39;ll start small, but they&#39;ll soon learn that everything they use, everything they touch on the computer, is really only code that some other human has built.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ll start to see that the computer-machine is influenceable, that they can tell it to do stuff and it will do it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;That is addictive.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;That&#39;s what we want.&amp;nbsp; We want to open their minds to how their world is constructed, and show them that they can influence it. They can control it. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;They can change the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
