<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webinars on Trisha Gee</title>
    <link>https://trishagee.github.io/tags/webinars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webinars on Trisha Gee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trishagee.github.io/tags/webinars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First presentation at the Virtual JUG!</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/presentation/first_presentation_at_the_virtual_jug/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the privilege of presenting the very first session for vJUG, a new virtual Java User Group that allows us to span geographies when sharing talks and stories. I&#39;m really interested in the vJUG idea, especially now I&#39;m not in London - if we can find good ways to share knowledge without having to travel, that will help us reach people who don&#39;t normally go to conferences or don&#39;t have a local user group to go to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar: Processing High Volume Data Feeds with MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/webinar_processing_high_volume_data_feeds_with_mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/webinar_processing_high_volume_data_feeds_with_mongodb/</guid>
      <description>Hot on the heels of my very first MongoDB webinar, I was&amp;hellip; encouraged&amp;hellip; to do another. Here at 10gen we&#39;ve been running a series of webinars around using MongoDB in the financial services domain. Yesterday was the last in the series, and was presented in association with C24 - John Davies, their CTO, did most of the talking, and demonstrated their product for automatically turning financial messages from one format into another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Official MongoDB Appearance</title>
      <link>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_first_official_mongodb_appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trishagee.github.io/post/my_first_official_mongodb_appearance/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the nerve-wracking dubious alarming great pleasure of presenting my first official MongoDB-shaped talk. This was in the form of a webinar, which is an interesting and different format.
I naïvely assumed it would be like a presentation but without the visible hand-waving, but it isn&#39;t really. For a start, you can&#39;t easily poll the audience to find out what their level of experience is, and taking questions is quite tricky, even with the technology to support it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>