<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recruitment on Trisha Gee </title>
    <link>http://trishagee.github.io/tags/recruitment/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Trisha Gee</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2011 - 2014, Trisha Gee; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Etiquette</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/linkedin_etiquette</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/linkedin_etiquette</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For no reason other than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; communications are starting to irritate me, here&amp;rsquo;s my personal
LinkedIn Etiquette guide. Feel free to disagree with it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to accept invitations from recruiters.  Not just because I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for a job (who knows what the future holds?),
but because I believe it shows a lack of respect to my network to bring recruiters one step closer to being able to contact them all.
It&amp;rsquo;s not about Evil or Good recruiters, but I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to make it easier for lazy recruiters to spam people I respect
(caveat: there are people who are technically recruiters who I have added into my network, either because I know them personally or because
they have proved their worth).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I get an invite without an introduction message from someone who&amp;rsquo;s name I don&amp;rsquo;t immediately recognise,
I&amp;rsquo;m going to check out that profile to see if we have employers in common or common connections, but usually I won&amp;rsquo;t accept that invitation.
I know LinkedIn makes it easy to click one button and request a connection, but I think my LinkedIn network is valuable and made up of people
I know (even if I only met you once at a conference), and a short introduction reminding me of where I know you from (or why you&amp;rsquo;d like to
connect) is going to help my poor, beleaguered memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endorsements - almost a total waste of time.  People I have worked with and respect have accidentally endorsed me for things they know
I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked on, simply because LinkedIn makes it too easy to click a button and endorse someone for two things they&amp;rsquo;ve already been
endorsed for and a third thing which, through some LinkedIn magic algorithm, is probably related to what you&amp;rsquo;ve done before and LinkedIn
hopes is only accidentally missing from your profile.  If recommendations were too easy to game (and they were), endorsements are almost
entirely valueless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I do find LinkedIn enormously useful.  I value it more than I think many others do for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It encourages you to keep your CV/resume reasonably up to date.  I personally believe everyone should do this,
not because you might want to hop jobs at a moment&amp;rsquo;s notice (although it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to do that), but because a) it&amp;rsquo;s really
difficult to remember what you did over the last 12 months, never mind a longer period - keeping your profile up to date means you can truly
highlight the good stuff you&amp;rsquo;ve worked on, and b) if you&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing to add to your resume from the last 12 months, that&amp;rsquo;s a good sign
that you&amp;rsquo;re not growing and your career needs a bit of love (if you think investing in your career is a Good Thing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s enormously useful for retaining a network of valuable contacts.  This is why, in my opinion,
one needs to be reasonably selective about who one adds to that network.  If you were looking for a new job, for example, and you&amp;rsquo;d been
selective about the recruiters you&amp;rsquo;d added to your network, those would be the first ones you&amp;rsquo;d contact, and you&amp;rsquo;d be reasonably certain of
a quality service.  But regardless of that, because not everyone is constantly job-seeking, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a specific person
(for example, someone comes to interview for your company; or you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a great speaker for your conference/event;
or someone approaches you about a job or an event to go to; or someone randomly e-mails you out of the blue and you&amp;rsquo;re not sure who they are)
and they&amp;rsquo;re either in your network or are connected to someone in your network, you know that you either know them or someone you know knows
them.  That makes them a Real Human and not a spam-bot or someone who wants something from you without giving value in return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not Facebook. Related to point 2, I am happy to add people I know only professionally (i.e. are not yet friends) to LinkedIn.  I&amp;rsquo;m
even happy to add people I don&amp;rsquo;t know personally if they don&amp;rsquo;t fall under rules 1 and 2 in the &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t add you if&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; section.
In Facebook, I have two (main) rules: I have to have met you in person (there are one or two exceptions but those are people I have known
for a long time only over the interwebs); I have to have spoken to you in the last year, or want to speak to you in the next 12 months.
This is for two reasons: 1) I want to keep my Facebook network relatively small so it&amp;rsquo;s more intimate, and therefore 2) I can share more
personal things on there without feeling self conscious or wondering who&amp;rsquo;s going to see it.  I have to be able to speak honestly on Facebook.
On LinkedIn, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to be so fussy - I can add you to my network if I like you but you haven&amp;rsquo;t (yet) crossed into friendship; I can
add you if I think I can be useful to you, or you to me; I can add you if I want a way to contact you (or want you to be able to contact me)
but don&amp;rsquo;t have a pressing need to stay in touch frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;rsquo;s an unnecessarily deep dive into my attitude towards LinkedIn.  It&amp;rsquo;s probably not going to change anyone&amp;rsquo;s behaviour, but I feel better for at least explaining why I won&amp;rsquo;t
necessarily add you back - all you need to do is type in the little invitation box to explain why we should be connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I value my connections, and I want to see that you do too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life on both sides of the interview table</title>
      <link>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Trisha Gee</author>
      <guid>http://trishagee.github.io/post/life_on_both_sides_of_the_interview_table</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InfoQ has posted the video of Dan North and I opining on the subject of hiring. &amp;nbsp;Most of the talk is spent on how to be a good interviewer, and touches on how to market your company to prospective hires. &amp;nbsp;We spend less time on how to do well as an interviewee, but in theory if you know what&amp;rsquo;s going through the interviewer&amp;rsquo;s mind, you should be in a much better position to take control of the interview and shine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/job-interview-tips#.UiBS9_WZJyU.blogger&#34;&gt;Hire Education - Making Interviews Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of funny because we talk a lot about hiring at ThoughtWorks (where we both worked, and which has one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/hardest-tech-company-job-interviews-2012-8&#34;&gt;toughest interview processes&lt;/a&gt; in the industry) and LMAX, which learnt a lot off ThoughtWorks and shaped its own process for a smaller company that has different goals. &amp;nbsp;Yet neither of us work at those places now. &amp;nbsp;Still, we share stories from many of the places we&amp;rsquo;ve worked (or chose not to work), and if there&amp;rsquo;s one take-home point, it&amp;rsquo;s that hiring (and being hired) is not a simple thing to do well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
